{(WHIRRING)
{ALARM SIREN)
(LAUGHS)
(GASPS)
Mayday, Mayday!
(COUGHS)
Pirates!
Hold them off!
Sheeta, stay out of the way
and you won't get hurt.
(TELEGRAPH BEEPING)
Come on!
Hurry up!
Break the door down!
(SCREAMS)
Where is she?
- Nol
- Heyl
I've found her,
she's hiding out here!
- Don't let her escape. Quick, get her!
- Come on, sweetheart!
- Mom! Don't let me go!
- Quit your whining, I've got you.
Ah, she's wearing the crystal.
- Go get her!
- Right!
DOLA: I want that crystal.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, no, there goes my crystal. Oh, no!
(CHATTER)
I need some meatballs for the boss,
please.
All right.
You're sure working late tonight, Pazu.
You're not kidding.
Things are finally busy for a change.
- Still working?
-Yep. Byel
Huh?
What is that?
Looks like a body. Whoa!
(PANTS)
Whoa!
Aaah!
(GROANS)
(STRAINS)
- MAN: Pazu!
- Huh?
What are you doing up there?
Did you bring my dinner?
Yeah, I did. But this girl
came down from the sky.
(STEAMWHISTLES)
MAN: Blast these old pipes!
Here you go.
Boss!
Listen, Boss, a girl came...
What? Not again!
- Ah, just when I get one thing fixed...
- Listen to me. A girl came down...
BOSS: Tighten the second valve,
will you? There's no time to lose.
This machinery is too old.
- 1 think I need a bigger wrench.
- I'll get it.
- Go run the hoist while I fix this.
- Huh?
-You think you can do it?
-Yeah. Here!
- Just stay calm and use your head.
- Right.
Hit the brake!
-What?
- (CLANKING)
Phew.
-Well, how'd it go, boys?
- No silver, not even any trace of tin.
We're just not having any luck.
Maybe we would if we tried
digging the mines just east of here.
1 don't know.
Those mines are worse than this one.
We'll just have to start all over again.
- Let's call it a day. Night.
- Night.
{MEN SIGH)
{HISSING)
Shut off the boiler, Pazu.
We're not going to find anything today.
Things keep going like this,
we'll all be starving soon.
And Pazu, maybe you
could oil that blasted machine.
Okay.
-Thanks. Good night.
- Night.
Mom, it's no use, let's call it off.
There's too much cloud coverage,
it's too dark.
What?
- Mom, don't worry. I'll find her.
-We'll all find her.
(YAWNING)
{BUGLE PLAYING)
{BUGLE CONTINUES)
{(SQUEALS)
PAZU: Hello!
It's about time you got up.
(LAUGHS)
PAZU: How are you feeling?
Hi there.
My name's Pazu. I'm really glad
to see you're doing all right.
You had me worried there.
Go ahead, feed them. Don't be shy.
These guys are really happy
we have a visitor.
(LAUGHING)
Thank goodness.
You laugh like a regular person.
The way you fell from the sky,
I thought that maybe
you were an angel or something.
Thank you very much for saving me.
Oh, I'm sorry. My name's Sheeta.
Sheeta. What a beautiful name.
I had to catch you.
You were just floating, and I...
-What? Floating?
-Yeah.
Well, I remember an airship,
but I can't remember anything else...
-That's all you remember?
-Mm-hm.
- I'm not sure how I survived.
- Hmm.
Well,
1 think I might have an idea about that.
May I see your necklace for a second?
This?
My grandmother gave it to me.
It's been in my family for generations.
Wow, it's beautiful.
Could you hold this?
Thanks.
Get a load of this.
Watch. Here I go!
- (GASPS)
- (LOUD CRASHING)
Pazu! Are you all right?
(GASPING)
Well, so maybe I had the wrong idea
about this necklace.
- (GASPS)
- (LOUD CRASHING)
(GROANS)
(SHEETA SCREAMS)
I'm so sorry, Pazu.
(GROANS)
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
You scared me. Does it hurt much?
Are you kidding?
If my head were any harder,
you could use it as a cannonball.
{BOTH GIGGLE)
Oh, the kettle! It must be boiling over.
Come on. Let's go.
- Follow me. This way.
- Okay.
I'll get breakfast started.
You can wash up over there.
-There's a clean towel too.
- Great. Thank you.
Laputa...
Sheetal! It's time for breakfast.
My father took that picture
from an airship. He loved to fly.
It's Laputa, the floating island.
An island that floats in the sky?
Yep. Most people think it's just
a legend, but my dad actually saw it.
That's a picture of his airship.
(CRASHING THUNDER}
PAZU: It looked like a castle
just floating in the sky.
He said it was the most
amazing thing he'd ever seen.
And that's the only picture
he was able to take.
But take a look at this, Sheeta.
Dad kept a journal and made
all sorts of drawings of Laputa. See?
There it is.
And he drew the castle, and also
what he thought the people looked like.
He was sure the castle was filled
with treasure, but nobody believed him.
They called him a liar.
Being called a liar is what killed him.
But I am gonna prove
that my dad was no liar, Sheeta.
As soon as I'm done building this plane,
I'm gonna take off
and find Laputa myself.
Huh?
Hmm.
Oh.
Wow! It's a real automobile.
You don't see many of those
around here.
-Those people are pirates, Pazu.
-What?
They're the ones
who attacked the airship.
-They're probably after you.
- (GASPS)
Come on!
- Good morning! Bye!
- Hey! Hold on, wait up!
Yes? How can I help you, mister?
Young man, query. Have you seen
a little girl around here?
Let me see now...Yeah, there are about
100 little gids in this town!
Which one?
-Thanks for nothing, kid.
- Bye!
They're definitely after you, Sheeta.
Louis, go tell your mother
she's in disguise.
No, she's in disguise.
Go tell my mother.
(GROANS)
Haven't seen her.
That's what you keep saying,
but I want you to think
really hard about it.
PAZU: Boss! Boss!
She'd be about the age of those two.
Oh, no!
-There she is.
- Don't let her get away!
Now!
Hey! Boss, they're pirates,
they're after her!
Pirates! I wanna seel
You can stop right there, my friend.
-Think you're tough, don't you?
- I'm tough enough.
-We'll see about that.
- Just go away. We're honest folks here.
Get away!
What did you do that for?
- Quick! Leave from the back.
- No, I'm gonna fight ‘em.
Pazu,
what if you end up getting yourself hurt?
So?
Somebody's gotta protect your friend.
Hmm? Oh.
-Why don't you get out of our way?
-Why don't you just try and make me?
- Maybe I will.
- Oh, yeah.
Make your shirt explode.
Hey, Boss, show him
what you're made of.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm not mending that, I hope you know.
(CHEERING)
MAN: Come on, you're not so big.
MAN 2: That's right!
You go get him, Boss!
He said Mom was ugly.
Now, go get him!
-That's it! Get him!
- Give him a break!
-That's it! Come on!
- Punch him!
-Yeah, yeah...
- Hey, loudmouth!
Get in there!
Give him a right, give him a left,
give him a right...
Whoa! Oh.
They're headed for the railroad tracks.
Let's move it!
{BOTH PANTING)
Hey!
-We've gotta jump on, Sheeta.
- Right.
-That's it.
- Come on.
Hey, Pazu, who's your friend there?
Her name is Sheeta.
Pirates are after us.
- It's the Dola gang.
- I'll be... Pirates?
Care to drop us off
at the police station in the next town?
Sure! I'll tell you what...
- Help me stoke up the engine.
-Will do.
{HORN HONKING)
Hey, it's Mom!
(GUNSHOTS)
You chowderheads!
Get your brother and hop on!
Huh? But Sheeta's hiding
inside that house...
Lame-brain, they made
an escape. Now, step on it!
-They escaped?
- Hey! I wanna come!
Mommy!
{(GRUNTING) Hey!
Hey, Pazu, here they come!
- Hey! Can't this engine go any faster?
-This is the best she'll do. She's old.
Floor it. Move over!
{MEN SCREAM)
I'd really prefer
to be in the car, Mother!
Increase the steam,
they're gaining on us!
We got ‘em!
Yeah!
We need you in here.
- Help with the fire.
- Okay.
(STRAINS)
Uh-oh.
Look out!
Come on, get 'em! Get 'em!
{CLANGING)
Hey, come back here!
You'll get yours!
Don't just stand there,
push this train off of the cliff.
What?
(LAUGHS)
-We sure showed them.
-I can do it now.
You were amazing!
- Heave! Heave! Heave!
- And heave and heave...
-Wait!
-...and stop.
You think maybe it's Muska?
Yeah, it's Muska all right.
We gotta find those kids!
Uh?
{HORN HONKING)
{HONKING CONTINUES)
Well, what do you know about that?
It's the army to the rescue.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Hey, could you kindly help
these two young people?
Pirates have been chasing them all day.
(GASPS)
Uh?
-What's the matter? Huh?
- Goodbye, Pazu.
Young lady, come back here!
{BOTH GROANING)
- Sheeta, wait!
- Halt or I'll shoot!
{MENYELP)
-That's an armored train, Mother.
-We're the Dola gang. Attack!
- Oh, no! Hey! Sheeta!
- Don't follow me, you'll get hurt.
{(YELPING)
{MEN SCREAMING)
Don't let go.
(SCREAMING)
Come on!
{PAZU STRAINS)
-Where are they, Mother?
- Be quiet. Just watch them.
{BOTH STRAINING)
{BOTH SCREAM)
Ahhh!
Huh?
{BOTH GASP)
Sheeta, we're floating!
See? This is what happened
the first time I saw you.
See that?
It's the power of the crystal.
{ALL GASP)
I knew it! I knew there was something
special about your necldace.
- Oh.
-Wool
The necklace
will let us down nice and easy.
- Boys, I want that crystal!
- SOLDIER: Fire!
It's fantastic, incredible.
I must have that crystal!
- (GASPS) It's going out...
-Wait just a minute.
I guess your necklace must come
to life whenever you're in trouble.
Wow, that's a long way up.
I hope they're all right, your boss and
his wife and that nice train engineer.
My friends are all miners.
They can take care of themselves.
I wouldn't worry about them if I were you.
Come on, Sheeta, let's go.
This has been a mining town
as long as anyone can remember.
Most of these tunnels
aren't even used anymore.
(DRIPPING)
Here you go.
Thank you. I'm glad
you brought some food. I'm starving.
And for dessert, I've got
a green apple and some candy.
Really?
You know,
that bag of yours must be magic.
It's always got just what we need.
{BOTH GIGGLE)
Mmm.
Sheeta, where exactly
do you come from?
I come from Gondoa,
deep in the northern mountains.
I used to live there with my parents,
and we were very happy.
But when my mother
and father died, I was all alone.
The only thing that kept me going
was the farm,
and taking care of my animals.
But one day, everything changed.
That was the day the men came
and took me away.
Whoa! Wait a minute!
-You mean they kidnapped you?
-Yes.
- It was that man in the dark glasses.
- Mmm-hmm.
I wonder who that guy is,
and what he's doing with the army?
You know what I think?
I think Dola and that man
are both after your necklace.
I think you're right.
But I had no idea my crystal
was so incredibly powerful.
It's been in my family
as long as I can remember.
Mother gave it to me before she died,
and she told me never to show it
or give it away to anyone.
Huh...
Well, we orphans should stick together,
don't you think?
I'm really sorry. It's my fault,
getting you mixed up in all of this.
Are you kidding?
This is the most exciting thing
that's ever happened to me.
I wouldn't miss an adventure
like this for anything in the world.
(GIGGLES)
- (GASPS) Wha...
- (GASPS)
Are you some sort of goblin
come to torment me?
It's Uncle Pom. Don't worry,
he's a friend. Uncle Pom!
Uncle Pom! Boy, am I glad to see you.
I can't see you clearly yet,
goblin, but you sound like Pazu.
And if these old eyes don't deceive me,
there's a she-goblin with you.
There are pirates chasing us,
Uncle Pom.
- Oh!
- And the army's right behind them.
(LAUGHS)
That sounds absolutely splendid.
-The tea is ready. Help yourself.
-Thank you. This is great.
Don't you get lonely
down here underground, Uncle Pom?
Never, my dear. All of these rocks
are my friends, they often talk to me.
Ever since last night,
they've been especially restless.
-The rocks talk to you?
- Oh, yes, Pazu.
The earth speaks to all of us.
And if we listen, we can understand.
The rocks speak in a very small voice.
Huh?
Oh, my.
- Amazing.
- Pazu, look above us.
Huh? Wow!
It was just
a hunk of rock a while ago.
Oh, my!
The answer lies inside these rocks.
Let me show you.
Wow.
Pazu, you see?
All the rocks around here
contain a bit of etherium.
Really?
Mankind once knew
how to mine etherium, but no longer.
Wait.
Look, my stone's glowing...
Well, goodness bless my soul!
That's a pure etherium crystal.
There hasn't been one since before
my great grandfather's time.
No wonder the rocks were restless.
This stone possesses
incredible power.
Legend has it that only the people
of the floating city of Laputa
knew how to make such crystals.
They made this crystal?
They used etherium
to make Laputa float in the sky.
I knew Laputa wasn't just made up.
You see, Sheeta?
It's just like my dad said!
{(WHIMPERS)
What's the matter?
I'm sorry, but would you put that
crystal away? It's too strong for me.
Oh, sorry.
What is it, Uncle Pom?
{SIGHING)
Great-grandpa used to tell me
that the rocks become restless
when Laputa appears over the mine.
Wow! So that must mean
Laputa's over the mine right now!
Listen! Sheeta, now I can prove
that the legend is true!
- Sheeta, I must tell you something.
-Yes, what is it?
That crystal is extremely powerful,
but with a power that rightfully belongs
to the earth from which it came.
To forget that and then to try and use
the crystal's power for selfish reasons,
will bring great unhappiness.
You understand?
Yes.
Your crystal should remind us
that we come from the earth,
and to the earth we must return.
Come on! Lighten up!
Two times already that crystals gotten
Sheeta out of some really big trouble.
And I have a feeling that crystal's
gonna help us find Laputa.
It's flying away.
Mom, can we
go back to the ship now, please?
It's too quiet.
We'd better just stay put
for the time being.
Does this mean no lunch?
Coast is clear. Let's go.
- Uncle Pom, thank you.
- Be careful, my dear.
(PANTS)
Wow! Look up there.
Beyond that cloud is a floating city
that no one here on Earth
believes exists.
But I swear,
I am gonna be the one to prove it.
- Pazu.
- Huh?
Listen, there's something
I haven't told you yet.
You see, my family
has a very old traditional name,
and when the stone was passed
on to me, I inherited that name.
And the name I inherited
was LucitaToelle Ur Laputa.
Laputa.You mean you're...
They've found us, Sheeta, let's go!
- Head back to the mine, hurry!
- Stop them!
- Hands up!
- Don't you touch her!
(SHEETA SCREAMS)
Let me go!
Oh, no, are you all right, Pazu?
You have to wake up, Pazu!
- Sir, we've captured them.
- And about time.
(GROANS)
Uh?
Hey, let me out!
Where am I?
MAN: Forward, march!
(STRAINS)
- (SHRIEKS)
- (THUDDING)
We're wasting time.
Twist an arm or two
and I guarantee the girl will tall.
I respectfully disagree. Such military
tactics risk wasting more time, General.
If my military tactics
had been used to begin with,
Dola wouldn't have had a chance
to interfere with us at all.
It was a military transmission
that the pirates decoded.
You've bungled things, sir,
and now I must fix them.
Your job, General, is to mobilize
the troops when it becomes necessary.
Muskal
Just don't forget that the government
put me in charge of finding Laputa!
Don't forget
that as the government's secret agent,
I am in charge of you, General.
Blast. I really hate that man.
{LOCK RATTLES)
I trust you slept well?
Where's Pazu? Is he all right?
I want to see him!
Now, this is fit for a princess.
Don't worry, Sheeta.
Your friend is being
treated as if he were the guest of royalty.
I want you to see something
before you see him.
Please step inside.
(GASPS)
What is it?
An artificial life form.
It's called a robot.
Laputa was just a legend
until this dropped from the sky.
(WHISTLING)
- Huh?
- (WOMAN SHRIEKS)
Now, the government
wants me to unlock Laputa's secrets.
For example, what's this fellow
made of? Metal or ceramics?
With our limited technology we have
no idea, but he does tell us one thing.
Come and see.
Oh, don't be afraid, Sheeta.
He's really quite dead, you know.
Look there.
It's the same emblem that
decorates the fireplace in your home.
And your crystal.
You see, Sheeta,
this crystal also comes from Laputa.
And I believe the powers locked inside it
are capable of leading a person
back to that city's treasures.
Then why? Why don't you just take it?
Just take it and keep
Laputa's treasures for yourself,
but leave Pazu and me alone. Please.
You think I'm doing this for money?
You understand nothing.
According to the legend,
the same technology
that kept Laputa airborne
also made it a major power
that once dominated the entire planet.
If such a horrible thing
is still floating up there,
you can understand what a threat
itis to the peace of the world.
Sheeta, the stone only works for you.
You must know of some way to make the
stone point out the location of Laputa.
I really don't know anything!
Please let me see Pazul
I don't want to see any harm
come to anyone,
but I simply can't control
what the military might do to him.
What?
In the event that you cooperate,
I'm sure whoever's
in charge will grant Pazu his freedom,
Lucita...
...Toelle Ur Laputa.
You know my real name.
Ur means "ruler" in Laputian,
Toelle means "true."
You are the legitimate heir to the
throne of Laputa, Princess Lucita.
(SCREAMING)
Let's go. Out.
Sheetal
Are you all right, Pazu?
I'm okay, but what about you?
They didn't hurt you, did they?
Pazu, I'm so sorry.
There's been a grave misunderstanding.
We had no idea
how nobly you fought
to protect our little Sheeta
from those awful pirates.
What's he talking about?
Pazu, do this for me.
Forget about Laputa.
What are you saying?
It's been decided
that the search for Laputa
will be made secretly
by the army with Sheeta's cooperation.
Really, the best thing you can do
is forget you ever heard of the place.
- Forget about Laputa?
- I'm sorry I caused you so much trouble.
I hope some day you can forgive me.
I can't forget, no way!
Laputa means too much to both of us.
- Goodbye.
- Sheetal!
{GRUNTING)
- Come back!
- Now behave, little boy, use your head!
Here, take this. A little something to
show our appreciation of your efforts.
Only you can do it.
Remember the words
that bring the crystal to life.
Keep your promise,
and you too will be free.
{DOOR CLOSES)
(SOBs)
Hey, Mommy! Mommy, it's Pazul
Pazu's outside!
Oh, my, Pazu.
Well, where have you been?
We were all very worried about you,
Pazu.
What happened to your friend?
- It's over now.
-What?
Pazu, come back!
Welcome home, sonny.
Get out! Get out or I'll throw you out!
This is my house!
You don't scare me.
You can't even protect one small girl...
-What do you mean?
- Hey, Mom, can I keep this money?
Up and sold the little girl,
did you? I know your type.
You don't know
what you're talking about!
They offered you money
and you took it, didn't you?
I only left because Sheeta told me to.
That's why.
So you believed her
and you came back here, right?
You're just a scared little boy
that runs away!
Says you!
You didn't even have the guts
to stand up to Muska and the army!
He who turns and runs away,
can steal the treasure another day!
Don't you think it's kind of strange
that the army's gotten into
the kidnapping business?
You think they'll keep her alive?
Don't you see that they forced her
to make a deal?
Huh?
She saved your life.
Getit?
Mommy, you amaze me.
How do you know these things?
Well...
You can't be a sensitive woman like me
without learning a few things.
Sheeta and I are exactly alike,
all warm and mushy and sensitive.
Now, so when you boys get married,
go find a gal like her.
Huh? She's gonna end up like Momma?
{BELL RINGING)
- Ma, that was good ham.
- Come here.
{BEEPING)
Ah, it won't work,
changing the code on me.
They're calling
for air destroyer Goliath.
They're planning to take off with Sheeta.
We've gotta hurry or it'll be too late.
- Come on, boys. Stop eating!
- I'm going, Momma.
I'm going!
Wait. Are you gonna rescue Sheeta?
- No, you little squirt, we want her crystal.
-Wait a minute!
You've gotta have Sheeta to make
the etherium crystal work,
otherwise it's useless.
Dola, please let me come with you,
I need to save her.
Sheeta means everything to me!
You know something? You're acting
like a sniveling little cry-baby.
Maybe you're right.
I should have protected Sheeta,
but instead I was stupid and angry.
But let me come with you
and I swear I'll protect her this time.
- Pazu loves Sheeta...
- Be quiet.
I guess you'd be useful
in getting Sheeta to cooperate.
You might never come back here again,
Pazu!
I know.
- Ready for what might happen?
- Mmm-hmm.
We leave here in one minute.
You guys be good.
Here, fasten this.
Let's rendezvous at the Tiger Moth.
What a superb ship. Muska, has the gin
surrendered the information?
It will take a little more time.
More time? Well, you'll have plenty
of that aboard Goliath.
We set out with her at first light.
Hurry, we have to get there
before sun-up!
Sheeta.
{ECHOING SOBS)
Well, well, now. What shall we do?
Sheeta, maybe Grandma
should teach you a spell?
One that will help you
when you're in trouble.
A spell?
Yes, my dearest,
an ancient, secret spell.
"Lite latuperito ulus...
"...areolus balo neetoril.”
Lite a...
The words mean "save me."
"Save me,
and revive the eternal light.”
So, "Lite latuperito ulus
areolus balo neetoril.”
Lite latuperito ulus
areolus balo neetoril.
(SCREAMING)
I knew it.
It's the sacred light.
The ancient documents were true.
It's not just a legend!
What are you talking about?
Tell me the spell.
What are the secret words?
- Did you hear that?
-Yeah.
- I'm telling you, this thing is alive!
- Halt! Stop!
Do you hear me? Alive!
{BOTH SCREAM)
{BOTH GASP)
Help, it's alive! It's after us.
- Run for your lives!
- It's the robot!
Run!
It's the robot!
{MEN SHOUT ABOVE)
- It's come back to life!
- Hurry, sound the alarm, quick!
There, see? He's moving!
-What's happening?
- Sir, it's the robot.
{MEN SCREAMING BELOW)
It's coming toward us.
Fire!
Shut the fire door. Hurry!
- Look there! What is it?
- Look out!
The power!
Yes, I understand.
It's your crystal!
The force of the sacred light
has brought the robot back to life!
-The way to Laputa has been opened.
- Let me go!
It's going to fly!
{SHRIEKS)
It's Laputa.
Finally, I now know the way to Laputa.
Hurry, no time to waste!
What do you mean, "robot™
I wanna know
who's trying to blow up my fortress!
Are you there?
Somebody answer me now!
-We're ready.
-You're connected now.
This is Colonel Muska.
We have an emergency.
You'll take your orders from me now.
Hurry! I need that shell now!
- Fire!
{(CLANKING)
Let's get up there now!
-We demolished it.
-We got him!
- Get the girl. Over there.
- Right, right.
- Is she dead?
- Hey, get up!
{GROANING)
- Nah, she's only fainted.
- Come on!
Oh, no!
- Must be some kind of war going on.
-Take her down, Dola.
Call me Captain!
Just keep your big head down, Shalulu!
Stop it, you're destroying
everything! Please stop!
Captain Mother,
Goliath is moving! Goliath is moving!
If we stay on this heading, we'll be
in the line of fire. Change course!
- Look, there she is! It's Sheetal!
-What?
Where'd you see her?
Steady as she goes, Captain.
She's on top of that tower!
- One for all, and all for Mom. Cover me!
- Good luck!
Sheetal
My hand. Take it!
Pazu!
We've gotta get in a little closer, Dola!
But they're here to help me.
Please, put me down!
Sheetal
Dola!
No, they're falling!
No.
Help!
Come on.
{GRUNTING)
Ah, come on, Dola!
It's now or never, Pazu.
- I'll take us in and you grab her.
- Right!
- Over here!
- Okay, Captain.
What are you doing, fools?
Don't let her escape!
Jump!
An entire army,
and they're getting away.
It's not over.
Muska! Muska, what on earth
happened to the robot?
-We destroyed it. And the girl's gone.
-What?
GENERAL:
Oh! Look at this, it's a disaster!
I think we may have found
what we've been looking for, Colonel.
Extinguish the fire,
organize a pursuit team!
It still possesses its sacred light...
...pointing to Laputa.
You may now go tell the General for me,
we will be departing on time.
{SHEETA SOBS)
Sheeta, you okay?
If I did something wrong,
I'd really like to apologize for it, Sheeta.
DOLA:We all did something wrong,
wasting our time on these two kids.
Here's your valley up ahead.
I'll drop you off and that'll be that.
It's all right. Dola, will you let
us sail with you and the boys?
Call me Captain, darn it!
I don't see what the heck's in it for me,
since you lost the etherium crystal!
We could work.
I have to find out the real truth
about Laputa for myself, Captain.
So, you're not interested in money,
but you want to find out
the truth about Laputa?
Well, I guess there's worse reasons
for you wanting to become a pirate.
Mother, I say let 'em come along!
Toe the line and work hard,
or overboard you go!
PAZU: Yes, Captain!
Yes! No more swabbing
the decks, hooray!
- 1 won't have to wash the dishes!
- I've peeled my last potato!
Yeehaw!
{ALLWHOOP)
- Sheeta, can you make pudding?
- I love pudding!
1 get to lick the spatulal
And I like chocolate cake with that...
What's that frosting
that's kind of pink and swirly?
Will you shut up?
Ah, what can I tell you?
They just really like dessert.
Whoa!
And disembark.
-What is this ship made out of, cloth?
- And don't you rip it.
Come on, we'll go topside.
{(WHIRRING)
Ugh!
You're going the wrong way. Come here!
1 don't like slowpokes.
- (PAZUYELPS)
- Pazu!
Come on, matey,
I haven't got all day.
Work, work, work,
busy, busy, busy, busy.
Left, right. Left, right.
You're not here to have fun.
This engine room is really amazing.
Is that what it's called?
Hey, Poppa, where are you?
Hey, Pop, I've finally
found you an assistant.
Stop yelling at me. I can hear you.
Believe me, sometimes I wish I couldn't.
Hurry up.
He's even tougher than my mother.
- It's too narrow, I can't reach.
- It's okay, I got it.
-What's your name?
- Pazu.
But the beam from the crystal
was pointing directly due east.
You sure about this?
Yes, I'm sure I could see
the sun rising from the tower.
You know,
it's the end of grass-cutting season,
so the sun rose not from due east,
but a little further south.
The light was pointing to the left
of the hill from which the sun rose.
-You see?
- Pretty smart.
- Found anything yet?
- Haven't found a single thing, Captain.
They're jamming the airwaves so we
can't find them, those flying devils.
Mom? How can we catch them
when they're faster than we are?
Well, it looks like we're cruising
on the windward side of ‘em.
So if we manage to ride the trade wind...
Let's see,
according to my calculations...
With wind velocity at 10...
Looks to me like we'll catch ‘em.
Attention, all hands, now hear this!
Goliath is already underway for Laputa.
We're gonna set sail and go after ‘em.
If we can catch the wind,
we'll be on their heels by tomorrow.
Now, the first man to spy Goliath
will receive 10 gold coins.
That's good money!
And if the stories we've heard
about Laputa are true,
there will be enough treasure
to make an honest pirate of us all!
(LAUGHS)
All right, all hands aboard,
look alive and get to work!
Let her rip!
Course 98 degrees,
velocity 50.
{(WHIRRING)
Now you gotta start dressing
like a real pirate. Let's see...
Here.
And this is where you'll be working.
(GULPS)
This is the galley.
I want it ship-shape,
sparkling clean, and ready for action
in one hour.
-That's an order.
-Butl...
The boys get awful hungry.
You'll serve five meals a day.
You blubber heads, I'm not running
a luxury cruise, now get to work!
{(WHIRRING)
{CLANGING)
Come in.
I'm afraid I'm still cooking.
Nothing's ready yet.
It took me a long time
to clean everything up.
Yes, what is it?
Er...
Yes?
I've finished my work for the moment
and I've come to offer you my help.
Well, that's kind of you.
Would you please hand me
those plates over there?
With pleasure, my little ang...
-What are you doing here?
- Helping.
I thought you said
you had a stomach ache!
- I'm in love with you. Hello.
-You?
- Move.
-Too crowded.
- Hey! What do I look like? A chair?
- Is there anything I can do?
-You!l
- Heyl
What's come over you, my dear?
It's not like you
to challenge a ship like Goliath.
-You know, the odds are against you.
- I'm after treasure, that's all.
I must admit,
those kids are cute.
What do you mean by that,
you old fool?
Nothing, but that little girl does
remind me of you not so long ago.
-Who asked you?
- Nobody.
Oh, look... Checkmate.
Fabulous!
Does anyone want anymore?
I do believe I will have a second helping.
-Yes? Oh!
- I want some more!
(SNORING)
Come oh, young pup.
Time to go on duty.
It's cold, take this.
Huh?
- I'll take over.
-Thank you.
Sheeta.
Whoa!
That was exciting!
Wow, you can see forever.
Sheeta. Here.
- (PAZUTHROUGH PIPE) You okay?
-That's better.
{PAZUTHROUGH PIPE) This is great.
Now we can keep watch together.
- Pazw?
- Hmm?
I'm really scared.
(SHEETATHROUGH PIPE} To tell you
the truth, I don't want to go to Laputa.
{PAZUTHROUGH PIPE)
What do you mean?
Didn't you tell Dola the truth?
SHEETA: I didn't lie to Dola. What I said
about the light's direction is true.
But what if someone else dies?
PAZU:You mean, like the robot?
SHEETA: He died to save my life.
I feel awful.
All this is because of a spell
my grandmother taught me.
She taught me all sorts of spells.
A spell to use when you're looking
for something, a spell to cure sickness.
There's even one she told me
I must never use.
- PAZU: What kind of spell?
- SHEETA: The spell of destruction.
She said that
to give power to good spells,
I had to know the evil ones too.
But she told me never to use them.
I was so scared when I learned
that spell, I couldn't sleep.
I didn't know the spells
were connected to my necklace.
Uncle Pom was right when he said
that it was dangerous for us
to misuse the power of the crystal.
SHEETA: And what if Laputa
has the same power
that can also be used for great evil?
I wish I'd thrown the crystal away.
But then we never would have met.
And anyway, even if you had,
Laputa would still exist.
Airplanes and flying machines
are getting better and better.
You know eventually
some explorer or another
will come across the city of Laputa
one day and claim it.
PAZU: I can't say I know what's best,
but if Laputa
really has such great power,
we can't let it fall into the hands
of bad people like Muska.
And,
if we run away now,
Muska is gonna chase us forever.
But Pazu, I don't want you
to become a pirate because of me.
I'm not gonna become a pirate.
PAZU: Don't worry,
Dola will understand.
She's much nicer
than she pretends to be.
And when we've finally found it,
I promise you we'll go back to Gondoa.
I want to see it all, Sheeta.
The old house where you were born,
the valley, and everything.
SHEETA: Oh, Pazu.
PAZU: Sheeta, what's that?
Right there, under the ship. See it?
Captain!
It's Goliath, right under our bow!
Starboard rudder, full speed ahead!
Why don't you go after them,
Muska? Get them!
It's useless to look for them
in the cloud cover.
I don't need to waste my energy
on a wild goose chase.
Besides, we're running
right on schedule.
It was farther north than I figured.
Pazu, listen carefully to me.
DOLA: Everything will be ruined
if we lose track of Goliath.
You've got good eyes. I want you
to watch her and keep us on course.
How do I do that, Captain?
The crow's-nest can be made into a kite.
See the metal handle on the bulkhead?
-Igotit.
-Turn it clockwise.
DOLA: Hook it up. And then turn
the handle, that'll make the wings open.
Now extend the wire.
You have to get the hang of flying it
on your own!
- Are you up there, Sheeta, my dear?
-Yes.
- Best you come down right now.
-Why?
Because you're a girl! A female!
That's man's work!
But you're female, Captain.
I grew up in the mountains,
I can do this.
- Sheeta, no!
- Be quiet. And Pazu agrees with me.
All right, me hearty.
Once you take off, you'll have
to use the phone to communicate.
(RINGING)
- SHEETA: You mean this phone?
- She is good.
Right. I think we're set.
Ready for takeoff.
DOLA: Aye-aye, anchor's away.
I don't see them.
They must be hiding
under the cloud cover.
DOLA: Perhaps,
but they could also be above you.
- Keep your eyes peeled.
- Roger.
{BOTH SCREAM)
Hold on tight.
(STRAINS)
DOLA: What happened?
PAZU: Nothing, just a gust of wind.
Didn't bother us at all.
We're fine.
We'll keep on watching.
- Afraid?
- Uh-uh.
1 got the hang of this thing now.
Storm ahead.
Sheeta, look in my bag.
There should be some rope in there.
- Okay.
- Let's tie ourselves together.
-This storm is gonna be rough.
- Good idea.
The mercury is dropping
really fast, Mom.
Blast our luck, boys.What a rotten time
for a storm. When is sun-up?
In one hour.
{WIND WHISTLES)
PAZU: Wait a minute,
something's not right.
The sun is coming up in the
wrong place. We're out of position.
You're right. We're supposed to be
heading east, not north.
We're going the wrong way! Captain!
Huh? What do you mean,
we're headed north?
But the compass needle
is pointing east, Mom.
There's something
confusing the compass,
and I want to know what itis.
- SHEETA: There it is. Look!
-There what is? Is it Goliath?
PAZU: No, it's a cloud.
And I've only seen one other like it.
A cloud?
It's heading right for us!
That's it...
I'm not gonna captain my ship
into the eye of a hurricane.
Pull back! Pull back, I tell you!
All engines reverse!
We're being pulled
into the center of the storm.
DOLA: Sorry, Pazu, we can't help you,
you have to ride it out.
Good luck, sailor!
(SHEETA SCREAMS)
-I can't get it to turn!
- Put your backbone into it, my boy!
Dola, the engine can't take it!
What do you want me to do about it?
Just do what you can.
Clouds are breaking up.
Look, it's the ocean!
- Pazu, it's a hurricane!
- 1 see it, Captain.We're going in.
Wow.
It's just like Dad said, two winds
blowing in opposite directions.
Shiver me timbers,
what a powerful storm!
Mom, it's no use, we'll be sucked in!
If there's one thing I can't stand,
it's a quitter!
- PAZU: Captain, Laputa's in there!
- Laputa's where?
This is just the kind of storm
my father saw,
and Laputa's in the middle of it.
DOLA: It can't be.
It'd be smashed to pieces!
- Pazu! Look there!
- Huh?
My boys, we have a dilemma.
It's Goliath off the port bow!
We're gonna go into the hurricane.
My dad made it through alive,
and so will we.
Ready? Brace yourselves, gentlemen!
We did it! Got 'em!
If we don't turn, we'll hit that storm.
- All ahead, full.
- Sir?
The light is pointing
to the center of the whirlwind.
Laputa is in that storm.
I won't retreat.
Now go straight ahead.
And that is an order, Captain.
- Ready, Sheeta?
-Yes!
{WIND HOWLING)
{THUNDER CRACKING)
{LIGHTNING CRACKLING)
(SILENCE)
Huh?
{SILENCE CONTINUES)
{MOUTHING)
{LIGHTNING CRACKLING)
Huh?
{BIRDS CHIRPING)
Sheeta.
Hey, are you all right? Wake up.
Look...
(GASPS)
Laputa?
- I'm sorry. Here.
-Wait a minute.
It's a very tight knot.
And... My...
My hands are trembling.
-Whoal
-Woo-hoo!l
-Wow.
-We're here. We really found it.
{BOTH LAUGHING)
Pretty birds...
They must live here, Pazu.
- (HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
- Huh?
1 think he must be here to meet you,
Sheeta.
But I don't have the etherium crystal.
Wait, I've gotta cut us loose.
{ELECTRONIC BEEPS)
Hey, wait!
You're gonna break that.
Wait! Please, Mr. Robot, don't do that.
We won't be able to go home
without it.
{ELECTRONIC BEEPS)
- It's a bird's nest!
-That's why he's here.
I'm so happy the eggs are all right, Pazu.
It must be his job to take care of them.
{ELECTRONIC BEEPS)
- He says to follow him.
- How do you know?
I just know that's what he said.
Look!
It's a city.
{BIRDS CHIRPING)
I can't believe we're inside a building.
{BIRDS CAWING)
-Wow, the walls are invisible.
-Yeah.
I wonder what happened here.
This used to be a city
of advanced technology.
PAZU: It must be a monument.
I wish I could read what it says.
Someone left some flowers. Look.
Did you leave the flowers?
Hey, that's a different robot!
It looks like it's been frozen
there forever. Hey...
They must've been
protectors of the garden,
and they've kept on guarding the place,
even long after all the people have gone.
Oh. You've picked another flower
for the grave. How kind of you.
Thank you.
He must be the only one left.
It looks like all the other robots
stopped working a long time ago.
(SQUEAKS)
{ALL SQUEAKING)
Ha!
{ELECTRONIC BEEPS)
You know what, Sheeta?
I bet he's not lonesome at all.
He's got plenty of friends,
the animals and the birds.
He takes care of them.
{BIRDS SQUAWKING)
{LOUD RUMBLING)
This way!
The army has destroyed
this part of the city.
I sure hope Dola
and the boys are all right.
Me too. Where are they,
do you see them?
Wait, there they are!
They've got them prisoner.
SHEETA: They've been captured!
We've gotta help them.
If we don't,
they'll hang 'em from the yardarm.
-What'll we do?
- Come on. Hurry.
Sir! Sir!
We've managed
to break down the wall, General.
Just a sample of what we found inside.
The city is full of treasure, sir.
- Momma...
-Whoa...
Would you like to have this?
Well, I've got a different kind
of necldace for you.
Have you radioed a report
on Laputa's discovery, Muska?
I was about to.
See if you can make it
difficult to decode.
And stop pocketing
those jewels, you scum!
The perfect thing to throw
those fools off the scent.
We're up so high.
I hope you're good at climbing trees,
Sheeta.
I've got a plan.
Whoa!
(EXPLOSIONS)
(SHOUTING)
PAZU: What a greedy pack of thieves.
We can't let them destroy the garden,
Pazu.
We have to find
the etherium crystal.
(GASPS)
We have to find it.
It's the only way
we can protect the garden.
I was wondering why
all the storm clouds just disappeared.
Then I realized,
if they hadn't cleared up,
the army couldn't have made a landing.
You think it was
because of my necldace?
Well, I don't know for sure,
but I think the power of the crystal
disintegrated that storm,
and now,
the castle has awakened from its sleep
for whoever holds the crystal.
We can't let Muska
figure out how to use the crystal.
If he does,
it'll be the end of everything.
But even if we can
get my grandmother's crystal back,
how can we use its power?
The spell, Pazu.
The spell of destruction.
Sheeta, it may be the only way.
SOLDIER 1:We need help over here!
SOLDIER 2:You, go find the general.
Quickly.
We need to get down there.
- I'll go first.
- Right. Be careful.
-Whoal
- Oh!
(GASPING)
It's okay. Whoa!
MUSKA: It's around here somewhere.
It should be here.
This is it!
{PAZU SHOUTS)
It's the boy!
Sheetal
- Stop!
- Don't shoot.
Well, well. Looks like we caught
a little princess.
Don't hurt her!
It came from over here.
Colonel, what's happening?
We've found another pirate.
And there's one more
hiding under your feet.
Yes, sir! We'll get him!
Sheeta, I'll find you!
Pazu!
Is that Pazu?
That wasn't me.
- I need the commanding officer.
-That way.
-The general's waiting over there.
- Guards, on the double! Now!
You men, come with me.
- Right away, sir.
-Yes, sir.
Dola.
Hi there. Sheeta's been captured.
I'm gonna save her.
When I cut your ropes,
make a run for it.
Good luck, now, Captain.
Wait a minute, boy.
You'd better take this.
Huh?
Thank you.
The boy has become a man.
What do you mean,
Muska's destroyed all the radios?
Sir, he must have done it
while most of the men were outside.
Several of the guards
have been seriously injured.
We've spotted Muska heading
for the black dome below, sir.
He's not alone,
he's got those other two men with him.
So Colonel Muska
reveals his true nature at last.
Now find him and arrest him!
- All right! First platoon, move!
- Second platoon, fall in!
You are to shoot
anyone who resists!
We must find Colonel Muska now!
Excuse me,
Colonel Muska, where are we?
We are in the center of Laputa.
The castle above us means nothing.
All of Laputa's scientific knowledge
is contained in this chamber.
-You may wait here, gentlemen.
- Colonel, please!
This is a sacred place
where only royalty is allowed to enter.
What's happened here?
These filthy roots
don't belong in this chamber.
Horrible things, I'll have them burned.
This way, come.
There it isl This is it. See?
Not here too! Ugh!
Roots!
At last! At last I have found it!
The largest etherium crystal ever,
and the source
of all the power in Laputa.
The amazing thing is,
this beautiful stone has been awaiting
the return of its king for 700 years.
SHEETA: 700 years?
700 years is a long time
to be without a king, isn't it?
It's the black stone.
Just as the legend says.
{INSECTS BUZZING)
Get away.
There it is, it's the same.
Who are you, Muska?
Yes, my dear,
I too have an old, secret name.
My real name is
Romuska Palo Ur Laputa.
You and I have the same royal
ancestors, we are both of noble blood,
but our ancestors left Laputa
to live on Earth. What a mistake.
-The explosives have no effect.
-This is no ordinary stone.
Then use
all of the dynamite we have.
MUSKA: General, there's no need
to do that. You may come in.
Where are you, Muskal
{(WHIRRING)
{MEN SCREAM)
Huh?
(YELLING)
MUSKA: Really, I don't understand
why you hesitate, General.
Please come in.
- Blast him. All right, follow me!
- Let's gol
After him, men!
Wait a minute, hold on, hold on.
Where is this guy? All right...
Just where are you, Muska?
MUSKA: Please, be quiet.
-What?
- Up there, look!
What's going on?
Hold your tongue, commoner.
You are in the presence
of the king of Laputa.
The man has gone crazy.
1 thought I would show you
an example of Laputa's power.
We are about to celebrate the rebirth
of the Laputian kingdom.
Sheeta?
Prepare yourself
for the thunder of Laputa.
Sheeta, I'm coming.
The fire of heaven that destroyed
Sodom and Gomorrah
in the Old Testament.
The Ramayana
referred to it as Indra's Arrow.
The entire world will once again
kneel before the power of Laputal
I can only say, well done, Muska.
You're a credit to our country.
As such, you deserve this reward.
Huh?
I have really had enough
of your incredible stupidity.
Run, everyone!
Goodbye!
{ALL SCREAM)
{LAUGHS WICKEDLY)
{MUSKA CONTINUES TO LAUGH)
- Blimey, more robots.
-Yeah, and there's a lot of them.
Make a run for it!
- Check the Flaptors.
- Okay, Mom!
They're ready to travel!
Time to go, Mommal
Hush up.
They don't know we're here.
Tarnation,
now where are Pazu and Sheeta?
Can't leave without 'em.
You had better be gracious
to the new king, dear.
You and I will be spending
quite a lot of time together.
Look at the fools.
Unbelievably stupid.
Pathetic.
They simply don't understand.
It is useless to fight me.
Robots!
{ELECTRONIC BEEPS)
Sheetal
A superior being such as myself
has only one option.
Burn them.
Don't you agree, Princess Lucita?
{MUSKA LAUGHS WICKEDLY)
Insolent little brat!
Sheetal
Be a good girl
and give the crystal back.
Please, open up! Please!
Sheeta, listen to me. Be reasonable.
There's no way you can escape.
Please, open! Help me!
Sheetal
{MUSKA LAUGHS)
PAZU: Sheeta!
Pazu?
-Where are you?
- PAZU: Sheeta, over here!
Sheeta.
You're alive!
- Stand back, I'm gonna blast through.
- Here we gol
- No, Pazu!
Hurry, take this!
Muska's coming, hurry!
Here, take it.
Throw it into the ocean.
{GUN FIRING)
Better protect that crystal
if you wanna see the girl alive.
Do you hear me?
(CLICKING)
{GUNSHOT NEARBY)
(SHEETA GASPS)
(SHEETA SCREAMS)
Get up, Princess! The game is over.
How appropriate that we've ended up
in the throne room.
Now get over here!
This is no longer a throne room.
This is a tomb for the both of us.
You see, a king without compassion
does not deserve a kingdom.
You will never possess the crystal.
You and I will die here, together.
Now I understand why
the people of Laputa vanished.
There's a song from my home
in the valley of Gondoa
that explains everything.
It says,
"Take root in the ground.
Live in harmony with the wind.
"Plant your seeds in the winter.
"And rejoice with the birds
in the coming of spring.”
No matter how many weapons you have,
no matter how great
your technology might be,
the world cannot live without love.
Laputa will live.
1 will return it to life.
Laputa's power
is the dream of all mankind.
Your ears are next,
unless you get on your knees
and obey me.
I command you, give me that stone!
PAZU: Stop right there, Muska.
I've hidden the stone.
If you do anything to harm Sheeta,
you'll never get it back.
No, Pazuy, listen.
Run away
before he kills you as well as me.
Look who's here.
Why don't you give me the stone
and the girl will live.
Otherwise I'll kill her.
Are you planning on fighting me?
Go ahead!
Use that cannon you can hardly lift.
You can have the stone
if you let me talk to Sheeta.
No, Pazu, get out of here
and throw the crystal away!
I'll give you one minute starting now.
Oh, Pazu!
Sheeta, listen to me very carefully.
Whisper the spell to me.
I'll say it with you.
Just put your hand
in mine and trust me.
Dola and the boys are free,
don't worry about them.
Time's up. What is your answer?
BOTH: Balus.
(SCREAMS)
{LOUD RUMBLING)
My eyes! I can't see!
No! No!
-We can't wait anymore, Mom!
- All right, then, let's shove off!
Hurry up!
Look at that,
the whole thing's collapsing!
Poor kids. I'll really miss them.
They used the spell of destruction.
They saved Laputa
from the evil hands of Muska.
{SNIFFs)
Mother, look! What is that
big blue light up there?
It's a big stone.
That tree's getting away
with our treasure.
Get it! Get it! Move! Come on, you...
{ALL SHOUTING)
Sheeta?
Pazu?
Looks like these roots saved us.
It looks fine. It should work.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Now!
What's going on here?
It's getting away from us!
Why the deuce
aren't we gaining altitude?
There's just
too much weight to gain alt...
Sheetal
{ALL CHEER)
MAN: Sheeta's alive!
- Dola!
-Thank goodness you're alive!
So are you. This is great!
No, it's not! My poor little ship
is gone forever! (SOBS)
Stop with the crying, you big baby.
I'll get you another ship!
Poor little thing, nothing worse
than having your pigtails shot off.
What have you got under there?
My fault. You must have hurt
yourself on these.
Now how'd they get inside my blouse?
All good pirates listen to their mom.
Bye!
- (LAUGHTER)
- Bye-bye!