(DISTANT METALLIC THUDDING)
(NOISE GETTING LOUDER)
(CREAKING AND HISSING)
(SILENCE)
(CREAKING ANDTHUDDING)
(DISTANT BELLS RINGING)
(TRAIN WHISTLES)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Sophie, we closed the shop.
You've done enough work.
Why don't you come out with us
this time?
No, I better finish this.
You go and have fun.
WOMAN: All right, suit yourself.
Let's go, girls.
GIRL 1: Wait for me!
GIRL 2: I'm ready.
GIRL 2: Do I look okay?
GIRL 3: It's Howl's castle!
GIRL 2: Where?
GIRL 1: Howl?
GIRL 3: I've never seen it close!
GIRL 1:
Do you think Howl will go into town?
(DISTANT HISSING AND CREAKING)
GIRL 1: He's gone.
GIRL 2: No, he's just hiding in the fog
from those planes.
GIRL 3: Did you hear what happened
to that girl Martha from South Haven?
They say Howl tore her heart out.
- GIRL 1: I'm scared to go out!
- What?
Don't worry,
he only preys on pretty girls.
(ALL LAUGHING)
WOMAN: All right, let's go.
GIRL 1:You girls are mean.
It's not funny.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(SIGHS)
(VEHICLES PASSING)
- (DOOR OPENING)
- (BELL JINGLING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(BELL RINGS)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYS)
(CHEERING AND WHISTLING)
(SOPHIE GASPS)
(CHEERING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(GASPS)
Hey. Looks like a little mouse
lost its way.
Oh, no, I'm not lost.
This little mouse looks thirsty.
We should take her for a cup of tea.
No, thanks, my sister's expecting me.
She's pretty cute for a mouse.
How old are you? You live around here?
Leave me alone.
You see?
Your moustache scares all the girls.
So? She's even cuter
when she's scared.
MAN: There you are, sweetheart.
Sorry I'm late.
I was looking everywhere.
Hey, we're busy here.
Are you really?
It looked to me
like the two of you were just leaving.
(GRUNTING) Hup!
Hup! (GRUNTING)
Whoa!
Don't hold it against them.
They're actually not all that bad.
Where to?
I'll be your escort this evening.
Oh, I'm, um, just going to the bakery.
Don't get alarmed,
but I'm being followed.
Act normal.
- Sorry. Looks like you're involved.
- (GASPS)
This way.
(SNORING)
- Hold on.
- (GASPS)
(GASPS)
Now, straighten your legs
and start walking.
(GASPING)
See? Not so hard, is it?
(LAUGHING)
You are a natural.
(CHATTERING)
(SIGHS)
I'll make sure to draw them off.
But wait a bit
before you head back outside.
Okay.
That's my girl.
(GASPING)
MAN: Excuse me, could we trouble
you for some more coffee?
-There you go.
- Do you have Lettie-shaped cookies?
- MAN: I'd buy those.
- Here.
What time do you get off?
She what?
- I'm here, where're you going?
- Hey!
Sophie?
- Lettie.
- What's going on?
Someone just told me
you floated down onto our balcony.
So that did happen. It wasn't a dream.
Lettie, would you like to use my office?
1 should really get back to work.
Thank you, though.
Wow. He must have
been a wizard, then.
But he was so kind to me.
He rescued me, Lettie.
Of course he did.
He was trying to steal your heart!
You are so lucky, Sophie.
If that wizard were Howl,
he would have eaten it.
No, he wouldn't.
Howl only does that to beautiful girls.
Don't give me that.
You need to be more careful.
It's dangerous out there.
Even the Witch of the Waste
is back on the prowl.
- Are you listening?
- Huh?
Ugh!
Lettie, the chocolate éclairs are done.
Okay. I'll be right there.
MAN: Thanks.
All right. I better get going then.
I just wanted to make sure
that you were doing okay.
- Hello, Lettie.
- Hi, how are you doing?
Sophie, do you really want to spend
the rest of your life in that hat shop?
The shop was just
so important to Father.
And I'm the eldest, I don't mind.
I'm not asking
what Father would have wanted.
I want to know what you want.
Well...
See you later, Lettie.
- Good seeing you again.
-You, too.
- I better be going.
- It's your life, Sophie.
- Do something for yourself for once. Will
you?
- Bye, Lettie.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(TAPPING)
(CREAKING)
(BELL JINGLING)
I'm sorry,
but the shop's closed now, ma'am.
I could have sworn I locked that door.
Must have forgotten.
What a tacky shop.
I've never seen such tacky little hats.
Yet you're by far the tackiest thing here.
I'm afraid you will have to leave now.
The door's over here, ma'am.
We're closed.
Standing up to the Witch of the Waste,
that's plucky.
The Witch of the Waste? (GASPS)
(HOWLING)
The best part of that spell
is you can't tell anyone about it.
My regards to Howl.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh. No.
Oh!
(GASPING)
That's really me, isn't it?
I've got to stay calm.
(SHRIEKS)
I've got to stay calm!
Now, there's no use
panicking, Sophie. Oh!
It's a bad dream, that's all.
Just go inside, go to bed.
You're gonna be fine, Sophie.
You're gonna be fine.
Got to stay calm.
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
Look who's here!
-You're back!
- Look at you!
What do you think?
It's all the rage in Kingsbury.
It's
go
rgeou
sl
I know!
Our customers will love it! Sophie!
Sophie!
GIRL: Your daughter
hasn't come downstairs yet today.
That's strange. I wonder what's wrong.
Sophie!
MOTHER: Sophie!
- (POUNDING ON DOOR}
- Sophie!
Don't come in here. I've got a bad cold.
I don't want you to catch it.
You sound ghastly,
like some 90-year-old woman.
SOPHIE:
I'll just stay in bed all day, so you go on.
Well, if you insist.
Up we go.
This isn't so bad, now, Is it?
You're still in pretty good shape.
And your clothes finally suit you.
(GIRLS TALKING AND LAUGHING)
But you can't stay here like this for long.
Oh! Being old is worse than I thought.
MAN 1:They say their prince is missing.
MAN 2: And they're blaming us.
MAN 1:Yeah, and it sounds like
they're gonna start a war over it.
MAN 2: Nobody wants to go to war.
MAN 1: Let's hope
the prince turns up soon.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(COUGHING)
Excuse me, could you use some help?
I'll be fine, but thanks for offering.
That was really kind.
MAN: Sure, there's room in back,
but where are you headed?
Just a little ways farther
than where you're going.
MAN:You're crazy
if you do this, Grandma!
There's nothing but witches
and wizards out there!
SOPHIE:Thank you.
I'll keep that in mind.
WOMAN: She's going to
the Wastes by herself?
MAN: She says she's looking
for her younger sister.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
I'll never get there with these legs.
At least my teeth haven't
fallen out yet.
That would make a nice cane.
Up we go.
Oh. (GROANING)
Might be too big. (GROANING)
This is one stubborn branch.
(PANTING)
You're not getting the best
of this old lady.
(GROANING)
Oh!
Just a scarecrow!
I was afraid you were
one of those blob men.
But how're you standing
on your own like that?
You're head's a turnip.
I've always hated tumips,
ever since I was little.
At least you're not upside down now.
So long.
(WIND HOWLING)
It's too cold.
And I can still see the town.
I've barely moved.
- (TAPPING)
- Hmm?
Go away! Quit following me!
There's no need to thank me,
you don't owe me a thing.
I'm sure you have
some kind of spell on you,
and I've had more than enough
of witches and spells.
So, just go find some field
and stand in it!
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
Thank you, this cane is perfect,
it's just what I need.
If you'd like to do me one more favor,
you could run off
and find me a place to stay.
{CHUCKLING) I seem to have become
quite cunning in my old age.
(ENGINE ROARING)
- A battleship! Oh!
- (WIND ROARING)
Why do you get so cold
when you're old?
I'm fatter than ever,
yet the wind blows right through me.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Someone's got a fire going.
Maybe there's a cabin nearby.
(HISSING AND CREAKING)
(GASPING)
(RATTLING ANDTHUDDING)
You turnip-head! That's Howl's castle!
That is not what I meant
when I asked for a place to stay.
(HISSING)
(METALLIC GROWLING)
Look at that. They call this a castle?
Ah!
Is that the way in?
Slow down!
For heaven's sake.
Make up your mind.
Are you gonna let me in or not?
Whoa!
Oh, my shawl!
It's nice and warm in there,
so I'm going in.
Oh, my shawl, thank you.
I'm sure Howl won't eat the heart
of a shriveled, old lady like me.
It's been a pleasure meeting you.
Even if you are
my least favorite vegetable.
Take care, Turnip-head.
(SIGHING)
Ah.
There we go.
What a dump.
When I think castle,
this is not what I picture.
Well, one nice thing about getting old
is nothing frightens you.
(SIGHING)
1 don't envy you, lady.
That is one bad curse.
Curses are tough. You're gonna have
a hard time getting rid of that one.
The fire spoke!
FIRE: The curse won't allow you
to talk about it, right?
Are you Howl?
No, I'm an extremely powerful
fire demon named Calcifer.
I just like to do that once in a while.
A fire demon. Well, then,
you should be able to break my curse.
Maybe, maybe not.
Listen, if you can find a way
to break the spell that's on me,
then I'll break the spell that's on you,
you got it?
If you're a demon,
how do I know I can trust you?
You promise to help me if I help you?
1 don't know, lady.
Demons don't make promises.
Then go find someone else.
Come on! You should feel sorry for me!
That spell keeps me stuck in this castle,
and Howl treats me like I'm his slave.
It burns me up. Got to keep
the water hot, the rooms warm,
- keep the castle moving.
- Oh, that's rough.
You ever try to move a castle?
If you can figure out how
to break this thing I'm in with Howl,
then you can break my spell.
After that, I can easily
break the spell that's on you.
All right, it's a deal.
(SNORING)
Hey, lady? Lady?
Hello? Lady? Hello? Hey, hey!
Lady? Lady?
Hey, let me get over there.
Some big help you're gonna be.
{CREAKING AND RATTLING)
- (CHEERING)
- (MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(SNORING)
(POUNDING ON DOOR}
- (POUNDING CONTINUES)
- (GROANING)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (GASPS)
(SNORING)
- Hey, who's this lady?
- (POUNDING)
- CALCIFER: Porthaven door.
- How'd she get in here?
(DEEP VOICE) Stand by.
(CLICKS)
(DEEP VOICE) Mr. Mayor, good day.
Good afternoon, sir.
Would the great
Wizard Jenkins be at home?
I am afraid that my master
is out at the moment.
1 speak for him in his absence.
An invitation from His Majesty the King.
The time for war is upon us.
His Majesty requires that every witch
and wizard aid our homeland.
Wizard Jenkins must report
to the palace immediately.
-That is all.
- SOPHIE: War...
I can't believe it's come to this.
And what do you think
you're doing here, Grandma?
Calcifer said that I could come in.
1 did not. She just wandered in here
from the Wastes.
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
She's from the Wastes?
How do we know that she's not a witch?
Do you think I'd let a witch in here?
- (DOORBELL TINKLES)
- Porthaven door again!
Must be a customer.
(DEEP VOICE) Stand by.
Yes, my dear child?
My mom sent me to pick up a spell.
BOY: Ah, yes, do come in.
GIRL: Okay.
Just keep quiet
and don't cause any trouble, Grandma.
(SEAGULLS CRYING)
It's not the Wastes.
Excuse me, Granny,
are you a witch, too?
That's right.
I'm the scariest witch of them all.
(GIRL GIGGLING)
BOY: Dust your ship with this powder
and the winds will favor it.
Thanks.
BOY: Farewell, child.
{DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
(NORMAL VOICE)
Quit telling lies to our customers.
What about you?
You're wearing a disguise.
I have to. I'm practicing my magic.
- (DOORBELL JINGLES)
- Hmm?
It's the Kingsbury door!
(DEEP VOICE) Stand by.
(CLICKS)
Would this be the residence
of the great Wizard Pendragon?
It is.
MAN: I bear an invitation
from His Majesty the King.
Please inform Mr. Pendragon
that all witches and wizards
are required to report
for duty at the palace.
1 will inform him right away.
(SOPHIE GASPING)
- (STEAM BLOWING)
- (ENGINE CHUGGING)
This is the royal city, isn't it?
BOY: Move it, Grandma,
or you'll lose your nose.
And stop wandering around!
(CLICKS)
(GASPS)
(WIND BLOWING)
(CHUCKLING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
BOY: Leave it alone, Grandma.
I'm getting angry.
-This is a magic house, isn't it?
- Ugh.
So, tell me,
where does the black one lead?
Only Master Howl knows that.
I need some breakfast. I'm starved.
Don't you want to have
some bacon and eggs?
Yeah, but we can't use the fire.
Master Howl's not here.
(CHUCKLING)
Don't worry, I can cook.
BOY: It doesn't matter.
Calcifer only obeys Master Howl.
That's right, lady.
I'm not taking orders from you.
(CALCIFER BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Oh, there's my hat. (GROANING)
That's better.
All right, Calcifer. Let's get cooking.
I don't cook!
I'm a scary and powerful fire demon!
(JABBERING)
How would you like a bucket
of cold water in your face?
Or maybe I should tell Howl about
our bargain?
Oh! Stupid me!
I never should have let her in here.
- So, what'll it be?
- (MUFFLED GRUNTING)
That's right. That's a good fire.
(SIZZLING)
Here's another curse.
May all your bacon burn.
Calcifer's doing what she says.
SOPHIE: I think I'd like some tea, too.
Do you have a kettle?
- Sure.
- CALCIFER: Hey, what are you doing?
Don't get the kettle!
Who's side are you on, anyway?
Markl, what are you doing?
- (CLICKS)
- MARKL: Huh?
Master Howl,
the king's messengers were here.
They said you have to report
to the palace
as both Pendragon and Jenkins.
(SIZZLING)
Calcifer? You're being so obedient.
Not on purpose. She bullied me.
Not just anybody can do that.
And you are who?
Uh, you can just
call me Grandma Sophie.
I'm your new cleaning lady.
I just started work today.
Give that to me.
Oh!
Hand me two more slices of that bacon
and six more of those eggs.
(SIZZLING)
Yummy.
(GROWLING)
So, then, who hired you to clean?
Uh, Calcifer did.
He's disgusted by how dirty it is in here.
Markl, get the plates.
Wait a second, you're all gonna eat
while I do all the work?
MARKL: Come have
some breakfast, Sophie.
(CALCIFER JABBERING)
Take a seat. Hhm.
Which do you want?
You only get one
‘cause the rest are dirty.
Looks like I've got
my work cut out for me.
- Bread, Markl?
-Thanks.
- HOWL: Sophie?
-Yes, thank you.
- So, friends, enjoy. Bon appétit.
- Bon appétit.
I can't remember the last time
we had a real breakfast.
{CHOMPING AND SLURPING)
Even the manners are a mess
in this house.
So, what do you have hidden
in your pocket, Sophie?
Huh? Oh...
- What is this?
- HOWL: Give it to me.
Oh!
(GASPS) Scorch marks.
Howl, can you read them?
That is ancient sorcery.
And quite powerful, too.
It's from the Witch of the Waste?
"You who swallowed a falling star,
"0 heartless man,
your heart shall soon belong to me."
That can't be good for the table.
(SIZZLING)
(GASPING)
Wow! It's gone!
The mark may be gone,
but the spell is still there.
Excuse me, my friends,
please continue your meal.
Calcifer, move the castle
60 miles to the west.
(GULPING AND SLURPING)
And while you're at it,
make hot water for my bath.
CALCIFER: Fine. Like moving the castle
isn't hard enough?
You're not working for
the Witch of the Waste, are you?
1 would never work for that witch!
She's the one who...
(GROANING)
I'm actually a...
If I ever get my hands on that witch,
I'm going to wring her fat neck!
Finish your breakfast! (GRUMBLING)
I've had enough of this!
You bugs better run
before I bite your heads off!
I'm sick of being treated
like some timid little old lady.
(CHATTERING)
Hello, sir, is my potion ready?
(DEEP VOICE) Come back later.
There's a witch on a rampage in there.
CALCIFER: Sophie, please!
Sophie! Please help me. I'm going out!
Please, get me some firewood, quick!
Hey, please help me.
Wait, what are you doing?
Don't! I'll fall! You crazy lady with tongs!
-You'll be fine.
- I'll fall! Help!
I'm just sweeping out the ashes.
No, I'm not fine! (COUGHING)
Please! I'm going out!
- (HUMMING)
- (COUGHING)
Please. I'm falling.
(MOANING)
Help, I'm falling!
Sophie, hurry up, please.
Hurry, please.
(MOANING)
Whoa!
(POOF)
(GASPING)
I'd appreciate it
if you didn't torment my friend.
Master Howl, are you going out now?
(CLICKS)
Markl, make sure the cleaning lady
doesn't get carried away while I'm gone.
(WIND HOWLING)
(CLICKS)
Sophie, what did you do now?
CALCIFER: She almost smothered me!
If 1 die, Howl dies, too, I hope you know.
Oh, be quiet. You're all right.
Now quit bothering me,
I've got a job to do.
(MOANING)
Wait, you can't come up here!
Whatever you don't want me to clean,
better hide it now.
(GASPING)
Save my room for last, okay?
(CHUCKLING)
These little outbursts
seem to be giving me some energy.
What a mess.
(GROANING)
Oh!
(WIND HOWLING)
{CREAKING AND RATTLING)
Incredible! Calcifer! Calcifer!
Are you the one moving the castle?
CALCIFER: Of course. No one
else does any work around here.
I am thoroughly impressed!
You are a first-class fire demon.
I like your spark.
She likes my spark! Ha-ha!
(HISSING)
Ah! Not ready! Not ready!
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
(ANIMAL HOWLING)
It's beautiful.
Yeah. It's called Star Lake.
Hey, what's that stick doing in there?
Oh, dear. Give me a hand, Markl.
(BOTH GROANING)
It's a scarecrow.
Yep, I've been calling him Tumip-head.
Somehow he always manages
to get stuck upside down.
(MARKL GASPS)
He keeps following me everywhere.
Seems to have taken a liking to me.
That's weird. Are you sure
you're not a witch, Sophie?
Oh, yes! I'm the worst kind
of witch ever, the kind that cleans.
(HISSING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Quit pulling so hard, Tumip-head!
I think he likes doing the laundry.
Looks like he'll have it dry in no time.
I bet he's some kind of demon.
Calcifer doesn't seem to mind him at all.
You're right. He probably is a demon.
But he led me here,
$0 maybe he's the good kind.
We got all the laundry
put away, Sophie.
Oh, thank you, Markl.
When you're old, all you want
to do is stare at the scenery.
It's so strange,
I've never felt so peaceful before.
(WIND HOWLING)
(HISSING)
(SHRIEKING)
(CLICKS)
(EXHALES)
CALCIFER: Whew.
You okay? I mean, you smell terrible.
(GROANING)
You shouldn't keep flying around
like that.
Soon you won't be able
to turn back into a human.
Isn't this great?
Sophie put these here for me.
This war is terrible.
They've bombed from the southern
coast to the northern border.
It's all in flames now.
I can't stand the fire in gunpowder.
Those dopey guys
have absolutely no manners.
My own kind attacked me today.
- Who, the Witch of the Waste?
- No,
some hack wizards who turned
themselves into monsters for the king.
Those wizards are going
to regret doing that.
They'll never change back into humans.
After the war,
they won't recall they ever were human.
Hey, aren't you supposed
to report to the king, too?
I'm tired.
Make some hot water for my bath.
What? Not again.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(ROARING)
(GASPING)
- Is Howl back?
-Yes.
He's wasting all my hot water again.
MARKL:
1 don't know why we're doing this.
Master Howl hardly eats anything.
Too bad.
- Good morning.
Don't you love early morning markets?
And just look at the water!
I've never seen the ocean before!
It's beautiful!
MARKL: It always looks like that.
(CHATTERING AND SHOUTING)
- (DEEP VOICE) Hmm. I hate potatoes.
- Pay up.
-Thanks, have a nice day.
- MAN: Thank you, come again.
All our fish
were caught fresh this morning.
Hmm, I hate fish.
MAN 1:
One of our ships is in the harbor!
MAN 2: It looks like it's on fire!
Looks like there's been a serious battle.
What happened?
Sorry, lady, we're closed.
MAN: The ship, it's sinking!
(SHOUTING)
- (HORN BLOWS)
- (BELL RINGING)
(SHOUTING)
Come on, Sophie, let's get a better look.
No, I've seen all I can take.
Let's go home.
I can't believe it.
It's our most advanced battleship.
(GASPING)
The witch's henchmen are here.
- What?
- Quiet down.
They're only a few feet away.
He's gone.
I don't understand why
no one else seemed to notice him.
(GASPING)
Look! There they are!
That plane!
That's what dropped the bombs!
Look, Sophie. It's the enemy's airship!
Sophie! Wait up! Sophie!
MAN: Ignore the flyers.
They're enemy propaganda.
(SOPHIE GASPING)
Sophie, are you okay?
I just need a glass of water.
I'll get it.
(PANTING)
(HOWL SHRIEKING)
Sophie! You sabotaged me! Look!
Look what you've done to my hair!
Look!
- What a pretty color.
- It's hideous!
You completely ruined
my magic potions in the bathroom.
I just organized things, Howl,
nothing's ruined.
Wrong! Wrong!
1 specifically ordered you
not to get carried away!
(CRYING) Now I'm repulsive.
I can't live like this.
Come on, it's not that bad.
You should look at it now.
This shade is even better.
1 give up.
I see no point in living
if I can't be beautiful.
(RUMBLING)
{RUMBLING GROWING LOUDER)
(HOWLING)
Howl, cut it out. Howl, no, stop it.
He's calling the Spirits of Darkness.
I saw him do this once before
when a girl dumped him.
Now, Howl, you're all right.
We'll just dye your hair back again.
Okay? Oh!
Fine! So, you think you've got it bad?
I've never once been beautiful
in my entire life!
I've had enough of this place!
(WHIMPERING)
Thank you, Turnip-head.
How did you get to be so kind?
Sophie, get back inside,
we need your help! Howl's in trouble!
Howl, cut it out! I'm gonna drown!
I'm drowning here, Howl. Sophie!
Sophie, help him, please!
Sophie! Do something!
- Such drama.
- Is he dead?
No, he's fine.
He's just throwing a tantrum.
- Come on. Give me a hand.
- Okay.
(SOPHIE AND MARKL STRAINING)
- Get the hot water running.
- MARKL: Right.
Come on, Howl, you can still walk.
- Get him cleaned up, Markl.
- MARKL: 1 will.
Now I have to mop again.
(PLAYING FANFARE)
This says they've landed
on the coast already.
- Where?
- North.
(CHIME RINGING)
{KNOCKING ON DOOR)
SOPHIE: Howl, I'm coming in.
I brought you some warm milk.
Want a sip?
I'll leave it here for you, then.
Try to drink it before it gets cold.
Sophie, wait.
Do you want some milk?
(RINGING)
The Witch of the Waste
is trying to find my castle.
(GASPS)
I saw her henchmen at the harbor.
I am such a big coward, all I do is hide.
And all of this magic
is just to keep everybody away.
I can't stand how scared I am.
Howl, why is the Witch of the Waste
trying to hunt you down?
She was once quite beautiful,
so I decided to pursue her.
Then I realized she wasn't.
So, as usual, I ran away.
I can't run much longer, though.
I have to report to the palace,
as both Pendragon and Jenkins.
How many aliases
do you have, anyway?
- As many as I need to keep my freedom.
- Hmm.
- Just refuse the king's invitation.
- See that?
That's the oath I took when
I entered the Royal Sorcery Academy.
I must report to the palace
whenever summoned.
You know, Howl,
I think that you should see the king.
What?
Give him a piece of your mind.
Tell him this war is pointless.
And you refuse to take part, huh?
(SIGHING)
You obviously don't know
what these people are like.
But he's our king.
He should want to hear
what all his citizens have to say.
(GASPS) I got it!
Why don't you go to the palace for me?
Huh?
Just say
that you're Pendragon's mother,
and your son is such a cowardly wizard,
he's too afraid to show his face.
Maybe then Madame Suliman
will finally give up on me.
Who's Madame Suliman?
You're wearing that hat?
After all the magic I used
to make your dress pretty?
-Take care of him, Markl.
- Mmm-hmm.
CALCIFER: Good luck.
- (CLICKS)
- (SOPHIE GASPING)
This charm will
guarantee your safe return.
Don't worry.
I'll follow behind you in disguise.
Now. Off you go.
Why do I feel like
this is not going to work?
(CAWING)
I wonder what Howl
disguised himself as.
Surely not a crow.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Can't be a pigeon,
he's too flamboyant for that.
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
That could be him.
Look how far I still have to go.
(ENGINE ROARING)
MAN: Come on! Step right up!
(APPLAUSE)
- (CHATTERING)
- (APPLAUSE)
Howl?You disguised yourself
as an old dog?
(COUGHS)
(GROANS)
You couldn't think
of something a bit more useful?
Do you know how hard it is
to do things when you're old?
Look who's here.
The tacky little girl from the hat shop.
The Witch of the Waste.
Thank you for handing
my scorching love note to Howl.
How's he doing, by the way?
He's acting like a big baby.
And he's working me to the bone
as his cleaning lady.
(CHUCKLING) How delightful.
So, tell me, what business
do you have here at the palace?
Job hunting.
I'm sick of working for Howl.
And what about yourself?
I received a royal invitation.
That idiot Suliman finally realized
how much she needs my powers.
If you're so great,
why don't you break the spell
you put on me?
I'm sorry, dear.
My talent lies in casting spells,
not breaking them.
Bye, Granny.
Now, just wait a minute!
You get back here right now!
If 1 didn't have you to worry about,
I would have clobbered her.
What on earth is wrong with you two?
Sorry, ma'am.
Vehicles are prohibited
beyond this point.
You must continue on foot.
That Suliman.
Using her magic to force me
to climb all those godforsaken stairs.
(SNIFFING)
(SNEEZING)
(DOG WHEEZING)
Come on, Howl.
We can do this, just act natural.
(GROANING)
(COUGHS)
Oh!
(GROANING)
Howl, why are you so heavy?
(BOTH PANTING AND STRAINING)
(GROANING)
Wait. Help. I can't make it.
What'd you say?
You suddenly remembered how
to break the spell you put on me?
1 told you. I don't know how.
(GROANING)
Then start studying.
I don't get it.
Where does she get all that energy?
(GROANING)
I have to rest a bit.
(PANTING)
(MOANING)
Why don't you just give up?
You're killing yourself.
I've waited for 50 years now
to be invited here.
Ever since that Suliman
banished me to live in the Wastes.
Well, good luck, then.
Too bad I'm not younger,
or I'd lend you a hand.
Come on, Howl.
You cold-hearted old hag.
Next time, I'll turn you senile, too.
(BELLS RINGING)
Almost there!
Honored guest, please follow me.
You should go help her
get up these stairs.
I am strictly forbidden
to offer such assistance.
That's so rude.
The king himself invited her.
Come on! Let's go!
Don't give up now!
Are you a witch or aren't you?
(GROANING)
Just shut up.
What happened?
You look so much older.
MAN: Mrs. Pendragon
and the Witch of the Waste!
(WITCH PANTING)
SOPHIE: Pull yourself together.
Isn't this what you've been waiting for?
MAN: Mrs. Pendragon
and the Witch of the Waste!
Your name's Pendragon?
Why does that name sound so familiar?
Uh, because that was
the name of my tacky hat shop,
- don't you remember?
- Is that what it was?
MAN: Wait in here, please.
(DOOR CREAKS AND SLAMS)
(GASPS)
A chair! It's mine!
(MOANING)
Howl, get back here.
Oh!
This way please, ma'am.
Huh?
(HUMMING)
(SHRIEKING)
{HUMMING GROWING LOUDER)
(RUNNING WATER)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
MAN: Thank you, Madame Suliman.
MEN: Madame Suliman.
So, you are Howl's mother, are you?
Yes, I'm Mrs. Pendragon.
You must be tired. Please have a seat.
Thank you.
I am Madame Suliman,
His Majesty's head sorceress.
(SQUEAKS)
That's not your dog, is it?
His name is Heen. He's my errand dog.
I had him escort you here.
(GASPS)
Oh.
I take it Howl won't be joining us?
He's such a lazy son,
he sent me instead.
I'm afraid the king would
find him completely useless.
I am very sorry to hear that.
Howl was the last apprentice
I ever took on.
I'd never seen such a gifted student.
I was so thrilled
to have finally found someone
talented enough to replace me.
Then, one day,
his heart was stolen by a demon.
He never returned
to complete his apprenticeship.
And from that day forward,
he has been using his magic
for entirely selfish reasons.
- Mrs. Pendragon.
-Yes?
That boy is extremely dangerous.
His powers are far too great
for someone without a heart.
If he stays selfish,
I'm afraid he'll end up
just like the Witch of the Waste.
Send her in.
(GASPS)
What on earth happened to you?
(HEAVY BREATHING)
I just restored her
to the age she actually is.
All her powers are gone now.
Once, she, too, was a magnificent
sorcerer with so much promise.
But then she fell prey
to a demon of greed,
who slowly consumed her,
body and soul.
Our kingdom can no longer
afford to turn a blind eye
to these disreputable
witches and wizards.
If Howl reports to me
and vows to use his magic
to serve the kingdom,
1 will show him
how to break from his demon.
If not, I'll strip him of all his powers.
Just like her.
That is enough!
Now I understand why Howl was
so concerned about coming to see you.
It's a trap.
You lure people here
with an invitation from the king,
and then you strip them
of all their powers.
Howl would never be so heartless.
He may be selfish and cowardly,
and sometimes
he's hard to understand,
but his intentions are good.
He just wants to be free.
Howl won't come here.
He doesn't need your help.
He can fix his problem
with his demon on his own.
I am certain of it.
Now I understand.
You're in love with Howl.
- (GASPS)
- Howl? Did you say Howl's coming?
I want his heart,
his heart belongs to me! (SOBBING)
Stop that, just calm down.
Howl is not coming here, okay?
Oh, I think he will.
I now know his weakness,
Mrs. Pendragon.
-Your Majesty.
- As you were.
So, then, how are you feeling?
I'm fine, thank you.
Thought I'd drop by,
rather than sit through
a dull war meeting.
- What an honor.
- Who are your guests?
This is Howl's mother, Mrs. Pendragon.
Ah.
Thanks for coming.
But I've decided not
to use magic to win this war.
We have tried using
Madame Suliman's magic
to shield our palace
from the enemy's bombs.
But the bombs fall
on civilian homes instead.
That's the problem with magic.
Right, Suliman?
You're so eloquent today, Your Majesty.
Suliman!
(GASPS)
I've got a new battle plan.
This time we're going
to beat them to a pulp.
Um... (LAUGHING)
Suliman, that's the best double
you've made of me yet.
Ha! Keep up the good work.
Your Majesty.
- Get my generals assembled.
- Sir.
So nice to see you again, Howl.
HOWL:
You're looking well, Madame Suliman.
Rather weak disguise.
Didn't I teach you better?
I'm not trying to outwit you.
I kept my oath,
I reported when summoned.
Now Mother and I will go.
I'm afraid not.
(SHRIEKING)
Whatever you do, don't look down.
It's time to show your mother
what you really are, Howl.
(WIND HOWLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(CHOIR SINGING)
Oh!
(GROANING)
Stop, Howl, it's a trap!
Hold on.
HOWL: Sophie, sit up here.
Did you have to bring
those two with you?
- Nice doggie.
- (SQUEAKS)
Hmm. I can't believe
you work for Suliman.
I guess it's too late to toss him.
HOWL: Sophie. Take the wheel.
SOPHIE: What?
- I can't fly, are you kidding?
- HOWL: They're gaining on us.
I'll distract them, then you can
fly back to my castle in the Wastes.
How? I don't know the way.
Hey, don't worry. The ring that
1 gave you will guide you back home.
All you have to do
is summon Calcifer with your heart.
Calcifer?
(HUMMING)
It's glowing.
Just keep following that light
and you should be there before dark.
I can't. Why did you make me
come here if you were coming yourself?
Knowing you'd be there
gave me the courage to show up.
That woman terrifies me,
I can't face her on my own.
You saved me, Sophie.
I was in big trouble back there.
Oh! Don't let go!
(SOPHIE SCREAMING)
- Wow. You're good.
- Are you nuts?
We've got a good lead now.
I can give you five minutes
of invisibility, so use it wisely.
- Howl!
- Good luck!
Oh!
(GROANING)
No, not now.
Oh, thank you.
That was the most fun I've had in ages.
I suppose Howl thinks he's evaded me.
Hmm. I bet his mother
can help me find him.
(GRUNTING)
Go!
ALL: Huh?
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(GASPS)
Almost there.
That's my hometown below us.
(SQUEAKS)
Don't try to be cute, dog.
I'm still not going to trust you.
(BELLS RINGING)
The castle is coming to meet us!
(CREAKING AND HISSING)
Sophie! Here!
Markl, help me!
How am I supposed to land this thing?
(CALCIFER SHRIEKING)
{SHRIEKING MUFFLED)
(PANTING)
Sophie!
- Nice doggie.
- (SQUEAKS)
SOPHIE: Markl!
I'm home.
Are you hurt?
Whoa!
- I missed you.
- I missed you, too.
Thanks for coming to meet us.
(SNORING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(MOANING)
Oh, this is bad.
You've gone too far, Howl.
(GASPS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
1 wonder if Howl's back home.
(GASPS)
Howl?
(WIND BLOWING)
(HOWL BREATHING HEAVILY)
Howl, is that you?
Are you in pain?
Tell me what's happening.
Go away.
No, I'm not going away.
I'm going to help you break
the spell that you're under.
You...You can't
even break your own spell.
-But you don't understand. I love you.
-You're too late.
Howl! No!
(SIGHS)
Calcifer, did Howl just get in?
Yeah, and he looks terrible.
You better figure out how
to break the spell on us quick.
Howl's running out of time,
1 hope you realize that.
You mean he'll become a monster.
Is that it?
1 can't tell you details of the curse, lady.
You should know that by now, come on.
Do you know
what Madame Suliman said?
She said that Howl's heart
was stolen by a demon.
Tell me now. What do you know?
I'm so sorry, but that would
be confidential information.
What if I dump a bucket
of water on you?
If you drown me, then Howl will die, too!
Hi, Turnip-head.
This isn't gonna be easy.
Okay. Ready!
- (METALLIC GRINDING NOISE)
- SOPHIE: Calcifer, open it wider.
Here we go!
(STRAINING)
(GROANING)
(METALLIC GRINDING)
1 said move!
ow!
Oh! Oh!
(SCREAMING)
If I just hang a little curtain here,
maybe Howl won't notice.
(MARKL GIGGLING)
Come on in, it's time to eat.
Here. Want some more?
CALCIFER: Don't feed her!
That's the Witch of the Waste!
Oh, she's all right.
CALCIFER: She keeps staring at me.
It's freaking me out.
What a pretty fire.
- Howl! Hello.
- Good morning, everyone.
Glad you're home.
Master Howl,
we can keep this dog, can't we?
The Witch of the Waste
and Suliman's dog at my table.
What possessed you
to let them in the house, Calcifer?
1 didn't let them in.
Sophie crash-landed her plane
into my face.
I knew she'd make a great pilot.
Looks like we have yet
another addition to the family.
Hmm, you've got quite
a nasty spell on you, too.
It seems everyone in this family's
got problems.
What a handsome man.
So, we've got a lot of work to do.
We're moving.
- Moving?
-That's good.
I'm sick of being stuck out here
in the middle of nowhere.
Madame Suliman is hot on our trail,
$0 we're gonna have to hurry.
I'm afraid your spell
is too strong for this move.
You're gonna have to stay behind.
There. All done.
- All right, Calcifer, line her up.
- (HISSING)
There. That should do it.
Sit tight for a second.
Be gentle with me, please.
On my mark.
(HOWLING)
(CREAKING)
(GASPING)
(SOPHIE GASPING)
(MARKL AND SOPHIE GASPING)
Moving's done. You can get down now.
This is great, Master Howl! It's huge!
Oh, what a pretty fire.
(DISTANT BELLS RINGING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
- But this is...
- I added on a bathroom,
since our family seems to keep growing.
Come over here, Sophie.
I added another bedroom, too.
Have a look.
(GASPS)
Oh.
Why'd you do this?
So we'd have a room that suited you.
Do you like it?
Of course.
It's perfect for a cleaning lady.
I got you some new clothes, too.
But you can open them later.
Come on, Sophie. Look at this.
- All right, a courtyard!
-That shop's ours, too.
Heen! Come on!
See that new color on the dial?
There's a new portal.
(GASPING)
It's a present for you. Come see.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Oh!
You like it? It's my secret garden.
It's incredible.
Did you use your magic to make this?
Only a little,
just to help the flowers grow.
(SIGHING)
This place is gorgeous, Howl!
It's like a dream.
HOWL: Sophie?
It all seems so familiar,
yet I know I've never been here before.
I feel so at home.
- Come with me.
- Okay.
- Look there.
- (SIGHING)
What a cute cottage.
That was my secret hideaway.
I spent a lot of time here
by myself when I was young.
You were alone?
My uncle, who was a wizard,
gave me this place as my private study.
Now you can come here
whenever you like.
What's the matter?
It's... You're scaring me.
I have this weird feeling
that you're going to leave.
Howl, tell me what's going on. Please.
I don't care if you're a monster.
I'm setting things up so that
all of you can live a comfortable life,
Sophie.
With all the flowers
you've got in this valley,
you could easily open up a flower shop.
Right? I'm sure you'd be good at it.
So, you are going away?
Please, Howl,
1 know I can be of help to you.
Even though I'm not pretty,
and all I'm good at is cleaning.
Sophie! Sophie, you're beautiful!
Well, the nice thing about being old
is you've got nothing much to lose.
Hmm?
(DISTANT METALLIC NOISE)
- What is that thing doing out here?
- A battleship?
Still looking for more cities to burn.
SOPHIE:
Is it the enemy's or one of ours?
HOWL: What difference does it make?
(APPROACHING ENGINE)
Those stupid murderers.
We can't just let them
fly off with all those bombs.
- (MEN SHOUTING)
- (ALARM SOUNDS)
What's happening? What did you do?
Just messed with it.
It won't crash, though.
SOPHIE: Oh!
Howl!
Uh-oh. Here they come.
(HISSING)
Those things are Suliman's henchmen.
Let's go.
Faster! We need to take off!
(SOPHIE GASPING)
All right, you're going in.
No! Don't let go!
(CLICKS)
Sophie, what happened?
Oh! I'm too old to be treated like this!
(KNOCKING)
- Uh, good night, Sophie.
- Good night, Markl.
Oh, don't worry
about Master Howl, Sophie.
Sometimes he likes
to go away for days on end.
Thank you.That's good to know.
- Need anything else?
- No, I'm fine.
Well. Good night, then.
You're in love.
Don't deny it.
You've been sighing all day.
(SIGHS)
Hmm. Just as I thought.
Have you ever been in love before?
Of course I have. I'm still in love.
(GASPS)
Strapping, young men
are so difficult to deal with.
But their hearts, I just adore.
You're terrible.
And they're so cute, too.
(DISTANT SIREN)
(GASPING)
What's that?
It's an air raid siren.
Air raid?
It's a long way's off.
But you better not
go outside tonight, dear.
I'm sure Suliman's henchmen
are looking everywhere for this place.
What a good fire.
He keeps this house so well hidden.
(EXPLOSIONS)
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
- Sophie, there's a strange lady in here!
- Hmm?
(GASPS)
Mother?
Sophie! (LAUGHING)
Thank goodness you're here!
I searched everywhere for you!
Oh, my, look at your face, you're so old!
Everyone's saying
it's my fault that you left!
(SOBBING) You'll forgive me,
oh, won't you? Oh, Sophie!
Mother.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I barely recognize the place.
Who is that woman?
Huh? The landlady?
Oh! I forgot to tell you!
I got married again!
He's such a nice man,
and he's filthy rich, too,
so we can all live together again!
You won't have
to work as a cleaning lady anymore.
That's all right, Mother.
1 actually like living here.
Really? (GASPS) I forgot!
I've got a car waiting. I've gotta run.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Sophie, I'm so glad I found you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SQUEAKS)
(SQUEAKING)
A peeping bug?
Can't Suliman do better than that?
Open wide, Cal.
(COUGHING)
1 hope you and your new husband
will be very happy.
-Thank you, Sophie. Bye.
- Bye, Mother.
1 did what I was told.
Now take me to my husband.
Yes, ma'am. I'm sure
Madame Suliman will be very pleased
with you.
Forgive me, Sophie.
(CHATTERING)
Wow. Look at all of them.
If they keep leaving at this rate,
the town will soon be empty.
- Do you want to leave, too, Sophie?
- What?
That lady said she wants you
to live with her now.
Yes, well, at least
she cared enough to visit.
Don't leave, Sophie.
I love you. You have to stay.
Oh, I love you, too, Markl. I'll stay.
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
Because we're a family now.
Yes, we're a family.
Thank you, Sophie.
I'll never let Suliman get ahold of Howl.
(WHEEZING)
(DISTANT ENGINES SPUTTERING)
But the newspaper says we won.
Only idiots believe
what they read in the paper.
That's so strange.
I can't get Calcifer going.
Do you have to keep smoking that?
It smells terrible.
Don't deny an old witch
her pleasures, young lady.
SOPHIE: Markl, will you
crack a window, please?
Mmm-hmm.
I wouldn't open that window,
if I were you, dear.
Calcifer's too weak right now
to protect this place.
Suliman's henchmen could get in.
(GASPS) Markl!
(SOPHIE GASPING)
Get back!
Markl, get back inside.
I'm going to check on the shop.
Mmm-hmm.
(PEOPLEYELLING)
(DOORBELL JINGLES)
(SIRENS WAILING)
There are bombs falling on us!
Why can't you put out
some fires instead?
(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
Howl! No!
Oh!
This is exciting.
(GASPING) Howl!
I'm sorry, Sophie.
1 should've gotten here sooner.
You're alive! Oh, thank goodness!
Master Howl! Sophie! You're okay!
Calcifer. You hang in there, now.
(GROANING AND COUGHING)
Tell me, was that cigar a gift
from Madame Suliman by any chance?
Howl, she fed me something gross.
I feel sick.
Why, if it isn't Howl.
I think you and I need to have
a nice, long, heart-to-heart chat.
There's nothing I'd like more than that,
but right now there's a war going on.
How unlike you, Howl,
not running away anymore.
Until later, then.
Stay here. Calcifer will protect you
from the henchmen.
I'll stand guard out front.
No, wait! Howl! Don't go out there.
It's too dangerous.
Another wave's coming.
And Calcifer's too weak
to stop the bombs.
Let's run! Don't fight them, Howl.
Sorry. I've had enough
of running away, Sophie.
And now I've got something
I want to protect. It's you.
Come back!
(GASPING)
(MOANING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(POUNDING)
(CLICKS)
(RAIN PATTERING)
There's where we are, at the shop.
Looks like Howl's in trouble.
(GROWLING)
Howl, look out!
(EXPLOSION)
What's going on? Turnip!
- Markl, I need your help.
- Huh?
Are you crazy? I can't move
the portals without Howl's help.
Try. If we don't break away,
Howl will keep protecting the hat shop.
I'd preferred him as a coward.
- Okay, we have to go now.
- Are we going for a stroll?
We can't do that.
It'll make us too vulnerable!
We already are.
If we don't move quick,
Howl doesn't have a chance.
Sophie! They're about
to bomb the hat shop!
Quick. Help her get outside, okay?
MARKL: Right.
You're coming with us. Hop on.
I can't! It's impossible!
No one but Howl
can take me out of this hearth.
There's no time to lose, Calcifer.
We have to try something.
Oh! Don't do this! No, no!
Help, help, crazy lady with a shovel!
If you take me out that door,
the castle could collapse.
Good!
-We're ready.
- Okay, step back.
Make sure I go out last, Sophie.
I don't know what'll happen,
but I'm sure it won't be good.
(WHIMPERING)
1 told you it would collapse.
(GASPS) Rain! Rain!
(ENGINES ROARING)
That ship's headed for town!
Markl, look after her, okay?
Turnip-head,
help me find a way back in.
Don't you worry, now, ma'am,
I'll take good care of you.
Markl, here's a way in!
CALCIFER:The roof's leaking.
Don't let me get wet!
Hold on for a second.
It's wet here, Sophie! Ah!
Too damp, too damp, very damp here!
Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry, please!
(MOANS)
Markl, hurry, get inside.
The castle's a wreck.
Told you we should have stayed put.
Howl and I could have handled it.
We have to tell Howl
we're not attached to the hat shop now.
Move the castle and take us to Howl.
- (SIZZLE)
- Ah! What?
I know you can do it.
I've never seen a fire with more spark.
But there's no chimney here,
and I keep getting dripped on.
And the wood's all damp.
They say that the best blaze brightest
when circumstances are at their worst.
Yeah, but no one really believes that.
Come on, let's be honest.
- Oh! What a pretty fire.
- Why don't you have a seat.
All right.
I need something of yours, Sophie.
Why's that?
I can't do it by myself.
How about your eyes?
Huh? How about this?
(GASPING)
(GASPS)
(CALCIFER MOANING)
(CALCIFER SHRIEKS)
Ah!
MARKL: Ah!
Thanks, Calcifer. You're fantastic!
Imagine what I could've done
with your eyes. Or your heart.
That's it! You've got Howl's heart!
I found it!
(SHRIEKING)
I can see Howl down there.
Looks like he's trapped!
(GASPS) Calcifer, hurry!
- No!
- Put it back!
- (CALCIFERYELLING)
- Let go!
Howl's heart, it's mine!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Put it back now!
It's hot! Ah!
- It's buming me!
- Let go!
SOPHIE: You're catching on fire!
No, it's mine. It's mine! It's mine!
(PANTING)
Ah!
Sophie!
(SCREAMING)
- Sophie!
- Sophie ruined it!
My heart's ruined!
(MOANING)
(WHEEZING)
Heen, what have I done?
I poured water on Calcifer!
(SOBBING)
What if I killed Howl, too?
(RATTLING)
It's moving. Is Howl still alive?
Can you lead me to him?
The front door.
(WIND HOWLING)
(WHEEZING)
(RATTLING)
Heen.
(RINGING)
(GROWING HISS)
That's Howl.
I know where I am.
I'm in Howl's childhood.
(HUMMING)
{HUMMING AND RINGING)
Oh!
(HEARTBEAT)
Howl! Calcifer!
It's me, Sophie!
I know how to help you now.
Find me in the future!
Sorry, Heen. I'm trying to hurry.
I just can't seem to stop crying.
(WHEEZING)
Howl.
I'm sorry. Did I come too late?
I didn't mean to make you wait this long.
I need you to take me to Calcifer
if you can.
- He's dead?
- No, Markl.
(MOANING)
Howl needs that back now.
Don't look at me. I don't have it.
1 don't know what you're talking about.
Please.
Please give it back.
You really want it that badly?
Yes.
All right, then.
-You'd better take good care of it.
- Okay.
Here, dear.
Thank you, you have a big heart.
Calcifer.
Sophie, I'm so tired.
If 1 give Howl back his heart,
what will happen to you?
I'l be okay if you do it. I think.
You dumped water on me,
and Howl and I both survived.
I better try then.
It's so warm and fluttering like a bird.
It's still just the heart of a child.
Please, help Calcifer live.
And please help Howl
take back his heart.
(RUMBLING)
(HUMMING)
(GASPING)
CALCIFER: I'm alive! I'm alive!
Look, I'm free!
Free! Free! (LAUGHING) I'm alive!
(MOANING)
He moved! See?
(ALL GRUNTING)
It can't stand without Calcifer!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Turnip!
His pole snapped!
Are you all right?
We'll get you a new pole, okay?
You saved us, Turnip.
Thank you, Sophie.
I'm the prince missing
from the neighboring kingdom.
Somehow I got that blasted spell
put on me.
I know that spell.
A kiss from your true love breaks it.
That's right. If it weren't for Sophie,
1 would have been a scarecrow
for the rest of my life.
WITCH: My, what a
strapping young man you are.
What's going on?
What am I doing here?
(GROANING]) I feel terrible,
like there's a weight on my chest.
A heart's a heavy burden.
Wow! Sophie,
your hair looks just like starlight.
It's beautiful.
You think so? So do I!
It looks like your true love
is in love with someone else.
You should go home anyway,
and tell your king to stop this dumb war.
Yes, that's exactly what I'll do.
One thing you can always count on
is that hearts change.
So as soon as this war is over,
I shall return.
I love it when you talk like that.
I'll look forward to your return, big boy.
(WHEEZING)
There you are.
You should have checked in earlier.
What on earth were you up to?
Howl found his true love.
You little traitor.
(SIGHS) The game is over.
Get me the Prime Minister
and the Minister of Defense.
It's time to put an end
- to this idiotic war.
-Yes, ma'am.
Hey, it's Calcifer!
You didn't have to come back, Calcifer.
1 kind of missed you guys.
And it looks like it's gonna rain.
I missed you, too, Calcifer.
Wow!
(SINGING IN JAPANESE)