["THE JAMES BOND THEME" PLAYS]
[GUNSHOT]
[MAN SPEAKING
IN HUNGARIAN]
...was so ably pointed out
by the secretary general
in his opening remarks.
But, and I must
emphasize this point,
no formula can, or will,
ever cover each case.
For instance--
[MAN CONTINUES
SPEAKING IN HUNGARIAN]
TRANSLATOR:
...when three
or more applicants
have been recognized,
which is in direct
contradiction--
[HIGH-PITCHED WHINING
BLARES]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[SLOW-PACED
DIXIELAND JAZZ PLAYING]
Whose, uh, funeral is it?
Yours.
[MUSIC TEMPO QUICKENS]
[CHEERING]
[TRIBAL DRUMS BEATING,
PEOPLE CHANTING]
[HISSES]
[♪♪♪]
[PAUL McCARTNEY & WINGS'
"LIVE AND LET DIE" PLAYING]
♪ When you were young ♪
♪ And your heart
Was an open book ♪
♪ You used to say
"Live and let live" ♪
♪ You know you did ♪
♪ But if this
Ever-changing world ♪
♪ In which we're livin' ♪
♪ Makes you give in
And cry ♪
♪ Say "live and let die" ♪
♪ Live and let die ♪
♪ What does it matter to ya? ♪
♪ When you got a job to do
You gotta do it well ♪
♪ You got to give
The other fella hell ♪
♪ You used to say ♪
♪ "Live and let live" ♪
♪ You know you did ♪
♪ But if this
Ever-changing world ♪
♪ In which we're livin' ♪
♪ Makes you give in
And cry ♪
♪ Say "live and let die" ♪
♪ Live and let die ♪
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
[SIGHS]
One more time again.
Ma non è
possibile, amore.
Scusami.
[DOORBELL CONTINUES BUZZING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Not married, by any chance,
are you?
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Good morning, 007.
Good--
Uh, good morning.
Insomnia, sir?
Instructions.
You haven't much time.
I'll explain as you pack.
Uh...
Pack, sir?
Three of our agents
have been killed
during the last
24 hours:
Dawes in New York,
Hamilton in New Orleans
and Baines
in the Caribbean.
Oh, Baines.
I rather liked Baines.
We shared
the same bootmaker.
Uh, coffee...
sir?
[CLEARS THROAT]
I take it these killings
are connected.
That's precisely what
you're going to find out.
[GRINDER WHIRRING]
Baines was working
on a small island
in the Caribbean
called San Monique.
Dawes was in New York
keeping an eye on its
prime minister, one Dr. Kananga.
Hamilton was on loan
to the Americans in New Orleans.
Is that all it does?
By the way, congratulations
seem to be in order.
The Italians
were most impressed
by the way you handled
the Rome affair.
Thank you, sir.
Sugar?
Oh, thanks.
BOND:
Well, the authorities
were more than helpful.
M:
There's one
small complaint.
They seem to be missing
one of their agents,
a Miss, uh...Caruso.
BOND:
Oh?
Uh, you wouldn't happen
to know where she is?
Ah, Miss Moneypenny.
Good morning,
Moneypenny.
Good morning, sir.
Certainly the hour
that's indecent.
Really? I've got your ticket
to New York,
Q has repaired
your wristwatch,
and some background material
on San Monique.
Thank you, Moneypenny.
I'm sure the overburdened
British taxpayer
would be fascinated
to know
how the Special Ordnance Section
disburses its funds.
In future, commander,
allow me to suggest
a perfectly adequate
watchmaker
just down the street.
Good God!
You see, by pulling out
this button, sir,
it turns the watch
into a hyperintensified
magnetic field
powerful enough to even deflect
the path of a bullet
at long-range,
or so Q claims.
I feel very tempted to test
that theory right now.
If you don't mind,
commander, my spoon.
Oh, sorry, sir.
Thank you.
Dr. Kananga is, at present,
in New York.
The CIA have been informed,
and they're helping out
with the surveillance.
Your flight arrives
at 11:30 a.m.
Now, where
did I leave my coat?
Oh, allow me.
Thank you.
Come along, Miss Moneypenny.
Good morning, Bond.
Sir.
Miss Moneypenny...
thank you.
Goodbye, James.
Or should I say,
ciao, bello?
[♪♪♪]
Siamo soli.
Finalmente.
Mmm...
Such a delicate touch.
Sheer magnetism, darling.
[♪♪♪]
WOMAN:
A man comes.
He travels quickly.
He has purpose.
He comes over water.
He travels with others.
He will oppose.
He brings violence
and destruction.
[SCREECHING]
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
[PHONE BUZZING]
Hello?
Mr. Leiter for you, sir.
Thank you.
Hello, Felix.
How are you?
BOND:
Traffic permitting,
I should be with you
in about half an hour.
Then you can buy me
the best lunch in New York.
Fine, James.
Your friend Kananga's
just left the U.N.
He's probably headed
back to his embassy.
No, no, don't worry.
I've got the place eyeballed,
wired for sound, the works.
Right. I'll see you
in about a half hour.
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINE REVS]
[HORNS HONKING]
Hey, easy, Charlie.
Let's get there in one piece.
Charlie?
[♪♪♪]
[FENDER CLANGS]
[HORN HONKING]
Right. Stand by.
Here comes
Kananga's limousine.
Out he gets...
with the usual goon squad
and the girl.
Time, 11:46.
What is that?
Hello, Felix. You know
how I hate to trouble you,
but I've, uh, run into
a little bother.
Your driver is dead,
and I've crashed your car.
You what?!
[BOND SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Get me a make
on a white pimpmobile.
347 Nelson-David-George.
MAN:
It would seem, Dr. Kananga,
that the conference
has not lived up
to your prior
expectations.
Well, we can only hope
that this
is a temporary setback.
However, I do have
some observations to make.
Take a letter, please.
To secretary general,
Pan-Island Unity Conference.
Sir...
I wish to point out...
"that...
KANANGA [ON TAPE]:
...too many
of our island neighbors
have once again
let themselves be bullied
by United States industry.
The story is an old one,
the record a clear one.
Since my historic
statement of principles
was delivered and acted upon
some six months ago,
our economic outlook
has improved dramatically.
By exercising our policy
of friendship to all
with favoritism
towards none,
new respect for the entire area
has been engendered,
and even though
some of my most trusted...
James, that car
is registered to a shop
at 33 East 65th Street,
that's only a block
away from here.
Right.
Take your time, buddy.
Kananga's knitting
a flag in there.
...it might
be the easiest thing to do.
[♪♪♪]
[BELL DINGS]
Something in heads?
Just browsing,
thank you.
[BELL DINGS]
Five dollars.
Do you think you could
gift-wrap it for me, please?
Lengthwise,
if you don't mind.
Thank you.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[♪♪♪]
...remains my first concern.
Thus, San Monique's
future obligations
vis-à-vis her island neighbors
would seem clear.
Those who fawn and crawl
in the face of intimidation
must, perforce,
look up to those who stand
proudly wrapped in
a justifiable self-confidence.
The time has come,
painful as it may be,
to gaze out among
our sister nations in the area
and see if any stands tall--
[ELEVATOR HUMMING]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
He's tailing.
I got him
in my sights.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, you know
where you goin', man?
Uptown, I believe.
Uptown?
You headed into Harlem, man.
Well, you just keep on
the tail of that jukebox
and there's an extra 20
in it for you.
Hey, man, for 20 bucks,
I'll take you
to a Ku Klux Klan cookout.
125th. You got a honky
on your tail.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
He's heading east.
Can't miss him.
It's like following a cue ball.
BOND:
That's the car.
They must have gone inside.
Pull up where you can.
Sure hope you
make friends easy.
Right on, brother.
He's headin' on in.
[POOL BALLS CLICKING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[CHATTERING STOPS]
Good afternoon.
Bourbon and water,
please.
First booth'll do.
Tell him neat,
would you?
Huh?
No ice.
That's extra, man.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
I'd like something
on the side as well.
Information.
Three men and a girl
came in--
MAN:
Relax, baby.
Mr. Big's gonna
take care of you in a minute.
[♪♪♪]
BOND:
Black queen on the red king,
Miss...?
Solitaire.
My name's Bond.
James Bond.
I know who you are,
what you are
and why you've come.
You have made a mistake.
You will not succeed.
Rather a sweeping
statement,
considering
we've never met.
The cards
have followed you for me.
MAN:
You get ripped off
in Detroit, baby,
you yell out to me.
You hear?
Is he armed?
Well, you can't be
too careful
in New York City these--
These days.
[♪♪♪]
[CHUCKLES]
Funny how the least
little thing amuses him.
BOND:
Oh, fascinating.
Well, that's you,
quite obviously.
An amazing resemblance.
Tell me,
am I in there as well?
Pick a card.
Turn it over.
You have
found yourself.
MAN:
I'm telling ya.
You're all gonna go to L.A.
and clean it up,
or I'm comin' out there
and clean you up.
And I mean that.
Is this the stupid mother
that tailed you uptown?
There seems to be some mistake.
My name is--
Names is for tombstones, baby.
Y'all take this honky out
and waste him. Now.
[♪♪♪]
"Waste him"?
Is that a good thing?
The reading is over.
Nothing about my future?
Us?
Now, promise
you'll stay right there.
I shan't be long.
Thank you.
[DISTANT SIRENS WAILING]
Keep your hands up,
honky.
What does he think this is?
I'll blow his
frigging head off, man.
Drop it!
[♪♪♪]
Now.
"Harold Strutter, CIA."
Where were you
when I didn't need you?
Got obvious you weren't
coming out front,
not even with that
clever disguise you're wearing.
Hm?
Whiteface in Harlem.
Good thinking, Bond.
Let's get outta here.
I'm surprised that
they didn't spot you too.
There's a most remarkable
girl back there
with a deck of cards.
I saw those cards
on the way up.
Spades, James,
every one.
You were nailed the minute
you left 74.
There's only supposed to be
one man who can pull together
that much black muscle
in this town.
Calls himself Mr. Big.
You name the business,
they say he has
a black concession.
What would a foreign
prime minister like Kananga
want with
an American gangster?
The question is,
what would Mr. Big want
with a two-bit
island diplomat?
FELIX [OVER RADIO]:
Mr. Big?
Where the hell
does he fit into this mess?
A genuine Felix lighter.
Illuminating.
[CHUCKLES]
Now listen, James.
We just found out that Kananga's
got a private plane
and he's leaving for San Monique
within the hour.
Well, then get me
on the next available flight.
I already did.
I just knew you wouldn't
pass up a chance
to get away from where
the real action is.
[♪♪♪]
[CACKLING]
The legendary
Baron Samedi, folks.
That's "Saturday" for those
of you who speak French.
Voodoo God of Cemeteries
and Chief
of the Legion of the Dead.
The Man Who Cannot Die.
But for our purposes,
just a performer
in a little
musical extravaganza
we've cooked up
for you wonderful people.
[TRIBAL JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
Good evening.
The name is Bond.
You have
a reservation for me.
Ah, yes, Mr. Bond,
of course.
Mrs. Bond's
been expecting you.
Mrs. Bond?
She arrived
earlier this afternoon, sir.
Said she preferred something
a little more private.
Bungalow 12.
An incurable romantic,
Mrs. Bond.
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN DIALECT]
[MUSIC ENDS, AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
[WATER RUNNING]
[FESTIVAL MUSIC
RESUMES PLAYING OUTSIDE]
Room service, please.
Oh, room service?
This is Mr. Bond,
bungalow 12.
I'd like a bottle
of Bollinger, please.
Slightly chilled.
Two glasses.
Thank you.
[CLICKING]
[BATHTUB WATER RUNNING LOUDER]
[WATER SPLASHING]
[♪♪♪]
[LOW VOICE]
Anybody home?
Your champagne, sir.
BOND:
What was that?
Your champagne.
Put it on the table, thanks.
Shall I
open it?
What?
Shall I open it?
Oh, no, no, I can manage.
Thank you.
There you are.
[WATER DRAINING]
[♪♪♪]
Mrs. Bond, I presume?
I'm Rosie Carver.
I guess I have a little
explaining to do.
Yes, either you or...
dear Uncle Felix.
Custom .38 Smith & Wesson.
Corrugated three-inch stock.
No serial number,
standard CIA issue.
Question is,
why point it at me?
The man who delivered
your champagne
is not a hotel waiter.
I was just trying
to be careful.
As for Felix Leiter,
you're right.
I've worked for CIA down here
for some time now
and he cabled me
you were coming
and asked if I wouldn't
help out if I could.
Well, perhaps
you'd better start
by getting
your head together.
Mm?
[LAUGHS]
There's a mirror
in the bathroom.
Yes.
Yes, you're only
my second mission, you know.
My first was Baines,
the agent who was killed.
It's a relief to know
I'm next in line
for the same kind of aid.
[ROSIE SCREAMS]
There's a--
Oh, a snake.
I forgot.
I should have
told you.
You should never go in there
without a mongoose.
Oh, I should have never
gotten into any of this.
I'm going to be completely
useless to you.
Oh, I'm sure we'll be able
to lick you into shape.
Well, it's, uh...
getting late, Mrs. Bond.
Tomorrow is going
to be a very busy day for us.
You see, Kananga is protecting
something down here,
something which, uh,
Baines obviously discovered.
You're going
to show me the spot
where Baines'
body was found.
That, I'm afraid,
only leaves us tonight
to, uh, well...
catch up on old times.
Felix told me there'd
be moments like this.
What did good old
Felix suggest?
If all else failed,
cyanide pills.
I settled
for two bedrooms.
Good night, Mr. Bond.
Mrs. Bond.
[ROSIE SCREAMS]
[♪♪♪]
[WHIMPERING]
Why, it's just a hat,
darling,
belonging to a small-headed man
of limited means
who lost a fight
with a chicken.
It's a warning.
Get it outta here!
Oh, please.
Please don't leave me
alone tonight.
James,
please promise me.
All right, darling.
If you insist,
I promise.
I thank you.
Rosie?
Breakfast's up.
Rosie.
BOND:
Are you ready yet?
What?
I have to see about
organizing a car.
I'll see you
in the lobby.
[DOOR CHIMES RING]
MAN:
Over here, sir.
Over here.
Guaranteed big fish.
Catch big fish, sir.
MAN 2:
Hey, baby. Over here.
Bring your man here.
$20, half a day.
You got warm lady, we got
cold beer over here, man.
MAN 3:
You wanna catch
a big fish, sir?
It's only £2
over here.
Good morning.
Come on, Rosie.
This one seems eager enough.
ROSIE:
Excuse me.
Where can I change?
Uh, me.
Clothes off. Where?
[BUZZING]
ROSIE:
Stop right there.
Turn around slowly.
Keep your hands up.
As I was saying, Quarrel,
a lousy agent,
but the compensations
speak for themselves.
Rosie Carver, meet the man
who shares my hairbrush,
Quarrel Junior.
I'm really sorry.
I could have shot you.
You might have even
killed me
if you'd taken off
the safety catch.
Never mind, darling.
You just let us know
when we get to the spot
where Baines was killed.
It's up in the hills
just after we clear
the next cove.
Hey, Quarrel!
Who the hell
lives up there?
QUARREL:
That's the house
of the Kananga woman.
She's supposed to have
the power of the obeah.
No one on the island dare
go up there except him.
[♪♪♪]
He comes again.
[OVER RADIO]
There will be violence.
He approaches even now.
By land or water?
Water.
He has arrived.
Good.
Rosie's been more efficient
than I anticipated.
I know a place where
we could rustle up a car.
Ah, beautiful, brave,
and now resourceful.
Rosie, you seem to be staging
a remarkable comeback.
Tell me about the future.
Is it death?
I said, is it death?
It is death.
They're coming.
Rosie knows what to do.
Now, I want no bodies this time.
No trace.
ROSIE:
It's down there.
But, uh, I thought you said
Baines was killed
up in the hills,
darling.
Up in the hills,
down there.
Why don't we have a bite
of lunch and discuss it, hm?
There's an excellent
paté in the hamper.
I'm in no hurry.
Are you?
No.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, James.
Ooh, you don't know
what finding you
has meant to me.
Oh, I can imagine.
And you've no idea
what finding this
has meant to me.
You do know
what the Queen of Cups means
in an upside-down position.
A deceitful, perverse woman.
A liar, a cheat,
and I'd like
some answers now.
Please, uh...
You don't understand, sir.
They'll kill me if I do.
And I'll kill you
if you don't.
But you couldn't.
You wouldn't.
Not after what
we've just done.
I certainly wouldn't
have killed you before.
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
[WHIMPERING]
It used to be
a convincing act, Rosie.
It's wearing
a little thin now.
It's not an act.
It's--
Make your choice.
Rosie!
You will explain
what went wrong.
I see the intervention
of a woman.
The girl was about
to confess.
We had to kill her.
The trap was set.
Tee Hee was waiting.
And you saw death.
It must have been
the girl's death.
If you do not ask
specific questions,
I cannot be responsible
for your misinterpretation
of the answers.
These growing signs
of impertinence
begin to disturb me,
Solitaire,
even as they did
with your mother before you.
She had the power
and lost it.
Became useless to me.
You will not
make the same mistake.
Solitaire.
Where is Bond now?
[BOAT ENGINE HUMMING]
I cannot see when you
are this way with me.
Things become unclear.
Let us hope these
momentary lapses
do not become
a habit.
Your power exists
to serve me
and it is mine
to control.
If and when
the time comes
I decide you are
to lose it,
I myself
will take it away.
Solitaire, go to sleep.
You have made me
angry with you,
and I have
no wish to be.
Tee Hee.
[BEEPING]
[♪♪♪]
SOLITAIRE:
Put down those cards!
It is a blasphemy.
They tell nothing
to those who cannot see.
Oh, but they do.
That's, uh,
a bit of luck.
Good luck
for both of us.
The cards
say we will be lovers.
You're mistaken.
It's impossible,
forbidden for me--
Now you must go.
But you do believe.
I mean, really believe
in the cards?
Well, they have
never lied to me.
Then they won't now.
Pick one.
[♪♪♪]
You knew the answer
before it was given.
Strangely enough,
somehow,
so did I.
So it's finally happened.
Just as it did
to my mother
and her mother
before her.
Well, of course
it did.
Well, you're--? You're visual
proof of that, aren't you?
Come on,
cheer up, darling.
Has to be a first time
for everyone.
Now, tell me,
where's Kananga?
I cannot see.
Oh, yes, the cards.
I'll get them.
No.
There's no need
to be frightened.
You'll soon be rid of him,
I promise.
I just need a...
little bit
of information, that's all.
The power...
I've lost it.
The high priestess
is wife to the prince
no longer of this world.
The spiritual bridge
to the secret church.
It's my fate.
By compelling me
to earthly love,
the cards themselves
have taken away my powers.
Darling, I have a...
small confession
to make.
Now, try not
to be too upset.
The deck was slightly
stacked in my favor.
It makes no difference.
The physical violation
cannot be undone.
When he finds out
I've lost my power...
he'll kill me.
Oh, now, come on,
he'll have to find you first.
Lovers' lesson number one:
We have no secrets.
For example,
I have a boat waiting.
You can be on it.
All I have to know
before we leave is...
what goes on
back there in Voodooland.
Darling,
three men and a girl
have been killed
in the last four days,
not counting the times
they've tried to stop me
from discovering whatever
Kananga's protecting.
Now, do you want to be
on that boat or not?
I simply read
the cards for him.
I've never been there,
and he's never taken me there.
I've never
dared to go,
but I've looked
in the cards.
I've seen great riches there.
They'll kill you.
Us, darling.
They will kill us.
Lovers' lesson number two:
Togetherness till death
do us part, or thereabouts.
Is there time before we leave
for lesson number three?
[♪♪♪]
Absolutely.
There's no sense
in going off half-cocked.
[BIRDS SINGING]
This way.
How can you be
so sure?
These scarecrows
are to scare people.
You're
not scared, are you?
Lesson number four:
Follow the scarecrows.
[FLUTE PLAYING MYSTERIOUS THEME]
Good morning, boss.
Good morning.
It's sure gonna be
a beautiful day.
[LAUGHS]
Yes, sir, a beautiful day.
They're heading
for the hill.
They're here.
If he finds it,
kill him.
[MACHINE GUN FIRING]
Quick!
We've lost him.
He has the girl.
They're somewhere
under the nets.
At any cost, any...
Bond must die.
[DOG BARKING]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING, SHOUTING]
[SPEAKS
INDISTINCTLY]
Unit two-five,
we have picked them up.
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]:
Base to 25. Arrest Bond.
But, I repeat,
the girl is not to be touched.
Message received and understood.
Over and out.
Base to all units.
I repeat,
the girl is not to be touched.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Go get some more water.
Get out of the way!
[♪♪♪]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING, SHOUTING]
Sweet mother of pearl.
[MEN SHOUTING]
All change.
End of the line.
Get down below quickly.
Here. I'll do that.
You get us started.
[ENGINE STARTS]
MAN [ON PHONE]:
It appears a bus--
James.
He'll be looking for me now.
I know he'll never stop.
Come on,
darling.
It's all over.
Voodooland was
just poppy fields,
a simple matter
of heroin smuggling.
I'll have a word
with a man named Felix
and turn
the case over to him.
And you and I will be off.
By the way,
where would you like to go?
Anywhere where we can
find one of these.
How quickly can we
make it to New Orleans?
Santa Mina,
four hours away.
You can catch a flight
and be there in the morning.
Then get in touch
with Felix on the scrambler.
Tell him to meet me
there tomorrow.
The Royal Orleans Hotel.
Tampa is closer.
Hamilton was killed
in New Orleans,
so there has to be
a connection.
And this is a valuable piece
of merchandise we're carrying...
which, with any luck,
they'll want back.
[♪♪♪]
Royal Orleans Hotel,
please.
Are you sure
this is the way to New Orleans?
I don't know,
but it sure beats
the hell out of Harlem,
don't it?
[CHUCKLES]
Well, hello, Jim.
What's happenin', baby?
[CHUCKLES]
Just ease back now,
Jim. Relax.
Mr. Big wants
to see you.
You made a mistake
back on that island, Bond.
You took something
that didn't belong to you,
and you took it from
a friend of Mr. Big's.
That type of mistake
is tough to bounce back from.
But I've only just arrived.
Today
is your lucky day, Jim.
You goin' skydivin'.
There's a hell of a view
of the lake from 10,000 feet.
My only regret
is I won't be there
to see it.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, that's him.
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Good morning.
You're...?
Mrs. Bell.
You're not my instructor.
Where's Mr. Bleeker?
Indisposed.
I'll be giving the lesson.
Come on, come on.
What's on for today?
Oh, let's just wing it,
shall we, Mrs. Bell?
You're over-revving.
MAN 1:
Leroy, slow down!
For Pete's sake, slow down!
MAN 2:
Do what the man say.
LEROY:
I can't--
I can't find the brake.
MAN 3:
Close those doors!
Holy shit.
[FIRES]
MEN: Look out!
Look out!
Okay, Don. Don't worry.
I'll take care of it.
Right. Talk to you later.
I gotta go and give a lesson.
Same time tomorrow,
Mrs. Bell?
FELIX:
Yes, Mr. Bleeker.
Yes, sir.
Well, I-I-I know you just can't
glue the wings back on.
BLEEKER: ...son of a bitch...
Now, Mr. Bleeker,
I'm sure there's no reason
for name-calling.
You can fit the rest
this afternoon.
Right, sir.
Don't forget the double vents.
I appreciate she may be
one of your best pupils, yes.
That'll do nicely.
That's a little frantic.
I'll keep the other three.
Any suggestion
of that kind
should be forwarded
in writing to Washington.
How is Mrs. Bell?
Intensive care,
but she'll pull through.
Yes, sir. Oh, no, sir, no one's
questioning your patriotism.
I'm sure
you're a veteran, sir.
Felix,
you might find out
if there's a Fillet of Soul
restaurant in town.
We're way ahead of you.
It's down on Docker Street.
Strutter's watching it now.
[BAND PLAYING SLOW-PACED
DIXIELAND JAZZ MUSIC]
[MARCHERS CHEERING]
[JAZZ BECOMES FAST-PACED,
UPBEAT]
Hell of a sendoff.
This way.
[BAND PLAYING ROCK MUSIC]
Where's Strutter?
He's gotta be
inside somewhere.
Two, gentlemen?
I got a nice booth over here
just against the wall.
Could you
find something
a little closer
to the stage?
What's wrong
with a booth?
I once had a nasty turn
in a booth.
Bourbon.
No ice, please.
Two Sazeracs.
Where's your sense
of adventure, James?
This is New Orleans.
Relax.
♪ When you were young ♪
♪ And your heart
Was an open book ♪
♪ Oh, you used to say
"Live and let live" ♪
One of you guys
called Felix Leiter?
Yeah, right here.
Telephone call for you.
Guy called Strutter.
Thanks.
For a minute there,
I thought Harry
was laying down on the job.
♪ Say
"Live and let die" ♪
♪ Oh, say
"Live and let di-i-ie" ♪
♪ Ooh, say
♪ What does it matter to ya? ♪
♪ When you got a job to do
You got to do it well ♪
♪ You gotta give
The other fella hell-ll ♪
What happened to my--?
Shh.
What happened to my friend?
What happened to your friend?
MAN:
Thanks for droppin' in, baby.
Mm-hm.
Yeah, you one tough pig
to nail down.
You've been pickin' at me
like some kind of maggot.
First you go up to Harlem
and kill one of the brothers.
Now,
that disturbed me.
But then you go and steal
this valuable young lady
from my good friend,
Dr. Kananga.
Now,
old Kananga,
he believes
in all that card crap.
I mean,
he's mad.
Well, possession being,
nine points of the law,
I would say Kananga
is your problem now. Thank you.
In fact, if I were you, I'd, uh,
watch my step from now on.
Yeah, well,
you just let me handle
our business with the man.
I've got my own plans
for you, baby.
But first...
there's one little question
that he wants answers for.
In that case, you'd better
ship me back to the island,
and let him ask in person.
I'm not in the habit
of giving answers to lackeys.
You damn lucky you got a ear
left to hear the question with,
which is...
did you mess with that?
That's between Solitaire
and myself...and Kananga.
I'll tell him
when I see him.
You ain't gonna see the sunlight
unless you answer me!
I had no idea you were
so frightened of him.
Did you touch her?!
When I see Kananga.
Right.
Quite revealing.
Kananga, poppy grower
in thousands of acres
of well-camouflaged fields
protected by the voodoo
threat of Baron Samedi.
And as Mr. Big,
distributor and wholesaler
through a chain
of Fillet of Soul restaurants.
Wholesale?
[CHUCKLES]
Sell heroin for money?
My apologies. I'm sure
you simply give it away.
Excellent,
Mr. Bond.
That's precisely
what I intend to do.
Two tons of it, to be exact.
When entering into
a fiercely competitive field,
one finds it advisable
to give away free samples.
Man or woman, black or white.
I don't discriminate.
Two tons of heroin
with a street value
well over a billion dollars,
nationally distributed free?
Now, that should make
a certain group of families
rather angry,
wouldn't
you say?
Angry?
Why, my dear
Mr. Bond...
it'll positively
drive them out of their minds...
and, subsequently,
out of the business.
[CHUCKLING]
Quite ingenious.
A sort of junkie's
welfare system.
Well, merely until the number
of addicts in the country
has doubled,
shall we say?
Then I will begin
to market that acreage
that you blundered into
the other day.
That heroin
will be very expensive indeed,
leaving myself
and the phone company
the only two going
monopolies in this nation
for years to come.
And here I thought
it was Solitaire
did the fortunetelling.
Let's hope for both
of your sakes she still can.
The question
still stands, Mr. Bond,
asked by
the gentleman concerned...
Did you touch her?
BOND:
Why, it's not
the sort of question
a gentleman answers.
Well, having set
the example,
I don't expect Miss Solitaire
to be any less the lady.
By the way...
That's a particularly handsome
watch you're wearing, Mr. Bond.
May I see it,
please?
You'll forgive me
if I don't get up.
Butter hook.
Tee Hee.
On the first wrong answer
from Miss Solitaire,
you will snip the little finger
of Mr. Bond's right hand.
Starting
with the second wrong answer,
you will proceed
to the more vital areas.
Solitaire,
my dear,
I want you to listen
to me very carefully.
On the back
of Mr. Bond's watch,
the registration
number 3-2-6-6.
Do I speak the truth?
You speak
the truth.
Well...
If nothing else, at least
I have laid your fears to rest.
My compliments
on a splendid operation.
There is one thing,
however, the--
[CLICKS]
KANANGA:
Whisper,
take him
to the farm.
When do we start back?
Soon,
Solitaire.
Soon.
Solitaire,
why?
I treated you well.
You lacked for nothing.
I don't understand
what you--
Mr. Bond's watch,
my dear.
I gave you
every break possible.
You had
a fifty-fifty chance.
You weren't
even close.
I had no choice.
Please believe me.
The cards.
[GRUNTS]
When the time came, I myself
would have given you love.
You knew that.
You knew that!
There's only one proper way
to deal with this.
[♪♪♪]
And one proper time.
[SAMEDI CACKLING]
[HORN HONKS]
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
[BIRD SQUAWKS]
[MACHINES HUMMING]
[LAUGHS]
The tonnage order
is nearly complete.
TEE HEE:
We move it out tonight.
And I mean tonight.
Mr. Bond.
How much do you know
about crocodiles, Bond?
Oh, I've,
uh, always tried
to keep them
at arm's length, myself.
[CHUCKLES]
Cute little nippers,
ain't they?
I don't suppose
those potential
overnight bags are orphans?
Oh, no, we have some
moms and dads as well.
In fact,
uh...
Quite a few thousand.
This is the part
I like best:
Feeding time.
I suspect
the highlight of the tour.
[CHUCKLES]
Ah, some of these babies
live to be 200 years old.
Look over there.
That's an alligator.
You can always tell
by its round nose.
Aha,
there's old Albert.
Now, he's a croc.
Got overcareless
with him
sometime back,
and he took my whole arm off.
Well done,
Albert.
Oh-ho-ho,
they'll eat anything...
even each other.
Then again, sometime they can go
a whole year without eating.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, I was
rather counting on that.
There are two ways to disable
a crocodile, you know.
[CHUCKLES]
I, uh-- I don't
suppose you'd care
to share
that information with me?
Well, one way
is to take a pencil
and jam it in the depression
hole behind his eyes.
And the other?
Oh, the other
is twice as simple.
You just put your hand
in his mouth,
and pull
his teeth out.
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMS]
[MEN SHOUTING]
It's on fire.
[COUGHS]
Adam,
get him.
Adam, get the car.
Cut him off.
Hector,
move, damn it.
Bond ripped off
one of our boats.
He's headed
for the Irish Bayou.
HECTOR [ON RADIO]:
The man that gets him
stays alive.
Now, move,
you mother--!
[ENGINE STARTS]
MAN:
Toby?
Toby, I got me a regular
Ben Hur down here...
doing 95
minimum.
TOBY:
Need any help, J.W.?
Hell, no.
[SIREN WAILING]
You got a set of wheels
that just won't quit, boy.
If they's yours,
that is.
Uh-uh.
You spin
around, boy.
Ten fingers
on the fender.
Legs apart.
I'm sure this ain't
exactly your debut
with this sort of thing.
You picked the wrong parish
to haul ass through, boy.
Nobody cuts and runs
on Sheriff J.W. Pepper.
And it's him speaking,
uh, by the bye.
What the fu--?
[FIRES]
[GLASS BREAKING]
[ENGINE ROARING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
TOBY:
J.W...
Soon as you nail
that offending vehicle,
Miss Pearson
just called.
Seems her dog's
foaming all at the mouth.
She's got him
locked up in the shed,
wondering if you'd like
to come over
and shoot it for her.
[CAR APPROACHING]
You tell Miss Pearson
to take a flyin'--
[CAR HONKS]
Dog.
That look like a boat
stuck in the sheriff's car
there, Eddie?
Boy, where you been
all your life?
That there's
one of them new car-boats.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
By the powers
invested in me
by this parish,
I hereby do commandeer
this vehicle
and all those persons
within.
And that means you,
smart-ass.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[BIRDS SINGING]
[SIREN WAILING]
MAN 1 [ON RADIO]:
Unit 23 in position.
MAN 2:
Ten-four, 23. Come in, 28.
MAN 3:
Hey, J.W.,
seems like Deke Rogers
done got his boat stole
off the river,
but picked up a new one
in his swimming pool.
MAN 2:
Sheriff, you want to get
your boys off our frequency?
Give me that.
Now you
listen to me, trooper boy!
We got a swamp
full of black Russians
driving boats
to beat the band down here!
MAN 2:
Relax, sheriff,
we've got a roadblock
waiting for them
at Miller's Bridge.
Unit 26 at Miller's Bridge.
We're just about all set here.
Make that secure there,
you hear?
Okay, fellas,
here they come.
[MEN SHOUTING,
SIRENS WAILING]
All right, out of my way.
I'm in charge here.
You two boys,
come on.
MAN 2 [ON RADIO]:
I don't want excuses, I want
those men and their boats
apprehended immediately,
did you hear?
Yes, sir, captain.
I understand.
But I don't know
right off
where we're going
to find
a boat fast enough
to catch 'em.
I got it. You call
my brother-in-law, Billy Bob.
He got the fastest boat
on the whole damn river.
Billy Bob will sure enough
fix their ass, huh?
Yeah,
call Billy Bob.
J.W.:
Now, there's two boats,
Billy Bob,
and they're movin' like
buttered pigs.
Now, I promised these boys
here you would get 'em.
Don't let me down,
hear?
Cool down, J.W.,
I'm on my way.
You want somethin',
boy?
Yes, I'd like to borrow
this boat, if I may.
Everybody on the river
would like to borrow this boat.
J.W.:
Billy Bob, we got 'em spotted.
They're headed
for Haley's Landing.
That's my brother-in-law.
That's Billy Bob.
He'll get 'em.
Billy Bob will get 'em.
Hot damn!
If one side of the Pepper family
don't get 'em,
the other side will.
Let's go.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
If any man can show
just cause
why they may not
lawfully be joined together,
let him now speak,
or else
hereafter and forever--
[SOBS]
[SIRENS WAILING]
DISPATCHER [ON RADIO]:
Headquarters to all units,
suspects seen
proceeding down via Liberty
towards Highway 11.
Proceed with caution.
Would you get that
chicken coop off the road!
Did you ever think of gettin'
a driver's license, boy?
[♪♪♪]
Are you sure that was
your brother-in-law, sheriff?
[TRUCK HORN HONKING]
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMS]
Hello, Felix.
What are you doing here?
We'll get to that later.
Kananga's in town.
He's got your girl with him.
They just took off.
There's
the son of a bitch!
I got him.
What are you?
Some kind
of doomsday machine, boy?
Well, we got a cage
strong enough
to hold an animal
like you here.
Captain, would you enlighten
the sheriff, please?
Yes, sir.
J.W., let me have
a word with you.
J.W., now, this fella's
from London, England.
He's a Englishman working
in cooperation with our boys,
a sort
of secret agent.
Secret agent?!
On whose side?
We busted the Fillet of Soul
an hour ago.
We came up with nothing
but these.
FELIX:
Kananga's clear.
You should have seen
the size of the guy
who got on the boat
with him.
Nine feet tall,
I swear.
Big top hat,
a cockamamie
flute in one hand
and Solitaire in the other.
[BAND PLAYING TRIBAL MUSIC]
The incendiary bombs
are set for midnight.
Now, that gives you
exactly...30 minutes.
Watch out for sharks
on the way back.
I'll see you
for breakfast, Felix.
Good hunting.
You're going
to need these
and the shark gun
on the way back.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING, DRUMS BEATING]
Seems like
the party's started.
My regards
to Baron Samedi, man,
right between the eyes.
[PEOPLE SHOUT]
[DRUMBEAT CONTINUES]
[RINGING]
[♪♪♪]
[CROWD YELLING]
[SCREAMING]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[CROWD SCREAMS]
[WHIMPERS]
[DRUMMING STOPS, CROWD QUIETS]
[CHANTS IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[CROWD REPEATS CHANT]
[CROWD CHANTING
IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[RINGING]
[♪♪♪]
[DRUMMING RESUMES]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
CROWD:
Ooh.
[SPEAKING
IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[MAN SHOUTS
[GRUNTS]
[WOMAN SCREAMS,
MEN SPEAKING IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[EXPLOSION]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[CROWD SHOUTING
IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[LAUGHS]
[SINGING IN NATIVE DIALECT]
[HISSES]
[YELLS]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[CLINKING]
[GRUNTS]
Trouble!
[ALARM RINGING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[WATER SPLASHING]
Ah, Mr. Bond,
there you are!
And Miss Solitaire
as well.
Hardly unexpected,
but most welcome.
Whisper!
Two more glasses
for our guests!
Uh, what shall we
drink to, Mr. Bond?
Well, how about
an earthquake?
[CHUCKLING]
Welcome home!
Where's our boy?
He'll be along
anytime now.
I checked behind a rock,
and his wet suit is gone.
Keep the change.
It's unfortunate that
your wet suit was discovered
only minutes before
the field was destroyed.
Now, don't tell me
you're not insured.
Oh, no. The poppy's
a very sturdy flower.
You have been a relatively
minor nuisance, in fact.
But this gun--
I-- I find it particularly
fascinating. Wha--? What is it?
A shark gun, naturally,
with compressed gas pellets.
[WHISPER CHUCKLING]
[KANANGA LAUGHING]
Ingenious!
BOND:
Uh, don't...
pull the pin out.
The air in here
is foul enough already.
Aw! Somehow I never thought
of you as a poor loser.
I was hoping you would join me
to a drink to the future.
Oh, Miss Solitaire used
to know all about the future.
She was especially good
at predicting death.
BOND:
Hah. An underground monorail.
Connected to the last refuge
of a scoundrel, no doubt.
The heroin leaves here,
I take it,
carried somewhere
by that winch.
Correct again, Mr. Bond.
What a quick study you are.
Let me show you
exactly how it works.
Where in hell
can the man be?
Relax. He must have got
tied up somewhere.
These cans hold
25 pounds each.
There are 20 cans to a shipment,
packed in watertight...
metal containers.
It's your show, Kananga,
but I'm sure there must be
a simpler way of drowning
someone.
Drown, Mr. Bond?
I doubt you'll get
the chance to drown.
[♪♪♪]
Perhaps we could try something
in an even simpler vein.
On the contrary,
Mr. Bond.
I think you'll find
those wounds quite fatal.
[LAUGHING]
Whisper.
The gate.
Oh, slowly, Whisper!
Slowly,
slowly.
Let our diners assemble.
[LOW VOICE]
Look out.
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
Where's Kananga?
Well,
he always did have
an inflated opinion
of himself.
Oh, James.
How do we get out
of here?
BOND:
We take the train,
of course.
Well, thanks
for everything, Felix.
I'll see you tomorrow night at
the 21 Club, and don't be late.
I still don't see why you
want to travel this way.
I mean, what the hell
can the two of you do
on the train
for 16 hours?
Say goodbye
to Felix, darling.
[TRAIN HORN BLOWS]
Now, the first thing to learn
in playing gin rummy
is to never take a card
from the exposed pile
unless
you really need it.
Gin.
James,
what are
you doing?
Just testing
an old adage.
Unlucky at cards...
Do hurry up,
James.
Won't be a moment,
darling.
[SIGHS]
Lock the door as well on
your way up, would you, James?
After all,
we wouldn't want anyone
to just walk in on us,
would we?
The first time in my life,
I feel like a complete woman.
The slightest touch
of your hand...
I was always
so afraid that a part of me
would stay
with the past,
but now I know there's
no chance of that any longer.
[CLATTER]
Just to be able
to reach out and touch you.
Mr. Bond, it's good
to see you again.
[YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
[YELLING]
[LAUGHING]
[YELLS]
SOLITAIRE [MUFFLED]:
James!
[BANGING]
What's going on?
Let me out of here!
[SCREAMING]
James, let me go!
Well, that
wasn't very funny.
[CLATTER]
Now what are you doing?
Just being disarming,
darling.
[PAUL McCARTNEY & WINGS'
"LIVE AND LET DIE" PLAYING]
[LAUGHING]
♪ When you were young ♪
♪ And your heart
Was an open book ♪
♪ You used to say
"Live and let live" ♪
♪ You know you did
You know you did ♪
♪ You know you did ♪
♪ But if this
Ever-changing world ♪
♪ In which we're livin' ♪
♪ Makes you give in and cry ♪
♪ Say
"Live and let die" ♪
♪ Live and let die ♪