また村が一つ死んだ
行こう
ここも時期腐海に沈む
オームの道
まだ新しい
オームの抜け殻！
すごい
完全な抜け殻なんて初めて
いい音
セラミック刀が欠けちゃった
谷の人が喜ぶわ
道具作りの材料にずっと
困らなくて済むもの
すごい目
これ一つなら
持って飛べるかな
あぁ　取れた！
わぁ　なんて軽いんだろ
ムシゴ椰子が午後の胞子を飛ばしている
綺麗
マスクをしなければ
五分で肺が腐ってしまう死の森なのに
誰
何かしら
胸がドキドキする
虫封じの銃が！
誰かが虫に襲われてる！
あっ　ごめん！
あそこだ
すごい胞子の煙
オーム！
きっとあの抜け殻の主だわ
あっちに逃げては駄目だ
気がついて
答えた！こっちへ来る
あの人は
なんて立派なオーム
- ？？？
- すまん！
オーム　森へお帰り
この先はお前の世界じゃないのよ
ね、いい子だから
怒りに我忘れてる
鎮めなきゃ
閃光でオームが目を回した
虫笛
オーム　目を醒まして
森へ帰ろう
気がついたわ
オームが森へ帰ってゆく
光玉と虫笛だけでオームを
鎮めてしまうとは
ユパ様！
ナウシカ　見間違えたぞ
一年半振りですもの！
父が喜びます
礼を言わねばならん
良い風使いになったな
いいえ　父がまだまだだって
うん、そうそう。こいつの事
すっかり忘れておった
ま！狐栗鼠！
私初めて
こいつが羽虫に攫われたのを
人の子と間違えてな
つい銃を使ってしまったのだ
それであんなにオームが怒ったのね
気絶しておったので
毒を吸わなかった様だ
いや、手は出さん方がいい。
ちびでも凶暴だ
おいで
さ
おっ　おい
ほら　怖くない
怖くない
ほらね　怖くない
ね？
怯えていただけなんだよね
ユパ様
この子私に下さいな
おお　構わんが
わぁ　ありがとう！
パイにクイ　私覚えてる？
不思議な力だ
疲れたでしょう、いっぱい走って
皆に変わりはないかな
どうした
父が
父はもう飛べません
ジルが？
森の毒がもうそんなに
はい
腐海の・に生きる者の定めとか
もっと早くに訪れるべきであった
いいえ　本当によく来て下さいました
先生　後で是非見て頂きたい物があるんです
私の秘密の部屋
- ほ
- みんなには内緒！
怖がるといけないから
私先に知らせに行きます
先生も急いで！
ユパ様？
これ運んで下さる？
気流が乱れてうまく飛べないの
それにしてもよく風を読む
さっ　もう少しだ
- おぉユパ様！
- ようこそ！
ほぉ　皆も息災か
水も風も滞りなく穏やかです
ユパ様！
あぁ　みんな元気だね
姫様　お着きになりましたぞ
もうちょっと
ユパ様！
ミトオジ、性が出るな
今宵はまた異国の話を聞かして下さい！
いいわ　回して
いい様ですな
うん
おぉ　本当に良い品じゃ
さすが明日にでも人手を繰り出して
取りに行かねばな
- さ、トヨト
- ええ
ユパ様　今年生まれたトヨトの子です
おぉ　どれどれ
ほほ　良い子だ
幼い頃のナウシカを思い出す
どうかこの子の名付け親に
なって下さいませ
いつもいい風がその子に
吹きます様に
引き受けよう
良い名を贈らせてもらうよ
ありがとう
どうか姫様の様に
丈夫に育ちます様に
うん　丈夫というなら
姫様は折り紙付きじゃ
だが腐海遊びまで似ると困るぞ
でもおかげでオームの殻を見つけたのよ
しかしだ　城オジの儂の身になってみろ
心配で・しておれんわい
オームの殻となりゃ
姫様の腐海遊びも無駄とは言えんのぉ
そうとも　儂もそれで助けられたのだからな
会うた子に助けられたか
この谷がいい
いつ来ても心が和む
今度の旅はどうじゃった
ん　酷いものだ
南でまた二つの国が
腐海に飲まれてしまった
腐海が着実に広がっている
なのにどこへ行っても
戦に植え
不吉な陰ばかりだ
なぜの谷の様に暮らせぬのか
ここは海から吹く風様に
守られておるからの
腐海の毒も谷へは届かぬ
どうだユパ
そろそろこの谷に腰を据えぬか
儂はこの様だ
皆も喜ぶが
んん
無駄じゃよ
ユパは探し続けるよう定められた男じゃ
定めか
大婆様　探すって何？
おや　ナウシカは知らなかったのかい
ほれ　あの壁の端にあるじゃろ
儂にはもう見えぬが
左の隅にいるお方じゃよ
その者、青き衣を纏いて
金色の野に降り立つべし
失われし大地との絆を結び
遂に人々を青き清浄な地に導かん
ユパ様　私古い言い伝えだと
ばかり思ってました
婆様　からかわれては困る
同じ事じゃろうが
私はただ
腐海の謎を解きたいと
願っているだけだよ
我々人間はこのまま腐海に飲まれて
滅びるよう定められた種族なのか
それを見極めたいのだ
私にユパ様のお手伝いが
できればいいのに
姫様　姫様
何　ミト
ゴルが風が臭うと言うとります
もうすぐ夜明けね
すぐ行くわ
ご苦労さん
いい嵐なんじゃが
どうもおかしい
あそこ！
ほら　また
船だわ
なぜこの様な辺境に船が…
何事かね
ユパ様　船です
- 船？
- 来るわ！
大きい！
トルメキアの大型船だ
飛び方がおかしい
不時着しようとしている
- ゴル、上げて
- え？
姫様　無茶じゃ！
海岸に誘導する
回ってきたぞ
えぃ　行きますぞ！
テト
なんて事
腐海に降りて虫を殺したんだわ
舵を引けぇ！ぶつかるぞぉ！
舵を引けぇ
舵を！
- 落ちた
- 姫様
右側の崖だ
行こう！
あの子だわ　生きてる
ここは…
風の谷よ　喋っては駄目
私は
ペジテのラステル
積荷を　積荷を燃やして
積荷？
お願い　燃やして
積荷ね　わかった
大丈夫　みんな燃えたわ
よかった
姫様！
この方はペジテ市の王族の姫君ですな
虫だ！ウシヤブが生きてるぞ！
まずい　仲間を呼んでる
傷付いて飛べないんだ
- 銃を持って来い！
- 駄目だ！打てば・中間を呼ぶぞ！
即死させる
ウシヤブは銃で死ぬもんか！
じゃあどうするんだ
待って
- ミト　メーベを持ってきて
- はい
姫様！
森へお帰り
大丈夫　飛べるわ
そう　いい子ね
- 姫様
- ありがとう
よかったぁ
たった一匹殺しただけでも
何が起こるかわかりませんからな
オーム
あった！来て！
こっち
やっぱりあの船に胞子が
くっ付いてたんだね
まだ毒は出してないな
もう一踏ん張りだ
うん　一つでも残すと
大変だからね
何だろうこの塊は
あの炎でも燃えないとはなぁ
ああみんな
こいつの詮索は後回しだ
胞子を焼く手伝いに行ってくれ
念入りに頼むぞ！
全く厄介な物を持ち込みおって
ミト　ここを見ろ
ああ？
動いとる
まるで生きとる様だ
ユパ様　これは…
旅の途中で不吉な噂を聞いた
ペジタ市の地下に眠っていた
旧世界の怪物が
掘り出されたと言うのだ
旧世界の怪物？
巨神兵だ
巨神兵
あの「火の七日間」で
世界を焼き尽くしたという…
こいつが
巨神兵は全て化石となったはずだった
だが地下で千年も
眠り続けていたやつがいたのだ
そういえば　こいつが人の形にも見えます
トルメキアは遥か西方の
凶暴な軍事国家
死んだペジテの虜囚といい、気になる
後お願い
何かしら
トルメキアの船だ！
みんなは城へ！
みんな　城へぇ！
みんな　城へ集まれぇ！
城へ！
父上！
婆様は隠れておれ！
私はここに居るよ
姫様！？
おのれ！
ナウシカ
双方動くな
動けばオームの皮より削り出した
この剣がセラミック装甲も貫くぞ
あの男　ユパです
トルメキア兵に訊く
この民の者は
昨夜そなた達の船を救わんと
必死に働いた
今もまた死者を丁重に葬ったばかりだ
小なりとはいえ
その国に対するこれが
トルメキアの礼儀か
戦を仕掛けるならば
それなりの理由があるはず
まず使者を立て
口上を述べるべきであろう
ナウシカ
落ち着けナウシカ
今戦えば谷の者が皆殺しになろう
生き延びて機会を待つのだ
くそぉ
この娘が！
止めろクロトワ
しかし…
なんてやつだよ
みんな殺しちまいやがった
諫言耳が痛い
辺境一の剣士
ユパ・ビラルダとはそなたの事か
我らが目的が殺戮ではない
話がしたい
剣を収められよ
姫様だ
聞け！
トルメキア帝国辺境派遣の司令官
クシャナ殿下のお言葉だ
我らは
辺境の国々を統合し
この地に王道楽土を建設するために来た
そなた達は腐海のために滅びに貧している
我らに従い
我が事業に参加せよ
腐海を焼き払い
再びこの大地を蘇らすのだ！
腐海を焼き払うだと？
そんな事できるのか
かつて人間をして
この大地の主となした
奇跡の技と力を我らは復活させた
私に従う者には
もはや森の毒や虫どもに
怯えぬ暮らしを約束しよう
待ちなされ！
腐海に手を出してはならぬ
なんだ　この婆
おい　連れて行け
言わせてやれ
腐海が生まれてより千年
幾度も人は腐海を焼こうと試みてきた
が　その度にオームの群れが怒りに狂い
地を埋め尽くす大波となって
押し寄せてきた
国を滅ぼし
町を飲み込み
自らの命が餓鬼で果てるまで
オームは走り続けた
軈てオームの骸を苗床にして
胞子が大地に根を張り
広大な土地が腐海に没したのじゃ
腐海に手を出してはならん
黙れ！その様な世迷い言許さんぞ
おや　どうするんじゃ？
儂も殺すのか
貴様！
殺すがいい！
盲の年寄りさ
簡単なものだよ！
ジルを殺した様にね
ジル様？
黙らせろ！
逆らうやつは容赦するな
みんな待って！
私の話を聞いて
これ以上犠牲を出したくないの
お願い
姫様
大婆様もわかって
この人達に従いましょう
なかなか良い谷ではないか
私は反対です
本国では一刻も早く
巨神兵を運べと命令しています
命令は実行不能だ
大型船すらあいつの重さに
耐えきれず
墜落してしまった
しかし　まさか本心でこの地に
国家を建設するなどと
だとしたらどうなのだ
お前はあの化物を
本国の馬鹿共の玩具にしろというのか
Ah, yes, I do see your point.
But I am just a soldier of Tolmekia.
lam not in a position
to make that decision.
Hmm. Weasel.
I'm reporting back to Pejite.
While I'm gone,
begin to awaken the warrior.
Right.
KUSHANA:They have a gunship?
KUROTOWA:Yes, an unexpected find
for such a quaint valley.
KUSHANA: Those are my orders.
I'll leave for Pejite
first thing in the morning.
But, Kushana, why must
the Princess go with you?
Aren't five hostages,
food and the gunship enough?
Select your five hostages
and load up the cargo barge
before tomorrow's departure.
MAN: Take it all.
(MEN GRUNTING)
We leave nothing here.
Mito, thank you
for accompanying the Princess.
No, I'm glad to go.
But look at those greedy Tolmekians.
They're stripping us of everything.
Don't worry about that.
Our only concern is that
the warrior stay dormant.
I'm going to leave the valley, then I'll
slip back and wait for my chance.
Good luck.
LORDYUPA: Nausicaa?
(SCRATCHING)
Teto, where has Nausicaa gone?
(CHITTERING)
(GASPS)
Nausicai, what are you doing here?
This chamber is filled with toxic plants.
I collected the spores
and grew them down here myself.
Don't worry.
The plants aren't poisonous.
They're not poisonous?
(SNIFFS) It's true.
The air is pure in here.
But I know these plants from the jungle.
These are some of the most lethal.
l irrigated this chamber using water
drawn from deep underground
by the castle windmill.
I used soil drawn from there as well.
I found that, with clean water and soil,
the plants from the toxic jungle
aren't poisonous.
All the poison is in the soil.
Even the topsoil in our valley
is polluted.
But I don't understand
who could've polluted the entire Earth.
You discovered this all on your own?
Yes. I was hoping to find
a cure for Father's illness.
But... (SOBS)
It's too late now. I'm shutting down.
I've already cut off the water.
Soon, these plants will wither and die.
(SOBBING)
Nausicaa.
I'm afraid of myself, Lord Yupa.
I had no idea that my rage
could drive me to kill.
(SOBBING) No more killing.
It has to stop.
(MURMURING)
CHILDREN: Princess Nausicaa!
We gathered these for you.
- Chiko nuts.
-You can take them on your trip.
Oh, my.
There are so many.
You must have worked very hard.
(CHILDREN SOBBING)
Thank you.
I'll think of you when I eat them.
CHILD: We don't want you to go.
Hurry up! Get in the ship.
(SOBBING)
All right, I must go now.
There's no need to cry.
I'll be back very soon, okay?
You mean it?
Of course!
Have I ever broken a promise to you?
No.
See?
Mmm-hmm.
You'll come back, huh?
Now, be good while I'm gone.
-We will.
- Okay.
Bye!
ALL: Bye, Princess!
- Good luck!
-Take care of the Princess!
Protect her!
Hey, Niga, aren't we in Pejite yet?
Yeah, hurry it up. My back is killing me.
Good Lord, no wonder
they sent you two off to be hostages.
- All you do is complain.
- (LAUGHING)
Hey, doesn't this
formation seem strange?
Why are we flying so close together?
MAN: Yeah.
It's as if they fear an attack.
The air beneath the clouds must be
charged with poisonous gas. (GASPS)
(GASPS)
-What?
- MAN: Hey, sit down.
It's a gunship!
MAN: Enemy ship! We're under fire!
Your Highness, they're attacking us!
- (NAUSICAA GASPS)
- (ALL SHOUTING)
- (ALARM BLARING)
- MAN: Our number two ship is down!
MAN 1: What did I tell you?
MAN 2: This is terrible!
(ALL SCREAM)
MAN 1: Look out!
He's coming in from below!
- MAN 2: That's a Pejite gunship!
- Pejite?
MAN 1: Number Three's been hit!
MAN 2: Signal from Number Three!
MAN 1:They can't steer!
They can't steer!
-Where's our fighter plane?
-These are some flimsy ships.
He's hit the rear guard!
(GASPS)
The barge detached.
Teto, come on.
We're going down.
We got to get out of here.
Princess!
Stop it! All this killing must stop!
You must stop!
(GASPS)
Princess!
(YELLS)
-This way, Mito.
- (MITO GROANING)
Princess, where are you going?
- Let's try the gunship.
-What?
Mito, hurry up!
Uh, right.
Start the engine.
Then we'll shoot the door open.
Got it!
(GASPS)
Come on!
Hurry!
Here, get in!
- Can we launch?
-1 hope so.
Open the throttle to full,
then fire the guns.
MITO: Roger.
NAUSICAA: Ready? Now!
Put on your masks.
I'm going below the clouds
to rescue the cargo barge.
Hold on, Teto. Don't die.
MITO: Look at this. I've never seen
the poison this dense before.
Mito, watch the starboard
side of the ship.
We should come across
the barge any minute.
Roger.
NAUSICAA: It should be gliding.
MITO: There it is!
Down to the right.
ALL: Princess Nausicaa!
Hold on. I'll throw you a tow rope.
The towing hook broke.
We can't be towed.
I don't want to land in the jungle.
The insects will eat us alive!
We'd rather jump to our deaths.
Calm down. Just dump the cargo,
and we'll help you land.
MEN: Goodbye.
MAN: Nice knowing you!
MITO: Listen to me.
Just dump the cargo.
Mito, cut the rear engine.
-What?
- Just do as I say. Hurry!
All right.
(ALL GASP)
Princess, what are you doing?
MAN 1: Put on your mask!
MAN 2: You'll die!
MAN 1: Put it back onl!
Listen, please. Dump your cargo
and glide down with us.
You'll be just fine.
MAN 1: We'll do whatever you say!
Just put your mask on!
Do it now, please!
Look at her smiling.
She actually thinks
we're going to be okay.
- Hurry! Ditch the cargo!
- Hurry!
Start the engine.
We'll look for a place to land.
Ah, l inhaled some of that poison.
MAN 1: Hurry it up!
MAN 2: This is so wasteful!
MAN 1: Don't think about it. Just hurry.
MAN 1: What do we do?
MAN 2: Princess!
- Is everyone okay?
-ALL:Yeah.
- KUSHANA: Don't move.
-You.
Thank you for rescuing me, Nausicaa.
Princess, you brought her
with you on purpose?
You're too naive.
You shouldn't think we're best friends
now, just because you saved me.
Listen, you don't understand the jungle.
This is no place for guns.
If you fire that here,
the insects will descend upon us
in seconds.
They're already enraged
from all your ships
crashing into their jungle.
- Look at them swarming.
- (INSECTS BUZZING)
The giant dragonflies
are the sentries of the jungle.
Soon, they'll summon hordes
of insects to this site.
We must get out of here now.
Bring me your extra rope. Quickly.
- (MEN AGREEING)
- Mito, repair their towing hook.
MITO: Right.
Oh.
Don't move.
I'm the one who gives the orders.
What are you so afraid of?
You act like a scared little fox-squirrel.
What did you call me?
Don't be afraid. There's nothing to fear.
1 just want you to go back
to your own country.
How dare you talk to me that way?
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTING)
They're here.
(GASPS)
Stay calm.
Whatever you do, don't startle them.
We're in the middle of an Ohm nest!
(WHIMPERING)
We're surrounded!
They're examining us.
Ohm, please forgive us
for disturbing your nest.
We're very sorry.
We are not your enemies.
We mean you no harm.
(WHIMPERING)
- Princess?
- (GASPS)
(CHILD SINGING)
(SINGING FADES)
(GASPS) The pilot from Pejite.
He's still alive? Ohm, wait!
What's going on?
-Their eyes are red with rage!
- (ALLYELL)
Princess, what in the world
do you think you're doing?
Take off as soon as the waters are calm,
and wait for me above the cloud line.
Mito, if I'm not back in one hour,
return to the valley.
Are you crazy?
MITO: Princess, no!
MAN: The Princess is gone.
MITO: Why don't I take that for you?
All right, let's do as the Princess said.
She better be okay.
(SQUEALING)
Whoa!
I'm trapped.
(GUN CLICKS)
It's jammed.
Ah!
(SCREAMING)
No... Ah!
-Who are you?
-You've done far too much killing.
My insect charm and flash grenade
won't do any good now.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
Quicksand.
Nol
Oh! (PANTING)
(BUZZING)
MAN: It's already been two hours.
MITO: More insects keep coming
by the minute.
MAN: Princess, where are you?
Princess!
MAN: (ECHOING) Nausicaa.
Nausicaa.
- (CHILD SINGING)
- Come here.
Come here, child.
YOUNG NAUSICAA: Father!
Mother's here, too?
Wait. Don't go this way.
Stay away! Ah!
Get back! There's nothing here!
Stay away from me! Please go.
(CRACKLING)
Get back inside.
She's got a baby Ohm.
The insects have bewitched her.
Hand it over, child.
YOUNG NAUSICAA: No.
It hasn't done anything wrong.
MAN: Insects and humans
cannot live in the same world.
You know that.
(YOUNG NAUSICAA SHRIEKS)
You knew that.
Don't kill it! Please, don't kill it!
Please. (SOBBING)
(CHILD SINGING RETURNS)
- (SQUEAKS)
- (SINGING STOPS)
Teto.
What a strange place.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PANTING) Hey!
I found your glider.
How are you feeling?
Where are we?
I should introduce myself first.
I'm Ashel from the land of Pejite.
I'd like to thank you for saving me.
I'm Nausicaa.
I'm from the Valley of the Wind.
What is this place?
(LAUGHING)
You're not going to believe this.
We're actually beneath the toxic jungle.
- Beneath the jungle?
-Yeah.
See that?
We fell through that hole up there.
Along with a bunch of sand.
(GASPS) How can we be breathing
without our masks?
1 don't know.
Somehow the air down here is clean.
I couldn't believe it, either.
I never dreamed
the toxic jungle could be like this.
What's wrong?
Nausicaa, don't wander off too far.
NAUSICAA: What a magnificent tree.
(WATER TRICKLING)
It's dead,
but water's still flowing through it.
This is like the sand
from the bottom of our well.
It looks like these trees
must die and fossilize,
and then crumble into sand.
Nausicaa?
Are you crying?
Mmm. It's okay, though.
I'm just happy.
I can't believe she's dead.
Lastelle was my twin sister.
1 wish I could have been there for her.
I'm sorry. I was too late to save her.
No.
I apologize.
You took care of my sister
while she was dying,
and I just shot down your ship.
It's okay.
So, the giant warrior's
in the Valley of the Wind now.
(CRUNCHING)
(GROANS)
Ugh, these nuts taste awful.
What are they?
They're called Chiko nuts.
They're supposed to be good for you.
(MOUTH FULL) Why is it everything
that's good for you tastes so bad?
(LAUGHING)
What's the origin of the jungle?
You sure spend a lot of time
thinking about strange things.
The trees of the toxic jungle
must have evolved
to purify the Earth of all the pollution
that we humans have made.
The trees absorb the pollution
so it becomes inert.
Then they die and petrify
and then crumble into purified sand.
That's how these underground
caverns must've been formed.
And the insects,
they evolved to guard this place.
If that's true, then mankind
is destined to go extinct.
It'll take centuries
for these trees to cleanse the Earth.
We can't survive with insects that long.
Somehow, we are going to
have to find a way
to stop this toxic jungle from spreading.
You Pejites sound
just like the Tolmekians.
What? We are nothing like those
bloodthirsty Tolmekians.
We'd never use the warrior
as a weapon.
Let's get some sleep, Asbel.
We'll need our strength
to make it to Pejite tomorrow.
(PULSING)
MAN: All is well, sir.
KUROTOWA: Fine, fine.
- Everything going smoothly?
-Yes, sir.
The warrior's torso is almost developed.
I swear, the more I gaze at you,
the more attractive you get.
You're awakening
long-forgotten ambitions,
even in a lazy old soldier like me.
Oh, is that a smile?
Perhaps you should remain buried
deep beneath the Earth after all.
- Sir!
- Mmm.
Her Highness's fleet was attacked
by a survivor from Pejite.
All but one of her ships were destroyed.
KUROTOWA: What happened
to Her Highness?
According to our reports,
her ship exploded in midair.
MAN: How shall we proceed, sir?
Do the villagers know
that their princess's ship went down?
- No, sir.
- Good. Keep it that way.
Continue working
as if nothing has changed.
ALL: Yes, sir.
So, is this lowly soldier
finally on the path to fame and fortune,
or on the path to destruction?
LordYupa,
Mito and the others are back.
They're all waiting for you
at the Acid Lake.
Down there.
MITO: We shouldn't have returned
without the Princess.
LORDYUPA: No, I'm glad
that all of you are safe.
You're letting me go?
LORDYUPA:Yes, granted that you
drown the giant warrior in the Acid Lake
and then return to your kingdom.
You have very few soldiers
left in the valley.
We could easily defeat your forces now,
but I see no point in further killing.
The warrior can't be
drowned or destroyed,
and until it walks on its own,
it can't be moved.
Don't you understand? It's too late.
There's no turning back now.
I was ordered to attack Pejite
because we feared
another kingdom would
get a hold of the warrior's power.
Once its existence is known,
all the remaining kingdoms
will send their armies here to claim it.
You really only have
one choice, Lord Yupa.
Revive the giant warrior.
Use it to repel the invading kingdoms
and learn to live with the monster.
Look.
(GASPING)
Hmm.
An insect did that?
That's right, and whatever
lucky man becomes my husband
will see worse than that.
The insects must be stopped.
You must revive the warrior and use it
to destroy them and their jungle.
Steal it from us
as we stole it from Pejite.
That's what I'd do if I were you.
No, we will keep the warrior dormant
as it was meant to be.
(GASPING) Lord Yupa!
- Emergency!
-You gotta give us the password.
-I'mina humy!
-Wind?
-Valley!
- Okay.
- Some of the spores survived!
-What? In the valley?
They're spreading poison everywhere.
The whole valley's in a panic.
(PANICKED MURMURING)
WOMAN: It's poison! See them?
(CLAMORING)
MAN 1: Please, don't be foolish!
MAN 2: We need to do something.
- MAN 3: Hurry!
- MAN 1: Before it's too late!
If we don't do something fast,
the whole valley will be destroyed.
Hurry, the spores are spreading fast.
If we give them tools to burn the spores,
they could use them against us instead.
We have no choice.
Hand over everything but their guns.
Yes, sir.
- Sir, the ship is ready.
-Try not to fail this time.
Assemble all the Tolmekian soldiers
left in Pejite
- and bring them to the valley.
-Yes, sir.
What a mess.
This is starting to look bad already.
(ALL SHOUTING) Come on! Hurry!
Let's go! Let's go!
Good luck finding the Princess.
Take care of the valley, and don't do
anything rash while we're gone.
ALL: Yes, sir.
Come on. Let's get back to the valley.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
Check it!
MAN: Oh, no!
We're too late.
The spores have infested
the entire tree.
This one's infected, too!
-WOMAN: This way!
- Get out of the way!
MAN: Hey, what do you think
you're doing?
(GRUNTING)
Oh, no. It's everywhere.
MAN: Obaba.
OBABA: This forest is doomed.
We must burn it down.
If we hesitate, the toxic jungle
will engulf the entire valley.
Isn't there some other way?
This forest has protected the valley
from the jungle's poisons for 300 years.
If only the Tolmekians had never come.
It looks like
things are getting out of control.
We better get back there fast.
ASBEL: You think so?
Everything looks the same to me.
NAUSICAA: The insects
have left the jungle.
What's going on?
My heart's pounding like crazy.
ASBEL: Hey, we're almost there!
Pejite's just over that mountain.
Something strange is going on.
What's that haze over there?
Asbel, put your mask on!
ASBEL: The insects. They're all dead.
-We've got to get to Pejite.
- Be careful.
The Tolmekian army
could still be there.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
NAUSICAA: A dead Ohm.
ASBEL: And the capital's
been destroyed.
Pejite is finished.
It was far too much to pay, even if it
did get the Tolmekians out of our city.
"Too much to pay"?
Asbel, what are you talking about?
An airship.
ASBEL: It's one of ours!
They're landing. Let's go.
MAN: Asbel, you're still alive.
What have you done to our city?
It's completely destroyed!
Don't worry. We can rebuild it.
And if the jungle starts to spread here,
we'll burn it off.
With what? The giant warrior isn't here.
We know. It's in the Valley of the Wind.
How do you know that?
(CHUCKLES) We've already
made plans to get it back.
Our plan is being executed
as we speak.
All Tolmekians in the valley
will be dead...
ASBEL:What?
What are you planning to do
to my valley?
Asbel, who is this?
She's the princess
of the Valley of the Wind,
and she saved my life.
- (MEN GASP)
-The Valley of the Wind?
Tell me! What is gonna happen?
Asbel, you know what the plan is.
You have to tell me.
We're going to bait insects
into the valley.
(GASPS)
So you lured the insects
here into Pejite?
(SOBBING)
What a monstrous thing to do.
We have to get the giant warrior
out of the hands of the Tolmekians,
no matter what it takes.
We're doing this for the good
of the planet. You've got to understand.
The good of the planet?
You're killing my people!
Don't do this, I beg you!
Please, please, stop this now!
It's too late.
Once the insects start stampeding,
they can't be stopped.
The Tolmekians nearly
killed off all our people.
They must be stopped.
We have no other choice.
- Stop her!
- MAN 1: Stop her!
MAN 2: Grab her!
Let me go!
Ah! Let me go!
Things may seem
bad to you now, Princess,
but once we have the warrior, we'll burn
the jungle, and take back the Earth.
You savages!
You're just as bad as the Tolmekians!
You're wrong. The Tolmekians
want to take over the world.
Listen, every one of us
relies on water from the wells,
because mankind has polluted
all the lakes and rivers.
But do you know why
the well water is pure?
The trees of the wasteland purify it.
And you plan to burn the trees down?
You must not burn down
the toxic jungle!
You should have left the giant warrior
beneath the Earth!
So what should we do?
Surrender and become
the slaves of the Tolmekians?
Don't you understand?
Asbel, tell them how the jungle evolved,
and how the insects are guarding it
so we won't pollute the world again.
Asbel, please?
- (GRUNTS) What are you doing?
- Stay right there.
Let go of the Princess, now!
Calm down, Ashel.
ASBEL: Let her go!
I mean it!
Nausicai, go back
and warn your people.
- (ASBEL GRUNTS)
- (NAUSICAA GASPS)
Asbel! Let me go!
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
What a bunch of fools.
I can't wait to beat the tar
out of those Tolmekians.
I thought we said
we wouldn't do anything rash.
Don't panic.
Just rescue the soldiers with the tanks.
-Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
Sir, the villagers just killed
our last soldier on the field.
- Are they heading for the castle?
- Not yet.
But more of them keep gathering.
All this over a little forest.
They're as annoying as the Pejites.
If they just calmed down...
Look out!
Huh?
(SCREAMING)
They hijacked our tank.
- Get this thing moving!
- I'm going. Don't rush me.
- MAN: Fire!
- Here they come!
Forward!
Come on, come on. Let's go.
Maybe it's this one.
Hey, it's doing something.
Niga, where are you going?
(ALL GASPING, SHOUTING)
What do you think you're doing?
- Go forward!
- I know. I know.
MAN 1:The tank!
MAN 2: Let's stop it!
MAN 3: Stop them!
They're getting away!
Send out all the tanks! (GASPS)
MAN 1: Your Highness.
MAN 2: Attention!
She's alive.
That dream didn't last long.
Your Highness!
We'll hold off the troops.
You round up the villagers
and seek shelter by the Acid Lake.
- Right. Let's go!
- Come on!
We just have to lie low until
the Princess returns in the gunship.
MAN 1: Don't slow down!
MAN 2:You can make it!
Keep moving!
Don't just stand there. Give me a hand.
But I have a bad back.
NIGA: Oh, get us out of here!
The tanks are coming!
You're turning in circles.
MAN: I know, I know.
NIGA: Go forward!
(SCREAMING)
MAN: We're hit!
- (ALARM BLARING)
- (GRUNTING)
What do you got, soldier?
It's a ship from Pejite.
I caught a glimpse
just beyond the clouds.
Good work.
MAN: Careful. She's a wild one.
Quicldy now.
Nausicaa, we're going
to get you out of here
$0 you can
warn the people of the valley.
There may still be enough time
if you take your glider.
It's ready and waiting for you.
Asbel told me everything
that has happened.
I'm going to be
taking your place, Princess.
- Put this on.
- But who are you?
I'm Asbel and Lastelle's mother.
(GASPS)
You're their mother.
(SIGHS) Please, forgive us.
What our people did
was horribly wrong.
Hurry.
NAUSICAA: What will happen to her?
WOMAN: Don't worry. She'll be fine.
WOMAN 1: There she is.
WOMAN 2: Yes, the Princess.
Please be careful.
And forgive us
for the way you've been treated.
- ASBEL: Nausicaa, this way.
- Here.
- Hurry.
-WOMAN 1: Be careful.
WOMAN 2: Good luck.
Thank you, everyone.
WOMAN 3: Take care.
I'm sory it took me so long.
Can you launch from here?
I'll try.
The Tolmekians!
Get us out of here! Head for the clouds!
MAN: Cease fire!
They'll never survive.
It's a pilot's worst nightmare
in those clouds.
MAN: This is suicide! I can't steer!
(ALL SCREAMING)
The storm is tearing the ship apart!
It's no use!
Our only hope is to
get out of these clouds and fight back!
- Oh!
-They expected this.
Look. What are they doing?
Oh, no. They're trying to pin us against
the clouds so they can board our ship.
(GRUNTING)
Open it up!
They're coming in.
You got to get out of here now!
I can't just leave you like this.
Or your mother, or the girl
who took my place in the cell.
You need all the help you can get!
You have to save the people
of the valley. Please.
Go, or my people
will never forgive themselves.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (BOTH GASP)
MAN: Go, go, go!
Take the ship.
I want every Pejite dead. Now.
- (GROWLS)
- (GASPS)
Go, Nausicai, go!
Asbell
There's the Princess!
Mito!
(SHRIEKS)
Ha-hal
NAUSICAA: Mito, Lord Yupa,
the valley's in danger.
- MITO: Princess!
- Hurry! Hurry! Please!
I'll send out the docking hook now.
LordYupa, pull the red lever
on your right.
Why is this taking so long?
Knock it down.
- (PANICKED MURMURS)
- (BABY CRYING)
This door's gonna bust
any second now.
Fine. Let them break it down.
We must fight them
with honor and with dignity.
What's behind us?
A bird?
Look! A gunship
from the Valley of the Wind!
What?
- (GROANS)
- (ALL GRUNT)
Get him!
(GRUNTS)
(MEN SCREAM)
It's Lord Yupa.
Kill him, and you'll be famous.
I suggest you surrender.
There's no ship coming to rescue you.
This guy's tough.
This is way too fast!
The engine's gonna burn out!
I don't care, as long as it holds out
until we get to the valley.
Increase speed!
Please, dear God,
please hear this prayer.
You must protect
the people of the valley.
- (COUGHING)
- (WHISPERING)
MAN 1: I don't like this waiting.
MAN 2: Check your weapons.
Well, this is dull.
Are they ever going to budge?
-They're waiting for their princess.
-The princess?
They expect her to come back here
and rescue them with their gunship.
That gunship could be
areal pain in the neck.
Should we start a fight now
and avoid the mess?
Do you know anything
about that old ship they're hiding in?
KUROTOWA: I've heard it was built
before the Seven Days of Fire.
I don't know if it's true,
but it's supposed to have traveled
everywhere, even to the stars.
They say guns can't
penetrate its armor,
but I bet if you hit it just right...
No, we're going to wait for the Princess.
What?
I want to see if she can make it back
alive from the middle of the jungle.
If she's not dead, I'd like a chance
to get to know her.
So, men, have you
made up your minds yet?
If you advise the villagers
to surrender, I'll let you go.
Or would you rather end up like Pejite?
It's strange that you're a princess, too.
You're not anything at all
like our princess.
Ah, take a look at my hands.
I have the same illness as King Jihl.
Six months from now,
my hands will be as hard as rocks.
But our princess told me that she truly
loves these beat-up old hands of mine.
When she looks at these hands,
she knows these
are the hands of a hard worker.
How can you be so foolish?
The jungle is killing you,
yet you want to live in harmony with it?
You plan to burn down the jungle,
but we've learned to use fire
only in small amounts.
That's right.
Too much fire gives birth to nothing.
Fire can reduce a forest
to ashes in a day,
while it takes the water and the wind
100 years to grow one anew.
We prefer the ways
of the water and the wind.
The Princess will be devastated
when she sees that our forest is gone.
Sir. Do we have any orders yet, sir?
- Just shut up.
-Yes, sir.
Something must have happened,
because she's starting to look
kind of cute to me.
Kurotowa, prepare the troops to attack.
What? We're not going to wait?
We'll begin the attack in one hour,
so get the troops fed and ready to go.
Ah, yes, food.
Plenty of time for a leisurely meal.
Someone's coming.
(GASPS)
Gol, what's wrong?
-The wind has died.
-There's no wind?
1 don't believe it.
It's never stopped before.
- Ahhh!
- Obaba, what's the matter?
WOMAN: Are you okay?
Someone... Someone, take me outside.
Something is very wrong.
(ALL GASP)
The wind has stopped blowing.
(RINGING)
- Obaba, what's making my ears hurt?
-It's in the air.
The atmosphere
is saturated with anger.
We're close.
We've cleared the jungle.
Three minutes to the Acid Lake.
Idle the engines.
Drop beneath the clouds.
Princess, what's that red glow?
Ohm!
- (RUMBLING)
- (OHM SQUEAKING)
Look at them all.
Every Ohm in the jungle
is headed straight for the valley.
What's making them
stampede like that? (GASPS)
(DISTANT SQUEALING)
Something out there
is calling to the herd.
- Mito, pull the ship up to the left.
- MITO: Roger.
What's that? Mito, send out a flare.
NAUSICAA: Ready?
Fire!
(EXPLOSION)
What the heck is that?
(GASPS)
No, they've got a baby Ohm.
They're using the baby
to lure the herd into the valley.
- I'll blast them out of the sky.
- No!
Don't shoot, Mito! Don't shoot!
What do you mean, don't shoot?
NAUSICAA: If we kill the baby Ohm,
there'll be no way to stop the stampede.
What are we supposed to do?
I can't just sit here
and watch our valley be destroyed.
Don't worry, Mito.
I'll get the baby Ohm back to the herd.
Just trust me.
Hey, what are you doing?
Go warn the valley!
But, Princess,
you don't even have a weapon.
MAN 1: Standby those engines.
MAN 2: That's right.
That flare is not one of ours,
Your Highness.
-What's the range?
- Approximately 20 leagues.
Just the other side of the lake.
- Is it the Princess' gunship?
- Most likely.
(WHISTLING)
(EXPLOSION)
MAN: It's a flare.
Yes, that's their distress signal.
It's the gunship, all right.
Hour's up, Kurotowa. Let's go.
- Sure you don't want to wait?
- No, I have chosen the bloody path.
MAN: Infantry, move out!
-Won't you go in?
- I'm staying right here.
The gunship!
Fire!
(GASPS) Hold your fire!
You idiot, stop it!
- It's the Princess' gunship!
- Princess!
Wait for my orders. Hold your fire!
Your Highness!
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
-What happened to the Princess?
-Yeah, where is she?
Shouldn't she be in the backseat?
Listen up.
A herd of Ohm is coming this way.
-They're what?
- ALL: The Ohm?
The Princess stayed behind
to try to stop the stampede
from reaching the valley.
This is no time for a battle.
Everybody, get to high ground. Hurry!
-The Ohm!
- Come on!
Obaba, I see a red glow in the distance.
- It keeps getting bigger.
- CHILD: It's coming this way.
Just hold on tight to Obaba, children.
The Ohm will come.
There's nothing we can do about it.
- MAN: Quickly!
- (ALL CLAMORING)
Don't panic. Just keep moving forward.
- Hurry!
-There's still time.
But, Mito, we're going to die anyway.
-We should die in the valley.
- No.
As long as the Princess
hasn't given up, we can't, either.
Hold the Ohm off
for as long as possible.
I'll be back with help.
Your Highness, don't do it!
It's not ready yet.
If not now, Kurotowa, then when?
Move out!
Don't shoot! Listen to me, please!
She flies like the wind!
I think she's trying to tell us something.
Maybe we shouldn't shoot her.
Anyone who interferes
with the plan is an enemy.
Besides, if we don't release
this baby Ohm in the valley soon,
we'll be the ones in trouble.
Here she comes.
Wait till she gets close, and then fire.
(GASPS)
- She's in range. Shoot her!
-l can't.
- It's Lastelle.
- Move it!
(ALL GRUNT)
(SQUEAKS)
(GASPING)
Ohm... (GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Don't be frightened.
I'm not your enemy.
(SOBBING)
I'm so sorry.
Is there any way you can forgive us?
We've treated you so badly.
No, no, ho, no, don't move.
You'll bleed to death.
Come on. Be a good boy. Hold still.
- (RUMBLING)
- (GASPS)
Oh, no! They've found us!
They're coming this way!
No, you can't go in this lake
with wounds like that!
This water's bad! It's filled with acid!
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS, CRIES IN PAIN)
(BUZZING)
Ohm?
(SOBBING)
You're so kind. It's gonna be all right.
Soon they'll be here to take you home.
Where are they going?
How can they be turning away?
Ohm, not that way!
You're headed straight for the valley!
They must be blind with rage.
If 1 can't find a way to calm them...
(CRASHING)
(LAUGHING)
Those idiots! They're drawing
the Ohm with their fire.
-We're gonna live.
- Come on. Let's get out of here.
Help me tip this over.
Wait!
No, no, don't shoot! Don't shoot!
You're gonna fly me back to the herd,
and we're gonna give
their baby back to them.
There's no reason
to try to pull a stunt like that.
It's too late. The herd won't stop.
(SHRIEKING)
You'll take us there and you'll set us
down in front of the herd.
- Now, let's get going.
- But there's no way you'll survive.
MAN: Fire! Fire! Fire!
(MURMURING)
Obaba, are we all going to die?
If that is to be our fate,
we can only wait and see.
-They don't even flinch.
-I think we should retreat, sir.
Don't be stupid, soldier.
There's nowhere to retreat to.
Hey, hold your position!
Wait! Hold it!
Stand your ground
until Her Highness returns.
Where is she? (GASPS) Your Highness!
(DEEP ROARING GROWL)
- (ALL MURMURING)
- MAN 1: The giant warrior!
MAN 2: It's him!
MAN 3: It's the warrior!
(ALL CHEERING)
Now we got ‘em!
-WOMAN: It's the giant warrior!
- MAN: The warrior!
It's falling apart. I knew it was too soon.
Incinerate them!
What are you waiting for?
Were you not designed to be the most
evil creature on the face of the Earth?
- (WHIMPERING)
- (SCREAMING)
Amazing. No wonder
the world was incinerated.
MAN: Hail to Kushana!
Hit them again!
Listen to me, warrior.
Fire on my command!
(GROWLS)
(SHOUTING)
Run!
MAN 1: It's dead!
MAN 2: No!
MAN 3: We're doomed!
MAN 3: Run!
The giant warrior died.
That's the way it should be.
The anger of the Ohm
reflects the anger of the Earth.
The Earth knows it's wrong
for us to survive
if we have to depend
on a monster like that.
- It's the Princess!
-The Princess is back!
WOMAN 1: Princess!
WOMAN 2: What is she doing?
MAN: She'll be killed!
((CHITTERING, SQUEALING)
- (ALL GASP)
- (SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Look, the color's changing.
Their rage is subsiding.
The rage. It's left the atmosphere.
We're okay.
The Ohm have stopped running.
-There's the Princess!
- (CROWD GASPING)
She's dead, Obaba. She's dead.
The Princess has quieted
the rage of the Ohm.
She gave her life to save the valley.
(CROWD SOBBING)
MAN: Look! Over there!
What is this? What are these lights?
(CHILD SINGING)
Teto.
I'm glad you're okay.
Ohm, thank you.
Thank you!
It's a miracle!
What beautiful creatures!
Who knew how wonderful
and caring the Ohm could be?
Children!
Look carefully and tell me
what these blind eyes cannot see.
The Princess is wearing a blue dress
that I've never seen before.
CHILD: It looks like she's walking
through a golden field.
(GASPS)
After 1,000 years of darkness,
he will come, clad in blue and
surrounded by fields of gold!
(SOBBING)
What's the matter?
The legend has come true!
- Look there!
- (GASPS)
The glider!
MAN: There's wind!
WOMAN: The wind has come back!
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
THE END