(WIND WHISTLING)
(SQUEALING)
Yet another village is dead.
(GROWLING)
(BUZZING)
Let's go.
Soon this place, too, will be
consumed by the toxic jungle.
NARRATOR: A thousand years have passed
since the collapse of
industrialized civilization.
A toxic jungle now spreads,
threatening the survival of
the last of the human race.
(MUSIC)
(MUSIC SWELLS)
(CREATURES WHISTLING)
(GASPS)
Ohm tracks.
Looks like they're still fresh.
(GASPS)
A perfect Ohm shell.
Amazing.
I've never seen a whole shell before.
(DINGS)
(GASPS)
A perfect sound.
(GRUNTS, SHUDDERS)
Ah!
(GASPS) It even chipped
a Xerconian ceramic sword.
This should make the people
of the valley happy.
They won't have to worry
about finding materials
for making tools for a long time.
What an amazing eye.
I wonder if I could
fly back home with this.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) It came off.
It's so light.
(LAUGHING)
Oh! The Mushigo palms are sending
out their afternoon spores.
It's so beautiful.
It's hard to believe
these spores could kill me.
Five minutes without a mask,
and I'd be dead.
(GASPS)
What's that?
My heart's pounding.
What's going on?
(DISTANT BOOM)
(GASPS) Gunshots.
Someone's in trouble.
The insects must be attacking.
- (GROWLING)
- Oops, sorry.
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
There they are.
Look at that cloud of spores.
An Ohm!
It must be the one that shed that shell.
Whoever it's chasing
will never escape that way.
I hope they see the signal.
Good.They're coming this way.
There they are.
What an amazing Ohm.
(OHM BELLOWS)
- Get upwind of it!
- Right!
Ohm, go back to the jungle.
This is not your world.
Come on, now. Be good.
Look at those red eyes.
It's blind with rage. I've got to calm it.
Look at that.
She's stunned it with flash grenades.
(PULSATING HUM)
An insect charm.
Ohm, wake up.
You need to go back to your jungle.
(RUMBLING)
It's coming to.
Unbelievable.
It's going back to the jungle.
She turned it back with nothing but
an insect charm and flash grenades.
Lord Yupa!
(LAUGHING)
Nausicaa. I didn't recognize you.
It's been over a year now.
It's great to see you.
Thank you for helping me
with that Ohm.
You've certainly mastered
that glider of yours.
You think so? Father says
I have a long way to... Hmm?
Oh, yes. I forgot all about
this little fellow.
He's the reason I got in
trouble with the Ohm.
Wow, is that a fox-squirrel?
I've never seen one.
I hadn't, either.
I saw an insect carrying him off,
and I mistook him for a human baby.
I had no choice but to use my gun.
Oh. So, that's why the Ohm
was so angry with you.
He's quite spirited.
Apparently, he didn't inhale
too much of the jungle's poison.
Better not touch him.
Even the babies are vicious.
Come on.
- It's okay.
- (SQUEAKS)
Careful.
There's nothing to fear.
(GROWLING)
Nothing to fear.
- (CRUNCHES)
- (STIFLED GRUNT)
See? Nothing to fear.
(LIGHT GROWL)
Right?
You were just a little scared,
weren't you?
(LAUGHS)
He's perfect.
Will you let me keep him, Lord Yupa?
Of course. Certainly.
(GIGGLES) Thank you!
Kai, Kui! Do you remember me?
What a mysterious power she has.
(LAUGHING)
You must be tired after
running from that Ohm.
So, how's your family, Nausicaa?
What's wrong?
It's...
Father can't fly anymore.
King Jihl?
So the jungle's poisons
are taking their toll.
Yes.
Father says it's the fate of all
of us who live near the jungle.
I'm sorry. I should have come sooner.
No, I'm just glad you could come at all.
Lord Yupa, there's something
I want to show you
when we get back to the valley.
I've created my own secret room.
- Oh.
- I haven't shown it to anyone yet
because I think it'll frighten them.
You get to be the first.
I'll go on ahead and announce you.
See you there!
- Lord Yupa?
- Hmm?
Do you think you could
carry this back for me?
I'm afraid it's not
the easiest thing to fly with.
(CHUCKLES)
She certainly knows
how to read the wind.
Come, you twol We're almost there.
GOL: Oh! Lord Yupa!
Gol, Muzu, how have you been?
(GOL LAUGHS) Good, good!
The wind is strong
and the water is clear.
GIRL 1: Hi!
GIRL 2: Hi, Lord Yupa!
Hello, girls. You're looking well.
WOMAN: Welcome home, Lord Yupa!
MAN: We've waited so long
for your return!
Princess, Lord Yupa has arrived.
I'm almost finished.
Welcome back, Lord Yupa!
Why, Mito, you're looking fit!
Thank you, sir. I'm looking forward
to hearing all the news
from the other kingdoms tonight.
Okay, start her up!
Nice work, Princess.
Thanks.
This is high-grade material, Lord Yupa.
I'll send out a party to retrieve the rest
of the shell first thing tomorrow.
- Come on. It's okay.
- Yes, ma'am.
Lord Yupa, we had a baby born
in the valley this year.
Wonderful. Let's have a look.
Oh, she's a fine baby.
Strong and healthy.
She reminds me of Nausicai as a child.
We would be very honored
if you would choose a name for her.
With your blessing,
fair winds are sure to favor her.
Very well.
I'll see that she's given a good name.
Thank you, Lord Yupa.
May she grow up to be strong
just like Princess Nausicaa.
Hmph! It's good to hope for a daughter
who's strong like the Princess,
but not for one who likes
to play in the toxic jungle.
But, Mito, the jungle is where
I found the Ohm shell.
All I do is worry when she's
running around out there.
I'd trade 1,000 Ohm shells
for a good night's sleep.
(LAUGHS) Sorry, Mito.
We'd rather have the Ohm shells.
And I think the Princess should
explore all she wants.
I agree. Who else would rescue
me when I'm in trouble?
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CHILDREN CHEERING, LAUGHING)
MAN 1: Welcome home.
WOMAN 1: Welcome home, Lord Yupa,
you've been missed!
WOMAN 2: Our blessings, Lord Yupa!
MAN 2: We're so happy you've returned.
WOMAN 3: Lord Yupa!
(LORDYUPA, JIHL LAUGHING)
JIHL: So Nausicaa rescued
the great Lord Yupa?
This is such a wonderful valley, Jihl.
It soothes my heart.
How are the other kingdoms
you visited faring?
Mmm, things are grim.
I found two more kingdoms to the south
that have been consumed by the jungle.
It seems as if
it spreads faster every day.
And the kingdoms that still survive
are torn by war and starvation.
The cities are plagued with fear.
Why can't the other kingdoms
live happily as you do here?
It's because we have
the wind from the sea
to protect us from the jungle's poisons.
We know the poison
cannot reach us here.
Lord Yupa, isn't it about time
you settled down here?
With my present condition,
it would bring peace of mind to us all.
Hmm.
(OBABA LAUGHS)
That's impossible.
Lord Yupa must continue his search.
It's his destiny.
It's my destiny, is it?
Obaba, what is it
that Lord Yupa searches for?
What? Nausicaa.
How could you not know this, child?
The answer is on the tapestry
which hangs before you.
Although I can no longer see it,
I remember it well.
There is a figure in the upper left corner.
After 1,000 years of darkness,
he will come,
clad in blue and surrounded
by fields of gold
to restore mankind's connection
with the Earth that was destroyed.
And he will guide the people of this planet
at last to a land of purity.
Lord Yupa, are you searching
for the man in blue?
I thought that was just a myth.
It is a myth. Obaba is just teasing me.
Not true. That is the goal you seek.
The only goal I seek, Obaba,
is to understand the mysteries
of the toxic jungle.
I want to know if mankind is truly
fated to be swallowed up by it.
Or if there is still some hope
that we may survive.
I want to know the truth.
I wish there was something
I could do to help Lord Yupa.
(WIND HOWLING)
MITO: Princess? Princess?
Mito? What is it?
Gol has detected something in the wind.
All right, I'll be right there.
What's going on?
There's a good storm
brewing, Princess,
and I'm afraid something's not right.
(GASPS)
There it is. Up there!
It's an airship.
What in the world is an airship
doing way out here?
What's going on?
Lord Yupa, there's an airship.
- Are you sure?
- Here he comes.
(RUMBLING)
It's enormous.
(RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER)
(ALL GASP)
It's a Tolmekian ship.
It's in trouble.
They're trying to make
an emergency landing.
- Help me launch, Gol.
-What?
Princess, it's too dangerous.
I'll just guide them to the shore.
Here they come.
All right, Princess. Ready to launch!
Teto, hold on.
(GASPS)
Oh, no, they must have
landed in the jungle
and angered the insects!
Turn your ship! You're gonna crash!
Turn the ship!
Turn! (GASPS)
- It's down.
- The Princess.
They crashed, by the sea cliffs!
Let's go!
Everyone, to the cliffs!
- Let's go! Let's go!
- (ALL CLAMORING)
(GROANS)
There she is. She's alive.
(STRAINING)
- (GASPS) Where am I?
- Don't talk.
You're in the Valley of the Wind.
(GASPS)
I am Lastelle...
(GROANS)
Lastelle of Pejite.
You must... burn the cargo.
The cargo?
I beg of you, burn everything.
Yes, Lastelle, I understand.
Everything is burning. Don't you worry.
MAN 1: Look over there!
MAN 2: Where?
Thank God.
Princess!
MAN 1: Get that fire out!
MAN 2:Yes, follow me! Follow me!
MAN 1: Every direction!
MAN 2: We need more men!
MAN 3: Hurry!
(MEN CONTINUE SHOUTING)
A princess of Pejite?
What's she doing on a Tolmekian ship?
Everybody, get out now!
There's an insect in there!
No. Oh, no!
(CHIRPING)
MAN 1: Oh, no! It's calling for help!
MAN 2: Maybe it can't fly?
MAN 3: Get your guns!
Don't shoot!
You'll enrage every insect in the jungle!
I can kill it in one shot.
- You can't kill that thing with just a gun.
- Then what do you suggest we do?
- Wait.
- Huh?
- Mito, will you get my glider, please?
- Right away.
MAN: Princess!
Easy, Princess.
(CHIRPING STOPS)
(WHISTLING)
You need to return to
your jungle. Understand?
- (CHITTERING)
- You're strong. You can fly.
MAN: Look! It's working!
There. That's a good boy.
MAN 1: Step aside, please.
MAN 2: Hey! Give them room.
- Here you go, Princess.
- Thanks, Mito.
MEN: Yes. Yes!
MAN: Look, it's worked!
(MEN CHEERING)
MAN: Yes!
- Unbelievable!
- She did it!
Thank goodness.
I'd hate to think what
would have happened
if the insects in the jungle
would've come to its aid.
(GASPS)
An Ohm.
(SOFT RUMBLING)
MAN 1: This row is clear!
MAN 2: Don't touch this areal
MAN 1: It's all clear.
MAN 2: Haven't covered this part yet.
The west grove is open.
MAN 1: Do you see any?
Over here! I found one!
They found one?
Down here.
That ship was infested
with spores, all right.
Good thing you found this
before it released its poisons.
Keep up the good work, son.
I'll keep searching
till I find every last one.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
What in the world do
you think that thing is?
1 don't know. The fire didn't
seem to harm it at all.
Okay, everyone.
We'll examine this thing later.
Go help look for spores in the fields.
Make sure you get
every last one of ‘em!
What a mess those Tolmekians
dumped on us.
Mito, take a look at this.
What?
(PULSING RUMBLE)
It's beating like a heart.
Looks like this thing is alive.
Lord Yupa, what is this?
While I was traveling,
I heard a frightening rumor.
It was said that a monster
from the old word
was unearthed
from deep beneath the city of Pejite.
A monster from the old world?
A giant warrior.
A giant warrior?
From the Seven Days of Fire?
That was 1,000 years ago.
It can't be.
YUPA: After they incinerated the Earth,
all the giant warriors were
said to have tumed to stone.
Apparently, one has lain
dormant deep underground
for the past 1,000 years.
If they unearthed it in Pejite,
what was it doing on a Tolmekian ship?
Tolmekia is far to the west,
and its rulers are very warlike.
That they had a Pejite hostage
on board worries me.
(MEN GRUNTING)
- Take care of the rest, will you?
- Right.
(SQUEAKING)
What can that be?
(RUMBLING)
- (GASPS) What's that?
- What's that?
- (PEOPLE MURMURING)
- WOMAN: What?
(PANICKED CHATTER, SHRIEKING)
Tolmekian airships!
Get everyone to the castle!
Out of the way!
(PANTING)
Everyone, to the castle!
Hurry! (GASPS)
They're after Father!
Move out! Move!
Go!
Obaba, quickly, hide yourself.
I think I'll stay right here.
MAN: Go, go! Go!
Up there.
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (GASPS)
GIRL: Princess!
(GASPS)
- How could you?
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
- (GASPS) Nausicaa!
- (SCREAMING)
Don't move.
This Ohm shell knife
can slice right through
that Xerconian ceramic armor of yours.
MAN: That's Lord Yupa,
the sword master.
Soldiers of Tolmekia, hear me now.
Last night, the people of this valley
risked their lives
attempting to prevent
your airship from crashing.
And just this morning, they finished
giving your dead a proper burial.
This may be a small kingdom,
but it clearly deserves
your courtesy and respect.
If you are here to make war,
there must be a fitting reason,
and it's only right to
first send a messenger
to announce your grievances.
(SHUDDERING)
Nausicaa, be calm.
If you fight now, the people
of the valley will be massacred.
We must stay alive and wait
for the right opportunity.
(GROANING)
I'm going to...
- WOMAN: Put it down, Kurotowa.
- But she...
Oh, fine. But look at this mess.
Now I must acquire all new men.
So, you're Lord Yupa,
the greatest swordsman in the land.
I'm offended that you think
we need reprimanding.
We're not savages who've
come to massacre your people.
We're here to talk. So would you put
your knife away? Please?
MAN: Ah, beat it.
MAN: Secure the room.
(LOW MURMURS)
- It's the Princess.
-The Princess.
- WOMAN: She's okay.
- (EXCITED MURMURS)
MAN: Listen now.
You will be addressed
by Her Highness Kushana,
commander of the Tolmekian army.
Villagers,
we have come to your land
in the name of peace.
Our goal is to unify the kingdoms
surrounding Tolmekia,
and build a world of prosperity.
You now live at the edge of the jungle,
on the verge of extinction.
Follow us, and join our enterprise.
We shall put the toxic jungle
to the torch
- and resurrect this land together.
- MAN 1: Burn the toxic jungle?
MAN 2: With what?
MAN 3: Is that possible?
I have in my possession
mankind's greatest tool,
the awesome force which
once allowed human beings
to rule the Earth.
I guarantee that those who join me
will live without fear of the insects
or the jungle's poisons ever again.
OBABA: Stop! Stop, I say!
You must not touch the toxic jungle.
What are you babbling about, woman?
Guards, take her away.
No, let her speak.
Since the origin of the toxic jungle,
1,000 years ago,
people tried time and again to burn it.
But time and again, their attempts
did nothing but enrage the Ohm,
and swarms of them
spilled from the jungle
and stampeded across the lands.
They toppled cities,
destroyed kingdoms
and killed thousands.
The Ohm could not be stopped.
Such rage did they feel,
the Ohm fought till
they died of starvation.
Then spores took root in their corpses,
and the land soon
became part of the toxic jungle.
That's why you do not interfere with it.
Silence, you old hag.
We will have none of your raving.
You won't, will you? How will you shut
me up? Will you kill me, too?
Ah, silence, I said!
Go ahead and kill me!
It'll be easier for you
to kill an old, blind woman
than it was for you
to murder our King Jihl!
- King Jihl?
- (ALL GASPING)
What? He was bedridden!
MAN: You murderers! You'll pay for this!
We won't let you get away with this!
Silence them! No mercy for the insolent.
Quiet, everyone, please.
I need everybody to listen to me.
(CLAMORING STOPS)
I can't bear to have anyone else die.
I beg of you...
Princess.
Obaba, please understand.
We need to do as the Tolmekians say.
(SAD MURMURS, SOBBING)
MAN: Move! Move!
Heave! Heave! Heavel
Heave!
MAN: Set it down over there.
Let's go. Come on!
Nice valley. I think we should keep it.
I must object, Your Highness.
Our orders are to transport the giant
warrior back to Tolmekia immediately.
Those orders cannot be carried out.
The giant warrior is so heavy,
even our largest ship
couldn't transport it.
Your Highness,
you can't seriously want to stay here
and start a new kingdom?
Then what should I do?
You really think
I should deliver up that monster
as a plaything
for those fools back home?
Ah, yes, I do see your point.
But I am just a soldier of Tolmekia.
lam not in a position
to make that decision.
Hmm. Weasel.
I'm reporting back to Pejite.
While I'm gone,
begin to awaken the warrior.
Right.
KUSHANA:They have a gunship?
KUROTOWA:Yes, an unexpected find
for such a quaint valley.
KUSHANA: Those are my orders.
I'll leave for Pejite
first thing in the morning.
But, Kushana, why must
the Princess go with you?
Aren't five hostages,
food and the gunship enough?
Select your five hostages
and load up the cargo barge
before tomorrow's departure.
MAN: Take it all.
(MEN GRUNTING)
We leave nothing here.
Mito, thank you
for accompanying the Princess.
No, I'm glad to go.
But look at those greedy Tolmekians.
They're stripping us of everything.
Don't worry about that.
Our only concern is that
the warrior stay dormant.
I'm going to leave the valley, then I'll
slip back and wait for my chance.
Good luck.
LORDYUPA: Nausicaa?
(SCRATCHING)
Teto, where has Nausicaa gone?
(CHITTERING)
(GASPS)
Nausicai, what are you doing here?
This chamber is filled with toxic plants.
I collected the spores
and grew them down here myself.
Don't worry.
The plants aren't poisonous.
They're not poisonous?
(SNIFFS) It's true.
The air is pure in here.
But I know these plants from the jungle.
These are some of the most lethal.
l irrigated this chamber using water
drawn from deep underground
by the castle windmill.
I used soil drawn from there as well.
I found that, with clean water and soil,
the plants from the toxic jungle
aren't poisonous.
All the poison is in the soil.
Even the topsoil in our valley
is polluted.
But I don't understand
who could've polluted the entire Earth.
You discovered this all on your own?
Yes. I was hoping to find
a cure for Father's illness.
But... (SOBS)
It's too late now. I'm shutting down.
I've already cut off the water.
Soon, these plants will wither and die.
(SOBBING)
Nausicaa.
I'm afraid of myself, Lord Yupa.
I had no idea that my rage
could drive me to kill.
(SOBBING) No more killing.
It has to stop.
(MURMURING)
CHILDREN: Princess Nausicaa!
We gathered these for you.
- Chiko nuts.
-You can take them on your trip.
Oh, my.
There are so many.
You must have worked very hard.
(CHILDREN SOBBING)
Thank you.
I'll think of you when I eat them.
CHILD: We don't want you to go.
Hurry up! Get in the ship.
(SOBBING)
All right, I must go now.
There's no need to cry.
I'll be back very soon, okay?
You mean it?
Of course!
Have I ever broken a promise to you?
No.
See?
Mmm-hmm.
You'll come back, huh?
Now, be good while I'm gone.
-We will.
- Okay.
Bye!
ALL: Bye, Princess!
- Good luck!
-Take care of the Princess!
Protect her!
Hey, Niga, aren't we in Pejite yet?
Yeah, hurry it up. My back is killing me.
Good Lord, no wonder
they sent you two off to be hostages.
- All you do is complain.
- (LAUGHING)
Hey, doesn't this
formation seem strange?
Why are we flying so close together?
MAN: Yeah.
It's as if they fear an attack.
The air beneath the clouds must be
charged with poisonous gas. (GASPS)
(GASPS)
-What?
- MAN: Hey, sit down.
It's a gunship!
MAN: Enemy ship! We're under fire!
Your Highness, they're attacking us!
- (NAUSICAA GASPS)
- (ALL SHOUTING)
- (ALARM BLARING)
- MAN: Our number two ship is down!
MAN 1: What did I tell you?
MAN 2: This is terrible!
(ALL SCREAM)
MAN 1: Look out!
He's coming in from below!
- MAN 2: That's a Pejite gunship!
- Pejite?
MAN 1: Number Three's been hit!
MAN 2: Signal from Number Three!
MAN 1:They can't steer!
They can't steer!
-Where's our fighter plane?
-These are some flimsy ships.
He's hit the rear guard!
(GASPS)
The barge detached.
Teto, come on.
We're going down.
We got to get out of here.
Princess!
Stop it! All this killing must stop!
You must stop!
(GASPS)
Princess!
(YELLS)
-This way, Mito.
- (MITO GROANING)
Princess, where are you going?
- Let's try the gunship.
-What?
Mito, hurry up!
Uh, right.
Start the engine.
Then we'll shoot the door open.
Got it!
(GASPS)
Come on!
Hurry!
Here, get in!
- Can we launch?
-1 hope so.
Open the throttle to full,
then fire the guns.
MITO: Roger.
NAUSICAA: Ready? Now!
Put on your masks.
I'm going below the clouds
to rescue the cargo barge.
Hold on, Teto. Don't die.
MITO: Look at this. I've never seen
the poison this dense before.
Mito, watch the starboard
side of the ship.
We should come across
the barge any minute.
Roger.
NAUSICAA: It should be gliding.
MITO: There it is!
Down to the right.
ALL: Princess Nausicaa!
Hold on. I'll throw you a tow rope.
The towing hook broke.
We can't be towed.
I don't want to land in the jungle.
The insects will eat us alive!
We'd rather jump to our deaths.
Calm down. Just dump the cargo,
and we'll help you land.
MEN: Goodbye.
MAN: Nice knowing you!
MITO: Listen to me.
Just dump the cargo.
Mito, cut the rear engine.
-What?
- Just do as I say. Hurry!
All right.
(ALL GASP)
Princess, what are you doing?
MAN 1: Put on your mask!
MAN 2: You'll die!
MAN 1: Put it back onl!
Listen, please. Dump your cargo
and glide down with us.
You'll be just fine.
MAN 1: We'll do whatever you say!
Just put your mask on!
Do it now, please!
Look at her smiling.
She actually thinks
we're going to be okay.
- Hurry! Ditch the cargo!
- Hurry!
Start the engine.
We'll look for a place to land.
Ah, l inhaled some of that poison.
MAN 1: Hurry it up!
MAN 2: This is so wasteful!
MAN 1: Don't think about it. Just hurry.
MAN 1: What do we do?
MAN 2: Princess!
- Is everyone okay?
-ALL:Yeah.
- KUSHANA: Don't move.
-You.
Thank you for rescuing me, Nausicaa.
Princess, you brought her
with you on purpose?
You're too naive.
You shouldn't think we're best friends
now, just because you saved me.
Listen, you don't understand the jungle.
This is no place for guns.
If you fire that here,
the insects will descend upon us
in seconds.
They're already enraged
from all your ships
crashing into their jungle.
- Look at them swarming.
- (INSECTS BUZZING)
The giant dragonflies
are the sentries of the jungle.
Soon, they'll summon hordes
of insects to this site.
We must get out of here now.
Bring me your extra rope. Quickly.
- (MEN AGREEING)
- Mito, repair their towing hook.
MITO: Right.
Oh.
Don't move.
I'm the one who gives the orders.
What are you so afraid of?
You act like a scared little fox-squirrel.
What did you call me?
Don't be afraid. There's nothing to fear.
1 just want you to go back
to your own country.
How dare you talk to me that way?
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTING)
They're here.
(GASPS)
Stay calm.
Whatever you do, don't startle them.
We're in the middle of an Ohm nest!
(WHIMPERING)
We're surrounded!
They're examining us.
Ohm, please forgive us
for disturbing your nest.
We're very sorry.
We are not your enemies.
We mean you no harm.
(WHIMPERING)
- Princess?
- (GASPS)
(CHILD SINGING)
(SINGING FADES)
(GASPS) The pilot from Pejite.
He's still alive? Ohm, wait!
What's going on?
-Their eyes are red with rage!
- (ALLYELL)
Princess, what in the world
do you think you're doing?
Take off as soon as the waters are calm,
and wait for me above the cloud line.
Mito, if I'm not back in one hour,
return to the valley.
Are you crazy?
MITO: Princess, no!
MAN: The Princess is gone.
MITO: Why don't I take that for you?
All right, let's do as the Princess said.
She better be okay.
(SQUEALING)
Whoa!
I'm trapped.
(GUN CLICKS)
It's jammed.
Ah!
(SCREAMING)
No... Ah!
-Who are you?
-You've done far too much killing.
My insect charm and flash grenade
won't do any good now.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
Quicksand.
Nol
Oh! (PANTING)
(BUZZING)
MAN: It's already been two hours.
MITO: More insects keep coming
by the minute.
MAN: Princess, where are you?
Princess!
MAN: (ECHOING) Nausicaa.
Nausicaa.
- (CHILD SINGING)
- Come here.
Come here, child.
YOUNG NAUSICAA: Father!
Mother's here, too?
Wait. Don't go this way.
Stay away! Ah!
Get back! There's nothing here!
Stay away from me! Please go.
(CRACKLING)
Get back inside.
She's got a baby Ohm.
The insects have bewitched her.
Hand it over, child.
YOUNG NAUSICAA: No.
It hasn't done anything wrong.
MAN: Insects and humans
cannot live in the same world.
You know that.
(YOUNG NAUSICAA SHRIEKS)
You knew that.
Don't kill it! Please, don't kill it!
Please. (SOBBING)
(CHILD SINGING RETURNS)
- (SQUEAKS)
- (SINGING STOPS)
Teto.
What a strange place.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PANTING) Hey!
I found your glider.
How are you feeling?
Where are we?
I should introduce myself first.
I'm Ashel from the land of Pejite.
I'd like to thank you for saving me.
I'm Nausicaa.
I'm from the Valley of the Wind.
What is this place?
(LAUGHING)
You're not going to believe this.
We're actually beneath the toxic jungle.
- Beneath the jungle?
-Yeah.
See that?
We fell through that hole up there.
Along with a bunch of sand.
(GASPS) How can we be breathing
without our masks?
1 don't know.
Somehow the air down here is clean.
I couldn't believe it, either.
I never dreamed
the toxic jungle could be like this.
What's wrong?
Nausicaa, don't wander off too far.
NAUSICAA: What a magnificent tree.
(WATER TRICKLING)
It's dead,
but water's still flowing through it.
This is like the sand
from the bottom of our well.
It looks like these trees
must die and fossilize,
and then crumble into sand.
Nausicaa?
Are you crying?
Mmm. It's okay, though.
I'm just happy.
I can't believe she's dead.
Lastelle was my twin sister.
1 wish I could have been there for her.
I'm sorry. I was too late to save her.
No.
I apologize.
You took care of my sister
while she was dying,
and I just shot down your ship.
It's okay.
So, the giant warrior's
in the Valley of the Wind now.
(CRUNCHING)
(GROANS)
Ugh, these nuts taste awful.
What are they?
They're called Chiko nuts.
They're supposed to be good for you.
(MOUTH FULL) Why is it everything
that's good for you tastes so bad?
(LAUGHING)
What's the origin of the jungle?
You sure spend a lot of time
thinking about strange things.
The trees of the toxic jungle
must have evolved
to purify the Earth of all the pollution
that we humans have made.
The trees absorb the pollution
so it becomes inert.
Then they die and petrify
and then crumble into purified sand.
That's how these underground
caverns must've been formed.
And the insects,
they evolved to guard this place.
If that's true, then mankind
is destined to go extinct.
It'll take centuries
for these trees to cleanse the Earth.
We can't survive with insects that long.
Somehow, we are going to
have to find a way
to stop this toxic jungle from spreading.
You Pejites sound
just like the Tolmekians.
What? We are nothing like those
bloodthirsty Tolmekians.
We'd never use the warrior
as a weapon.
Let's get some sleep, Asbel.
We'll need our strength
to make it to Pejite tomorrow.
(PULSING)
MAN: All is well, sir.
KUROTOWA: Fine, fine.
- Everything going smoothly?
-Yes, sir.
The warrior's torso is almost developed.
I swear, the more I gaze at you,
the more attractive you get.
You're awakening
long-forgotten ambitions,
even in a lazy old soldier like me.
Oh, is that a smile?
Perhaps you should remain buried
deep beneath the Earth after all.
- Sir!
- Mmm.
Her Highness's fleet was attacked
by a survivor from Pejite.
All but one of her ships were destroyed.
KUROTOWA: What happened
to Her Highness?
According to our reports,
her ship exploded in midair.
MAN: How shall we proceed, sir?
Do the villagers know
that their princess's ship went down?
- No, sir.
- Good. Keep it that way.
Continue working
as if nothing has changed.
ALL: Yes, sir.
So, is this lowly soldier
finally on the path to fame and fortune,
or on the path to destruction?
Lord Yupa,
Mito and the others are back.
They're all waiting for you
at the Acid Lake.
Down there.
MITO: We shouldn't have returned
without the Princess.
LORDYUPA: No, I'm glad
that all of you are safe.
You're letting me go?
LORDYUPA:Yes, granted that you
drown the giant warrior in the Acid Lake
and then return to your kingdom.
You have very few soldiers
left in the valley.
We could easily defeat your forces now,
but I see no point in further killing.
The warrior can't be
drowned or destroyed,
and until it walks on its own,
it can't be moved.
Don't you understand? It's too late.
There's no turning back now.
I was ordered to attack Pejite
because we feared
another kingdom would
get a hold of the warrior's power.
Once its existence is known,
all the remaining kingdoms
will send their armies here to claim it.
You really only have
one choice, Lord Yupa.
Revive the giant warrior.
Use it to repel the invading kingdoms
and learn to live with the monster.
Look.
(GASPING)
Hmm.
An insect did that?
That's right, and whatever
lucky man becomes my husband
will see worse than that.
The insects must be stopped.
You must revive the warrior and use it
to destroy them and their jungle.
Steal it from us
as we stole it from Pejite.
That's what I'd do if I were you.
No, we will keep the warrior dormant
as it was meant to be.
(GASPING) Lord Yupa!
- Emergency!
-You gotta give us the password.
-I'mina humy!
-Wind?
-Valley!
- Okay.
- Some of the spores survived!
-What? In the valley?
They're spreading poison everywhere.
The whole valley's in a panic.
(PANICKED MURMURING)
WOMAN: It's poison! See them?
(CLAMORING)
MAN 1: Please, don't be foolish!
MAN 2: We need to do something.
- MAN 3: Hurry!
- MAN 1: Before it's too late!
If we don't do something fast,
the whole valley will be destroyed.
Hurry, the spores are spreading fast.
If we give them tools to burn the spores,
they could use them against us instead.
We have no choice.
Hand over everything but their guns.
Yes, sir.
- Sir, the ship is ready.
-Try not to fail this time.
Assemble all the Tolmekian soldiers
left in Pejite
- and bring them to the valley.
-Yes, sir.
What a mess.
This is starting to look bad already.
(ALL SHOUTING) Come on! Hurry!
Let's go! Let's go!
Good luck finding the Princess.
Take care of the valley, and don't do
anything rash while we're gone.
ALL: Yes, sir.
Come on. Let's get back to the valley.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
Check it!
MAN: Oh, no!
We're too late.
The spores have infested
the entire tree.
This one's infected, too!
- WOMAN: This way!
- Get out of the way!
MAN: Hey, what do you think
you're doing?
(GRUNTING)
Oh, no. It's everywhere.
MAN: Obaba.
OBABA: This forest is doomed.
We must burn it down.
If we hesitate, the toxic jungle
will engulf the entire valley.
Isn't there some other way?
This forest has protected the valley
from the jungle's poisons for 300 years.
If only the Tolmekians had never come.
It looks like
things are getting out of control.
We better get back there fast.
ASBEL: You think so?
Everything looks the same to me.
NAUSICAA: The insects
have left the jungle.
What's going on?
My heart's pounding like crazy.
ASBEL: Hey, we're almost there!
Pejite's just over that mountain.
Something strange is going on.
What's that haze over there?
Asbel, put your mask on!
ASBEL: The insects. They're all dead.
-We've got to get to Pejite.
- Be careful.
The Tolmekian army
could still be there.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
NAUSICAA: A dead Ohm.
ASBEL: And the capital's
been destroyed.
Pejite is finished.
It was far too much to pay, even if it
did get the Tolmekians out of our city.
"Too much to pay"?
Asbel, what are you talking about?
An airship.
ASBEL: It's one of ours!
They're landing. Let's go.
MAN: Asbel, you're still alive.
What have you done to our city?
It's completely destroyed!
Don't worry. We can rebuild it.
And if the jungle starts to spread here,
we'll burn it off.
With what? The giant warrior isn't here.
We know. It's in the Valley of the Wind.
How do you know that?
(CHUCKLES) We've already
made plans to get it back.
Our plan is being executed
as we speak.
All Tolmekians in the valley
will be dead...
ASBEL:What?
What are you planning to do
to my valley?
Asbel, who is this?
She's the princess
of the Valley of the Wind,
and she saved my life.
- (MEN GASP)
-The Valley of the Wind?
Tell me! What is gonna happen?
Asbel, you know what the plan is.
You have to tell me.
We're going to bait insects
into the valley.
(GASPS)
So you lured the insects
here into Pejite?
(SOBBING)
What a monstrous thing to do.
We have to get the giant warrior
out of the hands of the Tolmekians,
no matter what it takes.
We're doing this for the good
of the planet. You've got to understand.
The good of the planet?
You're killing my people!
Don't do this, I beg you!
Please, please, stop this now!
It's too late.
Once the insects start stampeding,
they can't be stopped.
The Tolmekians nearly
killed off all our people.
They must be stopped.
We have no other choice.
- Stop her!
- MAN 1: Stop her!
MAN 2: Grab her!
Let me go!
Ah! Let me go!
Things may seem
bad to you now, Princess,
but once we have the warrior, we'll burn
the jungle, and take back the Earth.
You savages!
You're just as bad as the Tolmekians!
You're wrong. The Tolmekians
want to take over the world.
Listen, every one of us
relies on water from the wells,
because mankind has polluted
all the lakes and rivers.
But do you know why
the well water is pure?
The trees of the wasteland purify it.
And you plan to burn the trees down?
You must not burn down
the toxic jungle!
You should have left the giant warrior
beneath the Earth!
So what should we do?
Surrender and become
the slaves of the Tolmekians?
Don't you understand?
Asbel, tell them how the jungle evolved,
and how the insects are guarding it
so we won't pollute the world again.
Asbel, please?
- (GRUNTS) What are you doing?
- Stay right there.
Let go of the Princess, now!
Calm down, Ashel.
ASBEL: Let her go!
I mean it!
Nausicai, go back
and warn your people.
- (ASBEL GRUNTS)
- (NAUSICAA GASPS)
Asbel! Let me go!
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
What a bunch of fools.
I can't wait to beat the tar
out of those Tolmekians.
I thought we said
we wouldn't do anything rash.
Don't panic.
Just rescue the soldiers with the tanks.
-Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
Sir, the villagers just killed
our last soldier on the field.
- Are they heading for the castle?
- Not yet.
But more of them keep gathering.
All this over a little forest.
They're as annoying as the Pejites.
If they just calmed down...
Look out!
Huh?
(SCREAMING)
They hijacked our tank.
- Get this thing moving!
- I'm going. Don't rush me.
- MAN: Fire!
- Here they come!
Forward!
Come on, come on. Let's go.
Maybe it's this one.
Hey, it's doing something.
Niga, where are you going?
(ALL GASPING, SHOUTING)
What do you think you're doing?
- Go forward!
- I know. I know.
MAN 1:The tank!
MAN 2: Let's stop it!
MAN 3: Stop them!
They're getting away!
Send out all the tanks! (GASPS)
MAN 1: Your Highness.
MAN 2: Attention!
She's alive.
That dream didn't last long.
Your Highness!
We'll hold off the troops.
You round up the villagers
and seek shelter by the Acid Lake.
- Right. Let's go!
- Come on!
We just have to lie low until
the Princess returns in the gunship.
MAN 1: Don't slow down!
MAN 2:You can make it!
Keep moving!
Don't just stand there. Give me a hand.
But I have a bad back.
NIGA: Oh, get us out of here!
The tanks are coming!
You're turning in circles.
MAN: I know, I know.
NIGA: Go forward!
(SCREAMING)
MAN: We're hit!
- (ALARM BLARING)
- (GRUNTING)
What do you got, soldier?
It's a ship from Pejite.
I caught a glimpse
just beyond the clouds.
Good work.
MAN: Careful. She's a wild one.
Quicldy now.
Nausicaa, we're going
to get you out of here
$0 you can
warn the people of the valley.
There may still be enough time
if you take your glider.
It's ready and waiting for you.
Asbel told me everything
that has happened.
I'm going to be
taking your place, Princess.
- Put this on.
- But who are you?
I'm Asbel and Lastelle's mother.
(GASPS)
You're their mother.
(SIGHS) Please, forgive us.
What our people did
was horribly wrong.
Hurry.
NAUSICAA: What will happen to her?
WOMAN: Don't worry. She'll be fine.
WOMAN 1: There she is.
WOMAN 2: Yes, the Princess.
Please be careful.
And forgive us
for the way you've been treated.
- ASBEL: Nausicaa, this way.
- Here.
- Hurry.
- WOMAN 1: Be careful.
WOMAN 2: Good luck.
Thank you, everyone.
WOMAN 3: Take care.
I'm sory it took me so long.
Can you launch from here?
I'll try.
The Tolmekians!
Get us out of here! Head for the clouds!
MAN: Cease fire!
They'll never survive.
It's a pilot's worst nightmare
in those clouds.
MAN: This is suicide! I can't steer!
(ALL SCREAMING)
The storm is tearing the ship apart!
It's no use!
Our only hope is to
get out of these clouds and fight back!
- Oh!
-They expected this.
Look. What are they doing?
Oh, no. They're trying to pin us against
the clouds so they can board our ship.
(GRUNTING)
Open it up!
They're coming in.
You got to get out of here now!
I can't just leave you like this.
Or your mother, or the girl
who took my place in the cell.
You need all the help you can get!
You have to save the people
of the valley. Please.
Go, or my people
will never forgive themselves.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (BOTH GASP)
MAN: Go, go, go!
Take the ship.
I want every Pejite dead. Now.
- (GROWLS)
- (GASPS)
Go, Nausicai, go!
Asbell
There's the Princess!
Mito!
(SHRIEKS)
Ha-hal
NAUSICAA: Mito, Lord Yupa,
the valley's in danger.
- MITO: Princess!
- Hurry! Hurry! Please!
I'll send out the docking hook now.
Lord Yupa, pull the red lever
on your right.
Why is this taking so long?
Knock it down.
- (PANICKED MURMURS)
- (BABY CRYING)
This door's gonna bust
any second now.
Fine. Let them break it down.
We must fight them
with honor and with dignity.
What's behind us?
A bird?
Look! A gunship
from the Valley of the Wind!
What?
- (GROANS)
- (ALL GRUNT)
Get him!
(GRUNTS)
(MEN SCREAM)
It's Lord Yupa.
Kill him, and you'll be famous.
I suggest you surrender.
There's no ship coming to rescue you.
This guy's tough.
This is way too fast!
The engine's gonna burn out!
I don't care, as long as it holds out
until we get to the valley.
Increase speed!
Please, dear God,
please hear this prayer.
You must protect
the people of the valley.
- (COUGHING)
- (WHISPERING)
MAN 1: I don't like this waiting.
MAN 2: Check your weapons.
Well, this is dull.
Are they ever going to budge?
-They're waiting for their princess.
-The princess?
They expect her to come back here
and rescue them with their gunship.
That gunship could be
areal pain in the neck.
Should we start a fight now
and avoid the mess?
Do you know anything
about that old ship they're hiding in?
KUROTOWA: I've heard it was built
before the Seven Days of Fire.
I don't know if it's true,
but it's supposed to have traveled
everywhere, even to the stars.
They say guns can't
penetrate its armor,
but I bet if you hit it just right...
No, we're going to wait for the Princess.
What?
I want to see if she can make it back
alive from the middle of the jungle.
If she's not dead, I'd like a chance
to get to know her.
So, men, have you
made up your minds yet?
If you advise the villagers
to surrender, I'll let you go.
Or would you rather end up like Pejite?
It's strange that you're a princess, too.
You're not anything at all
like our princess.
Ah, take a look at my hands.
I have the same illness as King Jihl.
Six months from now,
my hands will be as hard as rocks.
But our princess told me that she truly
loves these beat-up old hands of mine.
When she looks at these hands,
she knows these
are the hands of a hard worker.
How can you be so foolish?
The jungle is killing you,
yet you want to live in harmony with it?
You plan to burn down the jungle,
but we've learned to use fire
only in small amounts.
That's right.
Too much fire gives birth to nothing.
Fire can reduce a forest
to ashes in a day,
while it takes the water and the wind
100 years to grow one anew.
We prefer the ways
of the water and the wind.
The Princess will be devastated
when she sees that our forest is gone.
Sir. Do we have any orders yet, sir?
- Just shut up.
-Yes, sir.
Something must have happened,
because she's starting to look
kind of cute to me.
Kurotowa, prepare the troops to attack.
What? We're not going to wait?
We'll begin the attack in one hour,
so get the troops fed and ready to go.
Ah, yes, food.
Plenty of time for a leisurely meal.
Someone's coming.
(GASPS)
Gol, what's wrong?
-The wind has died.
-There's no wind?
1 don't believe it.
It's never stopped before.
- Ahhh!
- Obaba, what's the matter?
WOMAN: Are you okay?
Someone... Someone, take me outside.
Something is very wrong.
(ALL GASP)
The wind has stopped blowing.
(RINGING)
- Obaba, what's making my ears hurt?
-It's in the air.
The atmosphere
is saturated with anger.
We're close.
We've cleared the jungle.
Three minutes to the Acid Lake.
Idle the engines.
Drop beneath the clouds.
Princess, what's that red glow?
Ohm!
- (RUMBLING)
- (OHM SQUEAKING)
Look at them all.
Every Ohm in the jungle
is headed straight for the valley.
What's making them
stampede like that? (GASPS)
(DISTANT SQUEALING)
Something out there
is calling to the herd.
- Mito, pull the ship up to the left.
- MITO: Roger.
What's that? Mito, send out a flare.
NAUSICAA: Ready?
Fire!
(EXPLOSION)
What the heck is that?
(GASPS)
No, they've got a baby Ohm.
They're using the baby
to lure the herd into the valley.
- I'll blast them out of the sky.
- No!
Don't shoot, Mito! Don't shoot!
What do you mean, don't shoot?
NAUSICAA: If we kill the baby Ohm,
there'll be no way to stop the stampede.
What are we supposed to do?
I can't just sit here
and watch our valley be destroyed.
Don't worry, Mito.
I'll get the baby Ohm back to the herd.
Just trust me.
Hey, what are you doing?
Go warn the valley!
But, Princess,
you don't even have a weapon.
MAN 1: Standby those engines.
MAN 2: That's right.
That flare is not one of ours,
Your Highness.
-What's the range?
- Approximately 20 leagues.
Just the other side of the lake.
- Is it the Princess' gunship?
- Most likely.
(WHISTLING)
(EXPLOSION)
MAN: It's a flare.
Yes, that's their distress signal.
It's the gunship, all right.
Hour's up, Kurotowa. Let's go.
- Sure you don't want to wait?
- No, I have chosen the bloody path.
MAN: Infantry, move out!
-Won't you go in?
- I'm staying right here.
The gunship!
Fire!
(GASPS) Hold your fire!
You idiot, stop it!
- It's the Princess' gunship!
- Princess!
Wait for my orders. Hold your fire!
Your Highness!
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
-What happened to the Princess?
-Yeah, where is she?
Shouldn't she be in the backseat?
Listen up.
A herd of Ohm is coming this way.
-They're what?
- ALL: The Ohm?
The Princess stayed behind
to try to stop the stampede
from reaching the valley.
This is no time for a battle.
Everybody, get to high ground. Hurry!
-The Ohm!
- Come on!
Obaba, I see a red glow in the distance.
- It keeps getting bigger.
- CHILD: It's coming this way.
Just hold on tight to Obaba, children.
The Ohm will come.
There's nothing we can do about it.
- MAN: Quickly!
- (ALL CLAMORING)
Don't panic. Just keep moving forward.
- Hurry!
-There's still time.
But, Mito, we're going to die anyway.
-We should die in the valley.
- No.
As long as the Princess
hasn't given up, we can't, either.
Hold the Ohm off
for as long as possible.
I'll be back with help.
Your Highness, don't do it!
It's not ready yet.
If not now, Kurotowa, then when?
Move out!
Don't shoot! Listen to me, please!
She flies like the wind!
I think she's trying to tell us something.
Maybe we shouldn't shoot her.
Anyone who interferes
with the plan is an enemy.
Besides, if we don't release
this baby Ohm in the valley soon,
we'll be the ones in trouble.
Here she comes.
Wait till she gets close, and then fire.
(GASPS)
- She's in range. Shoot her!
-l can't.
- It's Lastelle.
- Move it!
(ALL GRUNT)
(SQUEAKS)
(GASPING)
Ohm... (GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Don't be frightened.
I'm not your enemy.
(SOBBING)
I'm so sorry.
Is there any way you can forgive us?
We've treated you so badly.
No, no, ho, no, don't move.
You'll bleed to death.
Come on. Be a good boy. Hold still.
- (RUMBLING)
- (GASPS)
Oh, no! They've found us!
They're coming this way!
No, you can't go in this lake
with wounds like that!
This water's bad! It's filled with acid!
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS, CRIES IN PAIN)
(BUZZING)
Ohm?
(SOBBING)
You're so kind. It's gonna be all right.
Soon they'll be here to take you home.
Where are they going?
How can they be turning away?
Ohm, not that way!
You're headed straight for the valley!
They must be blind with rage.
If 1 can't find a way to calm them...
(CRASHING)
(LAUGHING)
Those idiots! They're drawing
the Ohm with their fire.
-We're gonna live.
- Come on. Let's get out of here.
Help me tip this over.
Wait!
No, no, don't shoot! Don't shoot!
You're gonna fly me back to the herd,
and we're gonna give
their baby back to them.
There's no reason
to try to pull a stunt like that.
It's too late. The herd won't stop.
(SHRIEKING)
You'll take us there and you'll set us
down in front of the herd.
- Now, let's get going.
- But there's no way you'll survive.
MAN: Fire! Fire! Fire!
(MURMURING)
Obaba, are we all going to die?
If that is to be our fate,
we can only wait and see.
-They don't even flinch.
-I think we should retreat, sir.
Don't be stupid, soldier.
There's nowhere to retreat to.
Hey, hold your position!
Wait! Hold it!
Stand your ground
until Her Highness returns.
Where is she? (GASPS) Your Highness!
(DEEP ROARING GROWL)
- (ALL MURMURING)
- MAN 1: The giant warrior!
MAN 2: It's him!
MAN 3: It's the warrior!
(ALL CHEERING)
Now we got ‘em!
- WOMAN: It's the giant warrior!
- MAN: The warrior!
It's falling apart. I knew it was too soon.
Incinerate them!
What are you waiting for?
Were you not designed to be the most
evil creature on the face of the Earth?
- (WHIMPERING)
- (SCREAMING)
Amazing. No wonder
the world was incinerated.
MAN: Hail to Kushana!
Hit them again!
Listen to me, warrior.
Fire on my command!
(GROWLS)
(SHOUTING)
Run!
MAN 1: It's dead!
MAN 2: No!
MAN 3: We're doomed!
MAN 3: Run!
The giant warrior died.
That's the way it should be.
The anger of the Ohm
reflects the anger of the Earth.
The Earth knows it's wrong
for us to survive
if we have to depend
on a monster like that.
- It's the Princess!
-The Princess is back!
WOMAN 1: Princess!
WOMAN 2: What is she doing?
MAN: She'll be killed!
(CHITTERING, SQUEALING)
- (ALL GASP)
- (SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Look, the color's changing.
Their rage is subsiding.
The rage. It's left the atmosphere.
We're okay.
The Ohm have stopped running.
- There's the Princess!
- (CROWD GASPING)
She's dead, Obaba. She's dead.
The Princess has quieted
the rage of the Ohm.
She gave her life to save the valley.
(CROWD SOBBING)
MAN: Look! Over there!
What is this? What are these lights?
(CHILD SINGING)
Teto.
I'm glad you're okay.
Ohm, thank you.
Thank you!
It's a miracle!
What beautiful creatures!
Who knew how wonderful
and caring the Ohm could be?
Children!
Look carefully and tell me
what these blind eyes cannot see.
The Princess is wearing a blue dress
that I've never seen before.
CHILD: It looks like she's walking
through a golden field.
(GASPS)
After 1,000 years of darkness,
he will come, clad in blue and
surrounded by fields of gold!
(SOBBING)
What's the matter?
The legend has come true!
- Look there!
- (GASPS)
The glider!
MAN: There's wind!
WOMAN: The wind has come back!