["THE JAMES BOND THEME" PLAYING]
[GUNSHOT]
Q:
I've being saying
for years, sir,
that our special equipment
is obsolete.
And now,
computer analysis reveals
an entirely new approach:
Miniaturization.
For instance, radioactive lint.
When placed
in an opponent's pockets,
the antipersonnel
and location fix seems obvious.
What we want
is a location fix on 007.
Number 10 is making ugly noises
about Operation Bedlam.
Ms. Moneypenny,
have you checked
with Communications?
Replies to our Cairo, Amsterdam
and Madrid inquiries:
all negative, sir.
The PM wants to be informed
personally when we find 007.
[ENGINE REVS LOUDLY]
[♪♪♪]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Hm.
WOMAN:
Don't.
[WOMAN GASPING]
[EXHALES HEAVILY]
Good morning.
My name's Bond.
James Bond.
Miss, uh--?
MAN:
Don't move, Mr. Bond.
Now, get up.
Put your hands
behind your head.
Move.
[WHIMPERING]
Get in.
Lie down.
[GUNSHOT]
[♪♪♪]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
[ENGINE REVS]
This never happened
to the other fellow.
[♪♪♪]
[HORN HONKS]
PORTER:
Your baggage, sir?
BOND:
In the boot.
Take care of those clubs.
Right, sir.
[CONVERSING INDISTINCTLY]
Commander Bond.
How are you, sir?
Fine.
Good to see you, Manuel.
[SPEAKS IN PORTUGUESE]
Everything seems up
to the Palacio's
usual high standards.
Yes, it's a good season.
By the way,
that red Cougar outside,
does it belong to a lady?
Yes, sir.
Contessa Teresa di Vincenzo.
Que bella.
Our best.
Fortunately,
we have had a cancellation.
Allow me.
[WOMEN LAUGHING FAINTLY OUTSIDE]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING AND CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE]
Mm.
This will do.
This will do me nicely.
MANUEL:
I'm sure we can look after
your special needs.
BOND:
I'm sure you can.
Thank you.
[ROULETTE WHEEL SPINNING]
[BALL FALLS IN SLOT]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Huit.
À la pointe.
Deux mille à la banque.
Give la banque.
Banco.
Les jeux sont faits, monsieur.
Change.
Carte.
Neuf. À la banque.
Thank you.
Quatre mille à la banque.
Give la banque.
WOMAN: Avec.
MAN 1: Pointe gagnée.
Suivi.
Carte.
MAN 1:
Quatre.
[PEOPLE GASP]
Neuf.
Vingt mille.
La banque, vingt mille.
Give la banque.
Vingt mille à la banque.
MAN 2:
La banque
a vingt mille.
Vingt mille,
la banque.
MAN 3:
Twenty thousand francs.
MAN 2:
La banque a vingt mille.
Too rich for my blood.
MAN 2:
Vingt mille, la banque.
Banque, vingt mille.
WOMAN:
Banco.
MAN 1:
Banco debout.
Carte.
MAN 1:
Neuf.
[CROWD GROANS]
La banque a gagné.
Madame?
[WHISPERS]
I don't have the money.
Je regrette, madame,
mais c'est impossible.
Mm. I regret too,
but I don't have any money.
[WHISPERS]
Dame can't pay up.
S'il vous plaît, madame,
venez avec moi.
S'il vous plaît,
madame...
Forgive me.
My mind was elsewhere.
Madame has forgotten we agreed
to be partners this evening.
Please continue.
MAN 2:
Merci.
Quarante mille
à la banque.
That's a bit of luck,
being bailed out like that
at the last minute.
Waiter.
Dom Perignon, '57.
Sir.
Why do you persist
in rescuing me, Mr. Bond?
It's becoming a habit,
Contessa Teresa.
Teresa was a saint.
I'm known as Tracy.
Tracy, next time play it safe
and stand on five.
People who want to stay alive
play it safe.
Please stay alive,
at least for tonight.
Come later.
I hope it'll be worth it,
partner.
Monsieur?
Send it to suite 423
with caviar for two.
Oui, monsieur.
Tracy?
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[GROANING]
Gate-crasher.
I'll leave you to tidy up.
Mm. Royal beluga,
north of the Caspian.
[SIGHS]
You're full of surprises,
contessa.
So are you, Mr. Bond.
Do you always arm yourself
for a rendezvous?
Occasionally.
I seem to be accident-prone.
I'll take that,
if you don't mind.
You're very sure of yourself,
aren't you?
Suppose I were to kill you
for a thrill?
I can think of something
more sociable to do.
Stop playing games.
Who was that man in your room?
You're hurting me.
I thought that was the idea
tonight.
Now, who was he?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I can be a lot more persuasive,
contessa.
I'm sure you can.
Whatever else I may be,
I'm not a liar.
[♪♪♪]
Get dressed.
[GUN CLICKS]
BOND:
You know, you're the most
extraordinary girl.
I'm not interested in
your opinion of me, Mr. Bond.
I'm here for a business
transaction.
Really?
Isn't Le Bleu
a bit heady for that?
So you know your perfumes.
What else do you know?
A little about women.
Think about me
as a woman
you've just bought.
Who needs to buy?
Look, you don't owe me a thing.
I think you're in some sort
of trouble.
Would you like to talk about it?
No, Mr. Bond.
The only thing you need know
about me is that I pay my debts.
Twenty thousand francs
is a lot of money.
Mm.
[WOMAN SQUEALS, LAUGHS]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
WOMAN:
Good morning, Commander Bond.
Good morning.
Café complet for two
with fresh orange juice.
Yes, sir.
Connect me with suite 423,
please.
The Contessa di Vincenzo
has left the hotel, sir.
Checked out?
A few minutes ago.
Thank you.
Paid in full, as well.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Thank you.
Mr. Bond?
Yes.
You've lost something.
Really?
[♪♪♪]
We'll give it to you
outside.
BOND:
Why not? Perhaps we can
make up a foursome.
You've thought of everything.
What a lovely surprise,
our meeting again so soon.
[GRUNTS]
BOND:
Thank you.
And where's the party
this time?
You have an appointment.
Business or pleasure?
Mystery tour, eh?
I think we'd all enjoy it
more without that.
[GRUNTS]
[HORN HONKS]
[WHISTLING]
[GRUNTING]
[LOCK CLICKS]
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Basta!
[POUNDING ON DOOR STOPS]
Do not kill me, Mr. Bond.
At least, not until
we've had a drink.
Then, if you wish,
I'll give you another chance.
I'm Draco,
of Draco Construction.
Mm-hm.
But today is the 13th,
commander.
I'm superstitious.
A martini for our guest, Olympe.
OLYMPE:
A pleasure.
Shaken, not stirred.
Of course.
Campari for me.
Mm-hm.
My apologies for the way
you were brought here today.
Please sit down.
I was not sure you would
accept a formal invitation.
There's always something formal
about the point of a pistol.
[CHUCKLES]
Thank you, chéri.
Olympe, we will finish
our struggle later.
As you wish.
She also plays a very good
game of chess.
Salute.
Cheers.
You usually drink
Corsican brandy.
Ah. What else do you know
about me?
Marc Ange Draco:
Head of the Union Corse.
One of the biggest
crime syndicates in Europe.
The biggest.
Not quite.
An organization known as SPECTRE
operates worldwide.
However, your legitimate
business fronts
are somewhat more extensive.
Construction,
electrical supplies,
numerous agricultural holdings.
Your dossier on me...
is not entirely complete.
I am also Teresa's father.
Tracy.
Yes, Tracy.
Tracy. My only child.
Her mother was an English girl.
A romantic
who had come to Corsica
to look for bandits.
Rather like those women
who ventured into the desert
looking for sheiks.
She found me in the mountains
hiding from the police
at the time.
I came to love this girl.
We married.
The result: Teresa.
Twelve years later,
my wife died.
I sent Teresa to Switzerland...
No, thanks,
I prefer my own.
...to finish her education.
Unfortunately, I didn't
give her a proper home.
She was without supervision.
So she joined a fast
international set.
One scandal after another.
When I disapproved,
cut off her allowance...
...she committed some greater
folly to spite me.
Yet, behind her bravado,
something was eating away
at her soul.
This can happen
to men and women.
They burn the heart
out of themselves
by living too greedily,
and suddenly...
...all is finished.
Why are you telling me this?
Without telling me,
she married
an Italian count,
who killed himself
in a Maserati with one
of his mistresses.
I gave her too much,
and it brought her nothing.
Now, why I tell you all this.
I've been informed of everything
you've done for my daughter.
Everything?
Don't worry.
Don't worry about that.
What you did,
the way you behaved,
might be the beginning
of some kind of therapy.
She needs help.
Your help.
I find her fascinating,
but she needs a psychiatrist,
not me.
What she needs is a man
to dominate her!
To make love to her enough
to make her love him.
A man like you.
You overestimate me,
Draco.
She's very attractive,
but what you ask is not for me.
Mm.
Listen to me.
On the day you marry her,
I'll give you a personal dowry
of one million pounds in gold.
That's quite an inducement.
But I don't need
a million pounds.
Stupido!
And I have a bachelor's
taste for freedom.
Please, just see her some more.
Who knows what will come of it?
I'm sorry, Draco,
but in my profession, I can't--
What?
You have connections
not open to me.
Where is Ernst Stavro Blofeld?
Blofeld?
[CHUCKLES]
Some of my men have recently
defected to him.
I don't know where he is.
Can you find out?
If I could, I wouldn't tell
Her Majesty's Secret Service.
But I might tell
my future son-in-law.
Go on.
Next week is my birthday.
For that,
Teresa always comes back to me.
You understand?
Let's say
I'll sleep on the idea.
You do that.
James, where have you been?
Much too far from you, darling.
Oh, same old James.
Ooh!
Only more so.
Heartless brute,
letting me pine away
without even a postcard.
Pine no more.
[WHISPERS]
Cocktails at my place,
8-ish, just the two of us.
Oh, I'd adore that,
if only I could trust myself.
Same old Moneypenny,
Britain's last line of defense.
[CHUCKLING]
You'd better go in.
He's running
a very tight ship today.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I'm relieving you from
Operation Bedlam, 007.
But, sir, Blofeld's
something of a must with me.
You've had two years
to run him down.
Does this mean you've
lost confidence in me?
I am well aware
of your talents, 007,
but license to kill is useless
unless one can set up
the target.
I'll find you a more
suitable assignment.
Sir, under the circum--
That's all.
[♪♪♪]
That was a quick conference.
How do you expect a girl
to keep herself alluring?
Take a memo, please,
Moneypenny.
Ready, James.
Sir,
I have the honor to request
you will accept my resignation,
effective forthwith.
Resignation from what?
Her Majesty's Secret Service.
And kindly present it
to that monument in there.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR SLAMS]
♪ Underneath the mango tree ♪
♪ Me honey and me
Can watch for the moon ♪
[THEME FROM "FROM RUSSIA
WITH LOVE" PLAYING]
[THEME FROM "THUNDERBALL"
PLAYING]
Sorry, ma'am.
[PHONE BUZZES]
007--
James Bond, here.
He wants you, James.
Request granted.
Not even "with regret."
What did you expect,
a knighthood?
Why don't you read it.
"Two weeks leave."
Well, you didn't really
want to resign, did you?
Moneypenny,
what would I do without you?
My problem is that you
never do anything with me.
It's a date.
The moment I get back.
Where are you off to?
Just someplace to laze about.
Beachcombing.
[DOOR SHUTS]
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
M:
What would I do without you,
Ms. Moneypenny? Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[CHILDREN SINGING]
Bonjour, Miguel.
[BULL MOOING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[MOOING]
WOMAN: Teresa.
TRACY: Good morning.
WOMAN:
It's been so long
since we've seen you.
[BULL ROARING]
Yes, very well.
There's Tracy.
Huh?
Tracy.
Where is she?
Ah, there she is.
Teresa!
Happy birthday, Papa.
You make it so by being here.
You look marvelous.
There's someone
I want you to meet. Come on.
Salut, Olympe,
how are you?
It's good to have you back.
You look wonderful.
Thanks.
WOMAN 2: Contessa.
Bonjour.
Mr. Bond, may I introduce
my daughter, Teresa?
Contessa.
Mr. Bond and I have already met.
But each time
is a renewed pleasure.
Madame always makes one
feel so welcome.
She likes you.
I can see it.
You must give me the name
of your oculist.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Ho! Ho!
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
Olympe, I didn't know
Mr. Bond knew Papa.
I think
there are many things
about Mr. Bond
one does not know.
It would be interesting
to attend night school,
perhaps.
Hyah!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Papa is up to something.
I'm sure of it.
Your father loves you
very much, Tracy.
Whatever he may arrange,
I know it's for your happiness.
What has
Papa arranged?
[SHOUTING]
[GRUNTS]
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Ah, Mr. Bond!
Thank you.
Many happy returns.
The best years
are still to come,
let's hope.
Oh, allow me.
What are you doing here?
Yes, wasn't it kind
of your father to invite me?
Mr. Bond and I are discussing
a business deal, Teresa.
Really?
Mm-hm.
No woman would waste
this excellent champagne
discussing a business deal.
Unless of course,
she happened to be part
of the arrangement.
Olympe, what have you said?
Don't blame Olympe, Papa.
I'm not your daughter
for nothing.
Hmm, I detect a certain
family resemblance.
I suggest you revise the terms
of your contract, Mr. Bond.
You'll find your liability
far too expensive.
Ah, now, there you're mistaken.
Papa.
Yes?
Mr. Bond wants
some information.
I wonder
what you're talking about.
You always taught me
that a good host
supplies his guests' needs.
Uh-huh.
And without obligation.
And then?
I'm not sure "obligation"
is quite the right word.
Tell him, Papa.
Tell him what
he wants to know.
Now!
Please. Please, Teresa.
There's only a possibility.
Nothing definite.
Tell him, Papa...
or you'll never see me again.
All right.
There may be a connection
between that man Blofeld
and a lawyer with offices
in Bern, Switzerland...
...named Gumbold.
Gumbold.
Bern, Switzerland.
Yes, Gumbold.
So...
Now Mr. Bond need have
no further interest in me.
Another mistake.
She always was
a headstrong child.
I'm sorry, uh--
Where has he gone?
[SHOUTING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Tracy!
Tracy.
I was always taught that
mistakes should be remedied.
Especially between friends.
[LOUIS ARMSTRONG'S "WE HAVE ALL
THE TIME IN THE WORLD" PLAYING]
Or lovers.
♪ We have all ♪
♪ The time ♪
♪ In the world ♪
♪ Time enough for life
To unfold ♪
♪ All the precious things
Love has in store ♪
♪ We have all ♪
♪ The love ♪
♪ In the world ♪
♪ If that's all we have ♪
♪ You will find ♪
♪ We need nothing more ♪
♪ Every step of the way ♪
♪ Will find us ♪
♪ With the cares of the world ♪
♪ Far behind us ♪
♪ We have all... ♪
♪ The time in the world ♪
♪ Just for love ♪
♪ Nothing more
Nothing less ♪
♪ Only love ♪
[♪♪♪]
I'll get cracking
on this appointment,
then catch up with you.
TRACY:
The story of our life,
James?
Just keep my martini cool.
Ha-ha.
[LOCK TURNS]
[♪♪♪]
I will be back in an hour.
Bon appétit,
monsieur.
[SPEAKS
IN GERMAN]
[TURNS LOCK]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[METAL CLANGING,
MOTORS WHIRRING]
[HORNS HONKING]
Such things should be left
to a girl's father,
who knows what
is best for her.
Papa.
But what could be better
than being in love?
Mr. Bond is--
Is in love with you?
That may come too...
someday.
Life's too short
for "someday," Teresa.
Tomorrow--
Tomorrow I will speak to him
alone, man-to-man.
No, Papa.
Why not?
No talk.
Whatever happens,
there'll be no regrets.
Please.
Mm.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
[PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[TURNS LOCK]
[PEOPLE CONVERSING
IN GERMAN]
[RINGS DOORBELL]
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Hammond.
Is the admiral in?
Certainly, sir.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hmm?
Excuse me, sir.
Commander Bond to see you.
Right. Show him in.
Aye, aye, sir.
If you please, sir.
Thank you.
Unusually small for
a Nymphalis polychloros.
I wasn't aware that your
expertise included lepidoptery.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were on leave.
Genealogy, sir.
Fascinating subject.
Came across a letter
from Gebrüder Gumbold,
solicitors in Switzerland,
to a certain Count
Balthazar de Bleuchamp.
De Bleuchamp?
French form of Blofeld.
You've been relieved from
Operation Bedlam, 007,
do you remember?
I assumed you'd
reassign me, sir.
This is a photostat copy
of a letter
addressed to our College of
Arms in the city of London...
with the request that
they undertake to establish
de Bleuchamp's claim
to the title.
And Sir Hilary Bray--
He's the sable basilisk
of the college.
--has replied to Gumbold,
suggesting that he should meet
de Bleuchamp in person.
Now, I've already taken
the liberty, sir,
of working
with the college on this,
using an examination of my own
family tree as cover.
I've also been reading up
on the technical side
of heraldry...
Uh, Sir Hilary Bray, please.
Commander Bond.
Ah, yes, sir.
BOND:
...so that, should he consent
to a meeting,
I could act as a representative
of the college.
BRAY:
Come.
Ah, good afternoon.
Good afternoon,
Sir Hilary.
Have a look at this.
Now, let me take your coat.
Arms of Sir Thomas Bond,
Baronet of Peckham,
died 1734.
Argent on a chevron sable.
Three bezants.
Good motto, eh?
"The World is Not Enough."
Phidian's doing
a splendid job.
Thank you,
Mr. Sable Basilisk.
We've traced your line
to a Sir Otho le Bon,
who held the manor
of Wickhamsbreux
by a knight's fee
from the Earl of Thanet,
1387.
We're in luck.
Gumbold's telephoned
from Bern
to say that his client has
consented to see me.
You mean me.
Yes, you.
But, Commander Bond,
I'm only able to countenance
this deception
on your assurance
that the matter
is of national
importance.
I haven't exaggerated.
My department appreciates
your help very much.
During the deception period,
I've arranged
to lose myself
amongst the churches
of Brittany.
I want to do some
brass rubbings there, anyway.
Where do I go
for this meeting?
Well, they're being
a bit canny about that.
They want a description
of myself.
Tactfully adjusted
to favor me.
Yes.
They will send the time
and place
from where I am to be, um...
"collected," as they put it.
It's not our sort of thing,
but under the circumstances--
Sounds as if
they're suspicious.
No, no, no.
Not suspicious.
Just, uh, discreet.
There was no objection
to my fee of 1000 guineas.
Could their claim
be genuine?
It's hard to say
at this point.
Our methods are very exacting.
We never like to speak
until we're absolutely certain
there could be no possibility
of error on our side
or forgery on anybody else's.
I hope I can live up to
your high standards.
Oh, one helpful physical point
might be that
the real de Bleuchamps
are without earlobes.
It's, uh, not the sort of thing
that we rely on, of course,
uh, but it could help.
No earlobes.
You might try inviting him
to Augsburg.
The de Bleuchamps have been
coming from there
for generations.
Yes, if he is our man,
I'd like to get him away
from Switzerland.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON PA]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[IN GERMAN ACCENT]
Sir Hilary Bray, baronet?
The same, dear lady.
I am Fraülein Irma Bunt,
personal secretary to the count.
How do you do?
Have you had a good journey?
No, quite intolerable.
I'm not a good traveler,
I'm afraid.
I'm sorry.
Grunther will
take your luggage.
No, I can manage.
[IN GERMAN ACCENT]
I take it.
You know Switzerland,
Sir Hilary?
I'm afraid not,
Fraülein--?
Bunt.
Interesting name
for a genealogist.
Are you from
a naval family?
Naval?
It's a nautical term,
you see,
meaning the baggy or
swollen parts of a sail.
Nothing personal,
of course.
Interesting.
You speak German?
I'm afraid not.
French, perhaps?
A little.
Where are we off to?
You will not be disappointed.
Please?
Like the bugs in a rug, yes?
You are comfortable?
Yes, indeed, fraülein.
Your kindness is
quite overwhelming.
Good.
[SLEIGH BELLS RINGING]
DRIVER:
Hup. Hup.
[DRIVER SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
So we are halfway.
Now we will have
a little flight.
I've never been in one
of these things before.
And first you must
your pipe knock off.
"Knock out," you mean.
I hope.
Mind your head,
Sir Hilary.
Please fasten
your safety belt.
[HELICOPTER ENGINE STARTING]
Now up into the Alps.
[♪♪♪]
That is avalanche damage.
You enjoy the skiing,
or the bobsled, perhaps?
I'm not a sporting man,
fraülein.
Even when I'm at my best.
Do you feel
the airsickness?
Up to there
is for the public,
and from here upwards
it is strictly private.
No one, no one at all
may come through without
permission from the count.
There is the Bleuchamp Institute
for Allergy Research.
What kind of allergies?
All of them.
Like the hay fever,
or the sickness caused
by the oysters,
or inability to eat meat.
The count is a great specialist
in this field.
I'll be glad to get my feet
on the ground.
Not ground. Ice.
[♪♪♪]
Fraülein, I should warn you,
guns make me very nervous.
They are to keep away the spies
from the chemical companies.
Many times already
they have tried
to steal our discoveries.
Yes, we live in a world
of avarice and deceit.
Here at least
is no avarice.
Really?
The Bleuchamp Institute
is not for profit, Sir Hilary.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE WARBLING]
The count does his work
for the sake of mankind.
I'm very happy
to hear it.
He wants to leave his mark
on the entire world.
Characteristic
ambition.
Characteristic?
Of a true
humanitarian.
Oh.
Formerly it was
a sports club,
open to the public.
Now it belongs to
the count,
who has given it
to scientific research.
Joseph, Sir Hilary Bray
will take number four.
I will show you there
after Grunther has taken you
for medical examination.
I'm quite all right now.
You are our honored guest,
Sir Hilary.
Thank you.
And after your experience
in the helicopter...
we must make sure that
you are entirely well again.
Grunther, take Sir Hilary
to Dr. Von Sant.
GRUNTHER:
Ja, fraülein.
Director, bitte.
[PHONE RINGS]
Yes?
[BUNT SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Provide him with
the usual comforts.
Ja.
You have 10 minutes.
And then take them
to number four.
Ja.
If you wish anything
for your comfort,
you must ring this...
[BEEPS]
...and the attendant will come.
Very considerate.
Thank you.
You must also
ring for him
to open the door
when you wish to leave.
Rather complicated
arrangement.
To stop patients
leaving the rooms
and disturbing each other
when they should be resting.
The count believes very strongly
in undisturbed rest.
Prudent fellow.
When can I see him?
We have a great deal to discuss.
He will send for you,
Sir Hilary, when he's ready.
Meanwhile, I should very much
like for you to join me
in the Alpine Room
before dinner.
Alpine Room?
Yes. Grunther
will come for you.
Shall we say 7:00?
Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING
IN DISTANCE]
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
[BELL CHIMES]
Fraülein Bunt
will receive you.
[WOMEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪♪♪]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Ah, Sir Hilary, please,
come to meet our patients.
Ladies, this is
Sir Hilary Bray, baronet.
How do you do?
He's a famous genealogist.
You will have a drink, yes?
Please,
come and sit down.
How do you do?
Thank you.
What is a baronet?
It's a kind of inferior
sort of baron.
Oh, how disappointing.
BOND:
Well, uh--
Oh, I don't mean
you're inferior.
I mean the title is.
What's a gyn--? Genealogist?
What is that?
Palmy word for an old
people's doctor.
Ah, so he's here to cure
Fraülein Bunt?
Watch yourself. She's got ears
like an elephant.
What will you drink,
sir?
Malt whiskey
and branch water, please.
Hey, I'm sorry I was so rude
about what a baronet is.
You gave a very accurate
description.
[GIGGLES]
ATTENDANT:
Sir.
Thank you.
I say, it's a treat,
having a man here for once.
Uh, you mean
there aren't any others?
Only the staff, and you can't
really count them.
We do not discuss
our affairs of the clinic.
Yes, but what is a genealogist?
Will nobody tell me?
It would give me
great pleasure.
Well?
Genealogy is all about
ancestors and families.
I mean, it could easily be
that any one of you here
is related
to a royal house...
if only we could go back
far enough to find out.
Now, if you will tell me
your names--
We do not use surnames here.
It is a rule of the clinic.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I didn't know that.
Come, it's time
for dinner.
Our schedule is rather strict.
So is our diet.
Please, Hilary,
if you would sit there
between Helen and Ruby.
I'm afraid I've never had much
to do with young ladies.
I have ordered you
a steak Piz Gloria.
I hope you enjoy it.
Thank you.
I'm sure I will.
WOMAN:
Can I have some ice water?
Thank you so much.
WOMAN 2:
Oh, this is good.
HELEN:
Are you here
for Christmas, Hilary?
Uh, well, I might be, if--
Oh, good, then we can
have a party before we go.
BOND:
That sort of thing
is not quite in my line.
Delicious!
I used to hate chicken.
Used to make me break out,
it was all over.
You'd be surprised where.
Mm! Potatoes did it to me.
Now I adore them.
No medical histories,
please.
Now, girls, I'm sure Sir Hilary
would like to tell us
about the College of Arms
in London.
RUBY:
Go on, Sir Hilary.
Please tell us.
If you'd really enjoy that.
RUBY:
Please. Yes!
WOMAN 2:
We promise to listen.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
WOMAN 1:
Come on, tell us all about it.
The Heralds' College,
or College of Arms,
consists of 13 members
of the royal household
appointed by the sovereign
to superintend
armorial, genealogical,
ceremonial and other matters.
WOMEN:
Mm-hm?
The 13 members are divided
into three categories:
kings, heralds and pursuivants.
Their titles and offices
are of great antiquity.
How compelling.
When I tell you that the first
Clarenceux King of Arms
was created in 1334...
and the first
Somerset Herald in 1448.
Now, when we authorize
a coat of arms
it can include all sorts
of funny things.
Crescent moons, portcullises,
beasts couchant are rampant,
bars, bezants--
Please, what is "bezant"?
Gold balls.
I brought a book
on the subject.
There's a picture of my own
coat of arms, actually.
Which includes four of them...
[WOMEN GASP]
...if you'd care to see them.
I'd love to. I'm in room--
No, no.
He will give the book to me.
I will pass it
to everyone in turn.
It is fairer
like that, yes?
Of course.
If you think so, fraülein.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
Is anything the matter,
Sir Hilary?
Just a slight stiffness
coming on...in the shoulder.
Due to the altitude,
no doubt.
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
The count will see you now.
Grunther will take you.
Thank you.
Please excuse me, ladies.
May all your allergies
be swiftly cured.
WOMAN:
What a nice man.
WOMAN 3:
Sweet.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
Of course,
I know what he's allergic to.
Bezants.
[♪♪♪]
[BELL CHIMES]
[FOOTSTEPS ECHOING]
[WATER DRIPPING]
[BUZZING, CRACKLING]
Antisepsis.
[ELECTRONIC BEEPING]
Please wait here.
[HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
Good evening, Sir Hilary.
Good evening.
Balthazar, Count de Bleuchamp.
If you'll forgive me,
that's what I'm here
to find out.
To confirm, Sir Hilary.
There can be no doubt
of the truth.
Please, sit down.
If there were no doubt,
I'm sure the College of Arms
would not have sent me.
Well, since you are here,
I'll make everything
very plain to you.
To begin with,
I was born without earlobes.
A well-known congenital
distinction
of Bleuchamp ancestry
like the Hapsburg lip
or the hawk nose of the Medicis.
Granted, but the fact that
you're of de Bleuchamp ancestry
doesn't necessarily make you
the reigning count.
I feel it in my blood
and in my bones.
I'm afraid the College of Arms
will require
more concrete proofs.
And it shall have them.
I have assembled
all the relevant documents:
Title deeds, certificates
of birth and death.
They'll be sent to your room
for authentication.
You've only to ask Fraülein Bunt
for anything you require.
Are you
quite comfortable here?
Yes, thank you,
but puzzled by your clinic.
Hm. Well, the methods
of the great pioneers
have often puzzled
conventional minds.
I've devised a cure
for allergies
which depends on holding
an unusual
and rather delicate
psychological balance.
So, you see, I must impose
rather special
conditions on my patients.
And, um...
your laboratories?
The cure is not entirely
psychological, Sir Hilary.
There are special vaccines
to be prepared.
Vaccines which must be modified
to suit each individual case.
So, you see,
I'm a very busy man
and I might not be able
to spare you
as much of my time
as I might wish.
If you wish to be confirmed
as Count de Bleuchamp,
you must give me
some of your time.
I must have details
of your living relatives,
also your parents
and grandparents.
Well, the documents
that you will see--
Can answer many questions,
but not all.
Oh, one more thing.
It would be helpful
if you could accompany me
on a visit
to Augsburg.
Augsburg?
The ancestral home
of the de Bleuchamps family.
There are notable Bleuchamps
tombs in the cathedral
and some important records
in the city archives.
If you were there to assist
with your personal knowledge--
That may not be convenient
for some time.
But I'm determined that
my title shall be recognized.
In any event, you may proceed
with your preliminary research.
I shall be happy
to start straightaway.
Thank you,
Herr Grunther.
[♪♪♪]
[BUNT SPEAKING IN GERMAN
OUTSIDE]
[BUNT AND MAN CONVERSING
IN GERMAN]
[♪♪♪]
[CLICKS]
Sir Hilary!
Shh!
[WHISPERING]
I brought you the book.
The illustrated book?
No, don't turn it on.
I want to see the pictures.
But you're a picture
yourself,
and twice as lovely
in the firelight.
You are funny,
pretending not to like girls.
Well, I don't, usually.
But you're not usual.
That lipstick
was an inspiration.
So are you.
Oh, Sir Hilary.
Call me..."Hilly."
Hilly.
What's your name?
Ruby Bartlett,
from Lancashire.
Morecambe Bay, actually.
How did you get here?
Do we have
to talk about that now?
[RUBY GIGGLES]
It's true!
How did you get here?
I had this awful allergy
about chickens.
My family's
got a chicken farm
and every time
I had to do something on it,
I nearly died.
A specialist said there was
this wonderful Swiss clinic
where they cured you, free,
because they were researching
at the same time.
Go on.
No, about the clinic,
I mean.
Oh.
Well, the specialist had me
meet Fraülein Bunt in London,
and she said I had
a very interesting case.
How right she was.
Oh, Hilly.
[HORN BLARES]
Oh, bother!
No, Hilly!
It's part of the cure.
Cassette number seven.
Number eight.
BLOFELD [OVER SPEAKER]:
Do you remember
when you first came here,
how you hated chickens?
How you were sick
when you even saw one?
But all that is over now.
For I have shown you
how foolish it was,
and your cure is nearly done.
I have taught you
to love chickens.
To love their flesh,
their voice.
Yes, your cure is nearly done.
And soon you will go home--
Ruby?
--to look after the chickens--
Ruby, wake up!
--which you love so much.
You do love me just a little,
don't you, Hilly?
One more thing
before you go.
Ruby.
I must teach you
how to give them special care.
I will tell you what to do.
Ruby, wake up.
I will tell you when.
I will tell you how.
And after you've done
what I teach you,
you will forget it forever.
Forever.
[CLICKS]
Hilly, you old devil.
[♪♪♪]
It is me, yes?
Quite undeniably, yes.
BOND:
How did you get out?
With a fingernail file.
It's so easy.
I wouldn't know.
I come to see the book,
the pictures, yes?
Oh, jolly good idea.
Now, where did I put it?
Hm, I had it
a few moments ago.
Perhaps if we turn on
the light?
No.
You're a picture yourself.
And twice as lovely
in the firelight.
But, Sir Hilary...
Hilly.
But I think you do not
like girls, Hilly.
Usually, I don't.
But you're not usual.
Coming here like this
was an inspiration.
So are you.
[MOANS]
You'll need to be.
What you say?
I said, a miracle,
our meeting like this.
I don't even know
your name.
I tell you
all about myself later.
In the morning.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Hey.
What about a lift
to the top?
It is not permitted.
All is private.
But surely there's a restaurant,
a sports club up there.
I've seen them
advertised.
It's all closed now.
Since when?
I've seen them advertised,
I tell you.
You are mistaken, sir.
For many weeks,
they are finished.
All right, but I'd still
like to get to the top.
From here up,
it's forbidden!
Private! Closed!
All right.
[GRUNTS]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
It's my turn now.
[ALL LAUGH]
Sir Hilary!
Good morning.
Good morning, Sir Hilary.
Your stiffness of last night
it is all gone?
For the time being,
I think.
Then come and do curling
with us, Sir Hilary.
Won't that be frightfully
energetic?
No.
We'll show you.
Perhaps you'd teach me.
[WOMEN CLAMORING]
Have a go.
We expect great things
of you.
We're leaving very soon, Hilly.
I must see you.
Eight o'clock tonight.
[SQUAWKING]
And the man was alone?
Ah, good morning, ladies.
Good morning!
Good morning, Sir Hilary,
and how's your research?
Riveting.
And very promising too.
MAN:
I've never heard anything
so ridiculous in all my life!
Since when is climbing
a mountain a criminal offence?
Excuse me.
Piz Gloria, sir,
is private property.
The whole Alp?
Ridiculous!
There are many signs,
and my servant warned you.
Your throw,
I think it is.
Oh, no, I had my throw.
Made a mess of it,
I'm afraid.
That didn't count.
You can throw again.
Oh, yes, go on.
Very civil of you,
fraülein.
--doesn't entitle these goons
to start shooting at me.
Who the hell are you anyway?
I am the director
of this institute.
You'll be sent down
by cable car
and you will refrain
from troubling us again!
What about my belongings?
BLOFELD:
They will be sent later.
But they're mine,
damn it!
We have certain rules
which must be observed.
The authorities
will hear about this!
Good day, sir.
Director-- Or count, as I think
I can now safely say.
Yes.
I thought I'd take
the afternoon off,
so if you're sending
the cable car down--
But you've already
had the morning off, Sir Hilary.
Must have a bit
of fresh air.
Those ancestors
of yours are hard work.
And the College of Arms
is being very well paid.
Well, if you put it
like that--
I do put it like that.
Let me show you
what I've achieved,
then we can plan
this trip to Augsburg
and finish it all off.
Not over Christmas.
The archives will be closed,
will they not?
Come, girls.
It's time for our massage.
Girls, that is enough
curling for today.
[WOMEN GROANING]
I must see you tonight.
Nine o'clock?
Ten? Well, back to work.
You've no idea
how it's piling up.
[♪♪♪]
Ruby. It's me, Hilly.
Hilly's so sad
that Ruby's leaving.
[RUBY GIGGLES]
Has that old cow told you--?
Fancy meeting you here,
fraülein!
Merry Christmas, 007.
I'm Sir Hilary Bray.
[CHUCKLING]
No, no, Mr. Bond.
Respectable baronets
from the College of Heralds
do not seduce
female patients in clinics.
On the other hand,
they do get their
professional details right.
The Bleuchamp tombs
are not in the
Augsburg Cathedral, as you said,
but in the Saint Anna Kirche.
Sir Hilary Bray would've known.
A small slip.
Takes more than a few props
to turn 007 into a herald.
Take more than cutting off
your earlobes, Blofeld,
to turn you into a count.
I may yet surprise you,
but I'm afraid that you have
no surprises left for me.
I know all about your mission,
Mr. Bond.
Your colleague.
Such a keen climber,
such a brilliant
conversationalist...
before he left us.
You realize
he reported where I am.
I doubt that.
In any case, no one's going
to come to your rescue.
In a few hours,
the United Nations
will receive
my yuletide greetings:
The information that I now
possess the scientific means
to control...or to destroy
the economy of the whole world.
People will have more important
things to think about than you.
If they believe your threat.
[BLOFELD LAUGHS]
Oh, they will.
In any case,
I have prepared a demonstration.
Remember that
disagreeable outbreak
of foot-and-mouth disease
in England last summer?
Well, I shall instruct them,
in very convincing terms,
exactly how I arranged that.
And my capacity
has improved since.
Allergy vaccines?
Bacteria.
BOND:
Bacteriological warfare.
With a difference.
Our great breakthrough
since last summer
has been the confection
of a certain
Virus Omega.
Infertility.
Total infertility
in plants and animals.
Not just disease in a few herds,
Mr. Bond,
or the loss of a single crop,
but the destruction
of a whole strain, forever,
throughout an entire continent.
If my demands are not met,
I shall proceed with
the systematic extinction
of whole species of cereals
and livestock
all over the world.
Including, I suppose,
the human race?
I don't think, do you, Mr. Bond,
the United Nations
will let it come to that.
Not after their scientists
analyze a small sample
of Virus Omega
they have received.
Epidemics of sterility.
Nothing is born.
No seed even begins to sprout.
They'll find an antidote.
Of course!
If I give them enough time.
They'll have time.
Once they're warned,
you'll have a problem
dispensing the stuff.
That problem
has already been solved.
I have been training
my own special
"Angels of Death."
Those girls.
Those girls,
and many others like them.
But exactly how?
That will remain my secret.
And how many hundred millions
do you want for your services
this time, Blofeld?
This time? This time,
the price is of another kind.
You'll be more amused
when you know what.
In the meanwhile,
I will keep you here
as my guest.
You'll be very useful in helping
to convince the authorities
that I mean what I say...
and I'll do what I claim.
Come, let me show you
to your new quarters.
You're likely to be with us
for some time, Mr. Bond.
So first...
a little therapy to soothe
your restless nature.
Oh, poor fellow.
He was restless too.
You perverse British,
how you love your exercise.
Every year,
dozens of amateur climbers--
They wind up
in the same predicament.
A kind of waxworks show
for morbid tourists.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Dear, dear me.
[♪♪♪]
Now, now.
Now, now, Mr. Bond.
You must learn
to be absolutely calm
before we can accept you
back into polite society.
[METAL CLANKS]
[DISTANT CLANKING]
Presents!
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
Going-away presents
from the count himself,
in appreciation.
I want
to open mine now!
No. It is more fun
to open them all together, yes?
Please sit down.
We will wait for the others.
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
Look, look, look!
Eggnog on Christmas Eve.
Just like home!
It is a treat
for the going-away party.
Your very good health,
my dears.
WOMEN:
Cheers! Cheers!
It has been so nice to cure you.
[RIPS]
It has something special in it
for the Holy Night celebration.
[♪♪♪]
BLOFELD [OVER SPEAKER]:
And now you're going
on a journey.
A journey home.
But first you must rest
for awhile.
Rest.
[♪♪♪]
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
[MEN SPEAKING
IN GERMAN]
BLOFELD [ON SPEAKER]:
I will tell you when,
and I will tell you how,
but it must be our secret.
Yours and mine.
Our secret.
And after you've done
what I teach you,
will you forget it...
forever?
Forever.
And now you may
open your eyes again.
Each of you has been given
a present,
such a prettily wrapped
present.
Now is the time to open them.
Open them.
You see, they're beautiful,
and you're longing to know
what is inside.
You may use anything
but the atomizer...
which you must never touch--
Never.
--until I tell you how
and where to use it.
Open the compact.
Adjust the volume control.
BLOFELD [FROM COMPACT]:
Every night at exactly 12:00,
you must be alone
so that you can switch on
that receiver
and listen for my voice.
I'll tell you what to do,
I will tell you when,
and I will tell you how.
After you've heard what I say
push the mirror back
to conceal the receiver again.
Push it back now
and close the case.
[ON SPEAKER]
Now rest again. Rest.
Rest.
In a few minutes,
you will wake up.
You will not remember
what I just told you
until you return home.
[ELEVATOR BELL CHIMES]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN GERMAN]
[ELEVATOR BELL CHIMES]
[♪♪♪]
Hilfe!
[ELEVATOR BELL CHIMES]
[CHATTERING]
WOMAN 1:
What a lovely present.
WOMAN 2:
I don't feel too good.
Please, girls,
we are in a hurry.
[WHISPERS]
Merry Christmas.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
Maybe you should've
been gift-wrapped.
[♪♪♪]
[SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
[PHONE RINGS]
[GUARD SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
[CAT GROWLS]
[SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
Flare.
GUARD:
He's making for the village.
We'll head him off
at the precipice.
[♪♪♪]
Idiot.
[FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING
IN VILLAGE]
Aaaggh!
Hilfe!
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
[GURGLING]
Aaagh!
[FESTIVE MUSIC CONTINUES
PLAYING]
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN
ON SPEAKER]
Goodbye, girls.
Merry Christmas.
And a happy New Year.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
WOMAN 1:
Auf Wiedersehen.
WOMAN 2:
Goodbye!
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[CONTINUES HONKING]
Right in there. Quick!
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
[BELLS RING]
[GRUNTS]
Bye.
[FESTIVE MUSIC CONTINUES
PLAYING]
[SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
Come on.
[HORN HONKING]
[CONTINUES HONKING]
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
[ANNOUNCER ON LOUDSPEAKER
SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[NINA'S "DO YOU KNOW HOW
CHRISTMAS TREES ARE GROWN"
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
♪ Friendship and kindness ♪
♪ But most of all ♪
♪ They need love ♪
♪ Do you know how Santa
Gets around? ♪
♪ He needs snowflakes
Snowflakes ♪
[LAUGHING]
♪ Reindeer, even though
They try ♪
♪ They need other things ♪
♪ Once a year
They have to fly ♪
♪ And they don't have wings ♪
♪ Do you know how
Santa gets around? ♪
[LAUGHING]
♪ He needs snowflakes
And reindeer ♪
♪ Sunshine and raindrops ♪
♪ Friendship and kindness ♪
♪ But most of all ♪
♪ He needs love ♪
James.
♪ Do you know
How Christmas cards are made? ♪
Darling, you're in trouble.
What is it?
There's people after me.
Can I help?
Have you got a car?
Outside.
[EXPLOSION]
Let's get out of here.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Stay close to me, James.
Not far now.
Nearside door.
[FIREWORKS CONTINUE EXPLODING]
Maybe he didn't see me.
I wouldn't go
"Banco!" on that.
Giving up bad habits, eh?
James, where are we heading?
Nearest post office
to contact London.
I know, Feldkirch.
Why are they looking
for you?
I suspect they're trying
to kill me.
Drive on.
No sign of them yet.
Or of someone
saying, "Thank you."
Thank you, Tracy.
You've got sharp eyes
and beautiful...
earlobes. What were you doing
so near Piz Gloria?
Now I have
a new interest in life.
Winter sports, eh?
Very wholesome.
Just one winter sportsman,
and Papa told me
where to find him.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Just keep my mind
on your driving.
[CHURCH BELL RINGING]
Good. There it is, James.
Hurry.
[♪♪♪]
[GUNFIRE]
James!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Shoot at them!
Good girl.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
Keep straight.
Turn left. That crowd
might discourage them.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[BOTH SCREAM]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
Looks like we've hit
the rush hour.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
We must stop them!
How do we get out?
BUNT:
Knock him out of the way!
I hope my big end
will stand up to this.
[METAL SCRAPING]
James! How do we get out?
Keep straight!
We can get out there.
TRACY: If you say so.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[SIRENS BLARING]
[SCREAMS]
[SHOUTS
IN GERMAN]
[CHUCKLES]
We didn't even stop
for the prize.
I told you that crowd
would discourage them.
[WIND HOWLING]
Oh, that's all
we need right now.
Pull in there.
Keep moving.
I'll open the doors.
[HORSES SNORTING]
Sorry about
the accommodations,
contessa.
We should have
rung ahead and booked.
If only I'd got through
to London.
At least you'll
get another chance.
But when?
[LOUD BANGING]
[♪♪♪]
Let's get some rest.
We'll push on
as soon as we can.
At least it's dry.
[WIND HOWLING]
[HINGES SQUEAKING]
[♪♪♪]
What really went on
up there, James?
[CHUCKLES]
Her Majesty's Secret Service
is still my job.
But there isn't anything
you can do about your job
at the moment, is there?
No.
Then why are you
thinking about it now?
I'm not.
I'm thinking about us.
Tracy, an agent...
shouldn't be concerned
with anything but himself.
I understand.
We'll just have to go on
the way we are.
No.
I'll have to find
something else to do.
Are you sure, James?
I love you.
I know I'll never find
another girl like you.
Will you marry me?
Do you mean it?
I mean it.
Mr. and Mrs. James Bond.
Of Acacia Avenue,
Tunbridge Wells.
Mmm. How about
Belgrave Square?
Or the Via Veneto, Rome.
Paris, convenient
for Le Touquet.
Monaco, handy for the Rainiers.
I wonder how much
they're asking for this place.
[CHUCKLES]
The proper time for this
is our wedding night.
And that's
my New Year's resolution.
Whatever you say, darling.
And that...is yours.
Good night, Tracy.
Good night, James.
It's not New Year yet.
[CHUCKLES]
[SNORTING SOFTLY]
[♪♪♪]
James!
Keep going!
Simple!
Good girl.
[GUNFIRE]
[MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
[SCREAMS]
[♪♪♪]
He had lots of guts.
You three
keep going.
Let's head for the trees!
James!
Keep going!
[TRACY SCREAMS]
Tracy, cling onto me!
[WIND HOWLING]
[♪♪♪]
BLOFELD:
A grave deep enough, I think,
to prevent even 007
from walking.
Get the girl.
[♪♪♪]
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
MONEYPENNY:
United Nations, sir.
Red scrambler.
M here.
Yes, we're standing by
as instructed.
I understand.
Thank you, sir.
Well, no decision
has been announced yet.
Of course, it's
a total news blackout.
But my informant
was very plain.
How plain, sir?
They're going to buy
Blofeld off.
Sit down.
And the price?
Amnesty.
A full pardon
for all past crimes.
Official recognition
of his title when he retires
into private life
as Count de Bleuchamp.
He seems to set
great store by that.
A very curious thing,
snobbery.
When will they conclude
the deal?
Blofeld wants to know
the council's decision
not later than midnight
the day after tomorrow.
Sir, that gives us time
to get to Piz Gloria first.
In force.
No, 007.
My instructions
are quite clear.
But, sir,
destroy the institute
and destroy Blofeld
and his virus with it.
It's been rejected as too risky.
Those girls...
God knows how many,
let alone where.
Sir, if we destroy
the center of communication
that controls those girls,
without Blofeld's voice,
they can do nothing.
I have my orders,
007, you have yours.
Forget it.
And the girl
who helped me escape,
we just leave her there?
This department is not concerned
with your personal problems.
This department owes her a debt.
She saved my life.
Operation Bedlam is dead.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
I understand.
[RINGS]
OPERATOR:
Your call to Marc Ange Draco,
head of Draco Construction.
Hello, Draco?
Yes, who is it?
Bond. James Bond.
Thank God, James.
I'd like to interest you
in a demolition deal
that requires
certain aerial activity
to install equipment.
Are you sure we're going to find
Teresa when we get up there?
I'm pretty certain.
Even if she's not there,
there's a good reason
for going anyway.
So you've explained.
Quite a crusade.
[♪♪♪]
It is a time
for celebration.
Perhaps,
if they agree.
They can do nothing else
and you know it,
and they know it.
I shall be able
to offer you
anything your heart
could wish for.
Paid for with how many lives?
Oh, come now, Tracy,
don't be so proud.
Your own father's profession
is not entirely within the law.
His brotherhood
also have...exotic ways
to keep it a closed shop.
RADIO OPERATOR:
Basel approach calling
unidentified aircraft.
You're flying
in controlled airspace.
We have no flight plan
filed on you.
[OPERATOR CONTINUES SPEAKING]
I think some people don't know
we're crusaders.
Now, if you're very,
very nice to me,
I could make you
my countess.
But I'm already
a countess.
Whereas if you
displease me,
I can promise you
a very different estate.
Excuse me,
sir.
Yes?
There is something
on the radio
you should hear.
...and destination. Over.
Excuse me.
CONTROLLER:
This is Zurich information
calling unidentified aircraft.
Over.
I repeat:
This is Zurich information
calling unidentified aircraft.
Well?
That helicopter
is one of three.
None of them have answered
air control.
And?
There are suspect aircraft
in the vicinity.
CONTROLLER:
...pilot's name
and destination. Over.
Zurich, this is Foxtrot,
Gulf, Sierra,
leading Red Cross
helicopter flight,
carrying Red Cross
medical supplies to Italy.
What's the trouble?
Over.
We have no record
of your flight plan
or registration.
Over.
I repeat, we have no record
of your flight plan
or your registration. Over.
Then your registrations
must be out-of-date. Over.
Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra,
this is Zurich information.
You must land at Zurich
and report.
I say again,
land at Zurich and report.
Over.
Do you wish to commit murder?
I told you,
this is a mercy flight
carrying blood plasma
and emergency equipment
for the victims
of the Italian flood disaster
at Rovigo.
I repeat:
mercy flight.
You understand me?
[CLINKING]
Gulf, Sierra?
Yes?
Zurich. Very well,
you may proceed. Out.
You see?
It is nothing.
That seems to have settled it.
In case one or both of us
is delayed on the way home,
it's better to have
a rendezvous for later.
Before we start
getting sentimental,
I think we're being followed.
I've been thinking
about your proposition.
Please,
tell me more.
MAN:
This is military air control.
There is no record
of your mission.
Alter course to Zurich
and land.
Fighters have been dispatched
to intercept you. Over.
I suggest you check
your records again,
carefully. Over.
I repeat, return to Zurich
and land. Over.
Check with Geneva.
Check with the Red Cross
in Geneva.
Meanwhile, call off
your air force.
It is making
my passengers sick.
Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra,
you are carrying passengers?
Of course I am.
Distinguished representatives
of the world press.
They've had enough
of your nonsense.
So have I.
Over and out.
There's a lot more
to tell,
but there will be plenty
of time later.
Take me
to the Alpine room.
Oh? Are you unhappy here?
[SIGHS]
Oh.
I want to see
the dawn.
Oh.
So poetic a pleasure.
What were
all the world's charms
to mighty Paris
when he found that first dawn
in the arms of his Helen?
And when do you expect
the signal
accepting your terms?
Ah. Any time
before midnight tonight.
Thy dawn, O master
of the world, thy dawn.
For thee, the sunlight
creeps across the lawn.
For thee,
the ships
are drawn down to the waves.
For thee, the markets throng
with myriad slaves.
For thee, the hammer
on the anvil rings.
For thee,
the poet
of beguilement sings.
Helicopters!
We're being attacked!
Get all positions covered!
[♪♪♪]
[EXPLOSION]
[GUNFIRE]
[SCREAMS]
[BULLETS RICOCHETING]
[MEN SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
Look to the girl!
[♪♪♪]
[GUNFIRE]
[GRUNTING]
[DISTANT EXPLOSIONS]
[TRACY YELLS]
[MEN SHOUTING, GUNFIRE]
Tracy! Darling.
Thank God, Teresa!
[GUNSHOT]
James, wait!
DRACO:
Guns make me nervous.
You've done your share.
Get her to safety.
Come on! Let's go!
And you!
Get the circuit
set up now! Let's go!
[SCREAMING]
[FIRES GUN]
[♪♪♪]
[GUNFIRE IN DISTANCE]
All points covered?
Yes, sir.
DRACO: Okay.
[♪♪♪]
All set to blow?
The fuse is set
for exactly five minutes
and 10 seconds time.
The place will
be sealed forever.
Will that give
the Englishman time
to get out?
He knows the schedule.
[CLICKS]
Where are you going?
Papa, where's James?
Don't worry.
He'll join us soon.
But we can't leave him!
He doesn't need your help!
I will not go
without him!
You'll have to!
Spare the rod and spoil
the child, eh?
Five, four, three,
two, one. Now!
[♪♪♪]
[BULLETS RICOCHETING]
[FIRES]
[BULLET RICOCHETING]
[LAUGHS]
[CHUCKLING]
He's branched off.
[♪♪♪]
Never mind that.
Go and get the brandy, huh?
Five-star Hennessy, of course.
[♪♪♪]
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[CHURCH BELLS CHIMING]
MAN:
Your Royal Highnesses,
my lords, ladies and gentlemen,
the toast is,
the bride and bridegroom:
Mr. and Mrs. James Bond.
CROWD [IN UNISON]:
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
WOMAN:
Good luck, Teresa.
Thank you.
[GIRLS SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
Anyway,
it's a pleasure...
to meet the man who cost me
three of my best operatives.
Yes, November '64,
the bullion job.
Mm.
You even got away
with quite a chunk
of the haul.
Tell me...
[GIRLS SINGING IN ITALIAN]
Congratulations, 007.
I must confess that
I've sometimes thought you
a little, uh--
Irresponsible?
Exactly. That's exactly
the word. Thank you.
This time, my boy,
I can't complain.
Nor can I.
Excuse me.
Teresa?
Yes, Papa?
Look, James,
I know that we haven't
always exactly seen--
Well, anyway,
don't forget,
if there's anything
you ever need--
Thank you, Q, but this time
I've got the gadgets,
and I know how to use them.
Au revoir.
Remember, obey your husband
in all things.
You promise me? Huh?
But of course I will.
As I always obeyed you.
[CHUCKLES]
Of course.
Well, James,
I wish you luck.
For the first
and last time.
Remember?
An old proverb:
"Her price is far above rubies,
or even your million pounds."
DRACO:
Teresa,
just because you are Mrs. Bond
don't forget my birthday
next year.
Have I ever?
DRACO:
Both of you. Heh.
Maybe all of you.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on, James.
Very happy.
Be happy, my darling.
Come on.
On your way.
Au revoir.
ALL:
Goodbye!
Drive carefully!
[HORN HONKING]
Miss Moneypenny,
what would you do without me?
I always cry at weddings.
007 never had any respect
for government property.
[HONKS HORN]
You know, I haven't given you
a wedding present yet.
I had an idea about that.
Three girls, three boys.
Pleased?
Mmm.
Not bad for a start.
But, darling, now we have
all the time in the world.
[SMOOCHES]
[CAR HORN HONKING
IN DISTANCE]
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[LAUGHS]
[BOYS AND GIRLS
CHATTERING]
BOY:
Say it with flowers!
He's got a point.
We do look like an ad
for a flower shop.
That reminds me,
I didn't even send you flowers.
Anyway, you have given me
a wedding present.
The best I could have:
a future.
Mrs. Bond, shut...
up.
And don't eat it
all at once.
He loves me--
Instinctively.
Infuriatingly.
Intensely.
In...
In...?
Indubitably.
[CHUCKLES]
First a boy,
and then a girl.
It's Blofeld!
It's Blofeld.
[ENGINE CUTS OFF]
It's all right.
It's quite all right, really.
She's having a rest.
We'll be going on soon.
There's no hurry, you see.
We have all the time
in the world.
[SOBBING QUIETLY]
[♪♪♪]